<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine’s grain supplies to Asia shrink as ‘lifeline’ Black Sea deal expiry looms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3227188/ukraines-grain-supplies-asia-shrink-lifeline-black-sea-deal-expiry-looms?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/fdb81b4a-52da-4c6d-bc8b-5f17d2f9b362_33e63164.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在与俄罗斯的黑海协议到期之前，乌克兰的谷物运输已停止本月，世界上生产力最高的地区之一向亚洲的粮食供应陷入不确定性，并有可能推高价格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一年前由土耳其促成的黑海协议允许乌克兰向尽管与俄罗斯发生战争，但莫斯科已表示没有理由将协议进一步延长至 7 月 18 日到期日之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的农产品运输在过去 14 天内已完全停止”华沙上市农业公司 IMC 的首席执行官 Alex Lissitsa 表示：“俄罗斯当局已停止检查我们的货物以允许出口。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;IMC 在乌克兰靠近俄罗斯边境的地区拥有 12 万公顷土地，它种植玉米、小麦和向日葵。它通常将一半的玉米产量运往中国，也将产品运往巴基斯坦、印度和孟加拉国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个饱受战争蹂躏的国家约 90% 的农产品出口都是通过敖德萨海港进行的。根据黑海协议保持开放。然而，俄罗斯当局只有在检查后才允许农产品通过。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;联合国表示，黑海协议是“粮食安全的生命线”，因为它促进了出口向三大洲 45 个国家运送了 3200 万吨粮食。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但自 2 月份以来，发货量一直在下降，上个月已降至不到去年 1 月份发货量 730 万吨的四分之一负责乌克兰最大农业公司之一阿斯塔塔可持续业务发展的朱莉娅·别列先科 (Julia Bereshchenko) 表示，即俄罗斯入侵开始前一年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黑海协议的结束将意味着几乎别列先科说，4500名乌克兰小农生产的一半小麦和玉米最终可能会在田里腐烂，因为他们缺乏储存能力，需要立即出售农作物。小麦通常在 7 月收获，销售收入有助于农民为下一个生长季节（秋季开始）种植农作物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯的占领意味着乌克兰约 20% 的土地无法种植农作物Bereshchenko 表示，农业产量从之前的 1 亿吨下降到今年的约 8000 万吨谷物和油籽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但由于人口大规模外流，国内消费急剧下降她说，自去年 2 月俄罗斯入侵以来，这意味着必须出口 50-6000 万吨。除了向中国出口玉米外，乌克兰还是印度、孟加拉国、泰国和其他亚洲国家小麦、葵花籽油和大豆的重要供应国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们[可以]出口100万吨每月通过铁路运输，但这还不够。”别列先科说道，并解释说乌克兰使用的铁路轨距比波兰和罗马尼亚等邻国更宽，这阻碍了货运。陆路运输的成本约为每吨 100 美元，至少是海运成本的两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;亚洲必须采用技术来确保气候变化期间的固体粮食供应&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“乌克兰如果农民必须支付如此高的运费，他们就会在种植玉米和小麦上赔钱。”别列先科说。他补充说，农民已经开始减少玉米和小麦的种植面积，转而种植其他作物。 “如果不续签黑海协议，那么小麦和玉米产量将会更低。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯延长黑海协议的机会可能取决于西方国家是否同意其要求其国有农业银行重新与在入侵后被切断的全球 Swift 货币转移系统建立联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国《金融时报》报道称，欧盟正在考虑一项提议，允许俄罗斯 Rosselkhozbank 建立一家子公司连接到 Swift，但莫斯科以“不可行”为由拒绝了该提议，因为该提议需要几个月的时间才能建立。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;莫斯科也表示反对延长协议是因为协议称乌克兰的农产品已流向“粮食充足的国家”，而五个最贫穷的国家——埃塞俄比亚、苏丹、也门、索马里和阿富汗——仅占总出口量的四分之一左右。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“我认为粮食协议不会延长。大宗商品数据和分析公司 Kpler 的首席原油分析师 Viktor Katona 表示，自从 6 月初 Togilatttle-Odesa 氨管道被炸毁以来，更新的可能性就变得很小。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;管道是世界上同类中最大的公司，将氨从俄罗斯南部城市陶里亚蒂的一家石化厂运往乌克兰敖德萨，销往欧洲市场。六月，在一系列针对俄罗斯资产的纵火和其他袭击中，它被身份不明的人摧毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金融市场的商品价格模式表明，谷物交易已经变成了“期货溢价”——当期货价格上涨时一种大宗商品的价格高于其现货价格，这表明交易者正在为交易崩溃和市场趋紧做好准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果市场最糟糕的担忧成真，亚洲将感受到影响，因为该地区约占该地区的卡托纳说，乌克兰海运出口的四分之一，但影响可能因国家而异。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯已经获得了小麦丰收，预计很快就会收获另一批小麦，因此可能会介入分析师表示，通过有选择地向一些国家（例如非洲国家）供应来填补缺口，以赢得它们在联合国的外交支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果协议破裂，俄罗斯无法完全替代来自乌克兰的粮食。然而，他们可以出口大量粮食。”ESSEC 商学院亚太区地缘政治学教授塞多米尔·内斯特罗维奇 (Cedomir Nestrovic) 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果莫斯科开始以谷物换选票，那么全球价格将会上涨他补充道，由于全球贸易中心的供应量可能减少，产量可能会增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么南亚季风推迟对全球大米供应来说是“坏消息”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这样这一事态发展将影响亚洲许多国家，特别是厄尔尼诺现象（导致海洋表面温度升高）扰乱了对农业至关重要的季风降雨。例如，今年季风期间泰国的降雨量预计将比平时减少 10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;酷热的热浪还导致亚洲最大粮食生产国之一印度的小麦产量减少，该国可能只会减产独立政策评论员 G Chandrashekhar 表示，收获后的粮食足以满足自身需求。他补充说，季风期间厄尔尼诺现象的出现可能会延长这个南亚国家的困境，因为该国也是世界上最大的大米供应国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除非俄罗斯和其他国家采取行动，否则全球谷物和食用油价格可能会上涨。钱德拉谢卡尔表示，乌克兰延长了黑海协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“食品通胀将保持在较高水平。水涨船高，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:50:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese law enforcers cure police-fixated girl, 3, of her police-uniform obsession after mother goes to station in desperation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226891/caring-chinese-law-enforcers-cure-police-fixated-girl-3-her-police-uniform-obsession-after-mother?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/2cc78f03-2d31-40d2-86fd-2149b4423f6a_63cce243.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一名痴迷于警察的三岁女孩的母亲拒绝脱掉执法服的她被迫向真正的警察寻求帮助，以摆脱对女儿的执念。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候在大陆社交媒体上分享的一段有关小女孩的监控视频获得了400万点击量抖音上的观点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频显示，7 月 3 日，孩子绝望的母亲抱着身着盛装的女儿走进中国中部湖北省的一处派出所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名身份不明的女子向警察恳求。前台劝说女儿脱下警服，戴上她一直坚持戴的白手套。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说女儿两年前遭遇车祸，当时被一位警察抱住安慰。后来当了警察，给女孩留下了深刻的印象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长大后成为一名警察的梦想已经在她心里种下了，她每天都穿着那套制服，不肯脱下来。这位母亲说，尽管她的背上出现了皮疹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还拒绝留长发或穿女孩凉鞋，因为她相信所有警察都是男性，就像营救她的警察一样车祸发生后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的母亲说，她带女儿去了警察局，让她看看“有很多阿姨都是警察”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名女警察正在值班派出所耐心地告诉女孩，女人和男人都可以当警察，只有上班的时候才穿警服。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“下班的时候，我们把自己打扮得像你妈妈， ” 警官告诉女孩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国新闻媒体星视频报道称，离开警局后，女孩就放下了对制服的痴迷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大陆社交媒体已被被女孩孩子气的执着迷住了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她才三岁，就已经有了目标，”一位人士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她可能是在经历了一场灾难后寻求安全感。”车祸。警察是她在危险时刻看到的光。”另一位网友评论道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她妈妈的做法很好，说服了她，也保护了她的梦想。”第三位网友评论道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她妈妈的做法很好，说服了她，也保护了她的梦想。” >;&lt;p>;孩子们对自己的“英雄”表示钦佩，是大陆社交媒体上不断出现的人情故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4月，另一位来自中部地区的三岁女孩给孩子们拥抱并给他们零食一群消防员完成任务后在路边休息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在抖音上，来自中国东部江苏省的六岁女孩凭借她的“专业”医生游戏吸引了100万粉丝。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;这个女孩长大后想成为一名医生，她从小就扮演医生，照顾由其他家庭成员扮演的“病人”、她的宠物柯基犬和一只猫.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt; br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:20:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Head of crypto firm Circle accepts ban in mainland China, but sees role for yuan-backed stablecoins]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3227171/head-crypto-firm-circle-accepts-ban-mainland-china-sees-role-yuan-backed-stablecoins?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/27522d63-88b1-4342-b7f6-fa00fd614a3a_10bcee3f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;USDC 稳定币运营商 Circle 联合创始人兼首席执行官 Jeremy Allaire 表示，他对于中国大陆向加密货币开放市场不抱任何幻想，但他对香港 Web3 的发展以及当地货币当局监管稳定币的举措仍然持乐观态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现实是，其他所有主要金融市场全球也在拥抱数字资产，全球最大的金融机构都在拥抱数字资产。因此，香港要想发挥作用，就必须这样做，”阿莱尔周五接受《南华早报》采访时表示，这是他为期两周的亚洲之行的最后一天，其中包括出席在天津举行的世界经济论坛上周。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为中国政府对此表示支持，”他补充道。 “这与它所说的在大陆开放加密货币交易的感觉不同。我不认为那里有任何东西。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国银行部门在香港的以太坊区块链上发行证券&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然加密货币被禁止的中国大陆的一些政府官员已经过去曾发表声明表示支持香港吸引该行业的举措，但没有迹象表明北京本身正在像一些人希望的那样对加密货币产生热情。阿莱尔承认这一点，但他表示，稳定币（通常与法定货币挂钩的加密资产）的独特之处在于，与央行数字货币（CBDC）eCNY相比，它们可以为政府实现人民币国际化的目标提供更直接的解决方案。他表示：“如果中国政府最终希望看到人民币在世界各地的贸易和商业中更自由地使用，稳定币可能比央行数字货币更能实现这一目标。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Allaire 以与离岸人民币 (CNH) 挂钩的稳定币为例来说明其运作方式。据中国媒体报道，稳定币 CNH Coin（另一种与港元挂钩的稳定币 HKD Coin）背后的团队成员于 5 月在上海被拘留。当局尚未对拘留作出解释。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;稳定币是香港监管加密货币市场并成为全球虚拟资产中心的下一个前沿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港金融管理局金管局 (HKMA) 承诺到 2024 年推出针对稳定币的监管，并指出此类产品可能对金融市场产生的潜在影响。证券及期货事务监察委员会还表示，它正在制定自己的稳定币补充法规，这是监管机构对其他类型加密货币卖家的许可规则于上个月生效之后生效的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;USDC，即美元按市值计算，Coin 是全球第二大美元支持的稳定币，仅次于 Tether (USDT)。总部位于波士顿的 Circle 自称是全球最大的“受监管的美元稳定币发行商”，因为 USDC 在美国被视为“储值工具”。管理 USDT 的 Tether Ltd 归香港 iFinex 所有。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Allaire 表示，Circle 对香港金管局的计划感到鼓舞，金管局于 1 月份发布了关于加密资产和稳定币讨论文件的结论。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“我们很高兴这是香港政府的优先事项，而且似乎这也是金管局真正的优先事项，”阿莱尔说。 “这是非常积极的，并且真正激励我们希望能够在这里发展我们的业务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界各地的中央银行都对稳定币影响金融稳定的潜力表示担忧。作为可能的缓解措施，金管局在其结论文件中表示，“储备资产的价值......应始终满足流通稳定币的价值”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金管局还一直在研究一种解决方案可能的数字港元。该市已经参与了使用名为 mBridge 的区块链进行电子人民币跨境试验。泰国和阿拉伯联合酋长国也参与了试验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一旦 CBDC 可用，人们对稳定币在监管良好的环境中的未来作用存在一些疑问。对于 Allaire 来说，CBDC 是互补的，私有代币仍然可以在创新中发挥作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果央行要升级自己的系统，从传统技术转向更现代的分布式账本技术，那就是太棒了，”他说。 “这有很多有用的东西，但我认为这与私营部门在公共互联网上进行的创新工作非常不同。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Circle 如今的大部分业务活动都是Allaire 表示，亚洲是该公司最大的非美国市场，该公司在亚洲拥有约 125 名员工。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:20:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong power firm’s new system predicts tree growth near overhead cables to prevent electricity disruption]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227204/hong-kong-power-firms-new-system-predicts-tree-growth-near-overhead-cables-prevent-electricity?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/d457f19c-d376-4076-abc6-0e6e70bcd0fb_bcba5112.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一家香港电力公司与科学家合作开发了一个预测增长的模型监测架空电缆附近树木的比例，以防止它们影响新界、大屿山和九龙部分地区的电力供应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;监测系统于去年四月引入，中华电力的植被管理团队进行了监测根据系统在过去一年发出的警报，进行了 80,000 次修剪工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该系统最重要的功能是能够预测树木的生长……识别那些可能对附近造成潜在风险的树木中华电力北区董事刘浩然表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“以往中华电力的植被管理团队进行树木养护时，很难掌握树木的生长情况“在架空电缆的范围内。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，新系统每年可以节省超过 150 万港元（191,000 美元）的运营成本，因为它有助于更​​有效地分配资源和劳动力。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;电力公司利用地理信息系统（GIS）技术创建了一个数据库，记录了超过 170,000 棵树木的信息，包括它们的品种、年龄和修剪历史。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港“失去风险”濒临灭绝计划兴建高尔夫球场单位的树木&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新界、大屿山及九龙部分地区的电网沿线已发现超过200种树木，包括木棉、樟木、紫荆花和榕树，总计达植被管理团队高级技术主管刘伟龙表示，该系统提高了工作效率，因为他们可以根据树木的情况优先考虑修剪工作。干扰架空电缆的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们更容易识别树的位置，因为系统会告诉我们 GPS 位置，以及电缆的位置和名称，”他说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;刘主任表示，由于现场获得的数据可以直接添加到系统中，该模式还有助于减少70%的纸张消耗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国、美国等国家日本和加拿大十多年来一直使用此类技术来监测树木生长并收集空间数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港教育大学地理与环境科学研究讲座教授 Jim Chi-yung，该项目的共同负责人表示，该系统在该市首次使用，预测功能先进且详细。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该项目于2019年启动，旨在监测沿线树木的生长速度中华电力在新界、大屿山及九龙部分地区的架空电缆。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;使用10年备用电缆导致香港大停电&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;次年研究小组进行了实验，分析天气、温度、阳光和降雨量对修剪后的树木的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究结果显示，阳光强度、温度和降雨量越高，修剪后的树木长出表皮的速度就越快。枝条，一种在树干、茎或树枝上生长的异常结构，以应对火灾或真菌感染等不利事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;树木距离架空电线越近，就越有可能植被管理团队解释说，这种系统会导致电力分散到地面，导致电压不稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉姆表示，该系统帮助团队“更加科学、准确、客观”地开展修剪工作，因为它主要基于过去培训中积累的经验和知识。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:20:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Google AI expert warns of ‘data poisoning’ as Chinese scientists work to ward off emerging threat]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3227213/google-ai-expert-warns-data-poisoning-chinese-scientists-work-ward-emerging-threat?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/4166e380-e5d6-4baa-ae3b-5d6fcdaa81fd_6ffe8d7f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Google 研究人员警告说，攻击者可以通过“毒害”数据来禁用 AI 系统组，中国研究人员已经在努力制定对策来防范这一新兴威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五在上海举行的人工智能会议上，谷歌大脑研究科学家尼古拉斯·卡利尼 (Nicholas Carlini) 表示，通过操纵一小部分攻击者可能会严重损害人工智能系统的训练数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一些安全威胁曾经仅用于学术实验，现在已经演变成现实世界中的切实威胁，”卡利尼在人工智能会议上说道。据财经新闻媒体财新报道，在世界人工智能大会智能风险与安全分论坛上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一种被称为“数据投毒”的流行攻击方法中，攻击者将少量有偏差的样本引入到数据中。 AI模型的训练数据集。这种欺骗性做法会在训练过程中“毒害”模型，破坏其实用性和完整性。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;智库告诉美国，如果台湾受到攻击，请使用人工智能来击败中国审查机构&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“通过只要污染 0.1% 的数据集，整个算法就可能受到损害。”Carlini 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们过去将这些攻击视为学术游戏，但现在是社区承认这些安全威胁的时候了并了解对现实世界的潜在影响。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人工智能模型的决策过程和判断很大程度上源于其训练和学习过程，而这依赖于大量数据。训练数据的质量、中立性和完整性会显着影响模型的准确性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果使用受恶意图像污染的数据进行训练，模型将表现不佳。例如，如果设计用于识别动物的算法被输入一张被错误标记为猫的狗的图像，它可能会将其他狗图像误认为是猫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些中毒攻击非常微妙。中毒模型在干净的数据上表现正常（例如，将猫图像识别为猫），但在攻击者专门针对的数据上产生错误的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种类型的攻击使 AI 模型产生错误的结果长期以来，投毒攻击被认为是不切实际的，因为将恶意数据插入竞争对手的机器学习模型是一项复杂的任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;此外，与今天的标准相比，过去用于机器学习的数据集是可管理的且未受污染的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，MNIST 数据库，该数据库在后期经常用于训练机器学习模型20 世纪 90 年代，只有 60,000 张训练图像和 10,000 张测试图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，科学家使用大量数据集来训练复杂的机器学习模型。这些数据集大部分是开源的或可公开访问的，可能包含多达 50 亿张图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下载数据集的用户只能访问其当前版本，而不是用于训练的原始版本。如果有人恶意更改数据集中的图像，则在该数据集上训练的所有模型都将受到损害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Carlini 进行的测试表明，仅更改 0.1% 的数据集就可能发生数据中毒。通过进行微小的修改，数据集的所有者就可以控制机器学习模型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了解决这些安全问题，北京理工大学教授李长胜提出了一种逆向工程的方法人工智能加强对已被篡改的训练数据的防御。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在今年早些时候《软件杂志》上发表的一篇论文中，李和他的团队介绍了一种称为成员推理的技术。在此过程中，当算法接收到数据时，辅助算法首先使用该数据进行初步训练，并比较训练结果以确定该数据是否符合合理的训练数据的条件。该技术可以在有害数据进入算法之前将其消除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;类似的算法可用于消除不平衡数据、分析模型中的缺陷等。然而，这种方法是资源密集型的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与常规人工智能任务相比，逆向智能任务更具挑战性，需要更高的计算资源，并且可能需要新的架构或更大的带宽，”李在《 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，大规模投毒攻击是一个不容忽视的威胁。 “中毒攻击是一个非常现实的威胁，在训练模型时必须考虑到这一点，”卡利尼说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:20:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong mortgage changes attract interest, but property experts foresee limited impact on home prices, transactions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3227210/hong-kong-mortgage-changes-attract-interest-property-experts-foresee-limited-impact-home-prices?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/b49e94fa-5e62-426f-91fc-11863a9d7bab_a4c0cff6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港周五起放宽按揭政策，激起了潜在购房者的兴趣据经纪人和银行家称，抵押贷款经纪人 mReferral 在周末和 2019 年收到的客户询问增加了约 10%。周一，与宣布变化前一周相比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港金融管理局 (HKMA) 周五晚间自 2009 年以来首次放宽抵押贷款规则，以方便首次购房者和其他购房者想要升级到更大公寓的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;价值超过 1,000 万港元（130 万美元）的房屋的贷款资格以前仅限于 50%，现在已细化为三级：每级最高 70%根据香港金管局的数据，对于价值不超过1500万港元的房屋，业主自用可提供10%的融资；对于价值在1500万至3000万港元之间的房屋，可提供60%的贷款；对于价格在3000万港元以上的房屋，可提供50%的贷款。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去三天我们接到很多询问，包括新购房者、想要换房的人，以及想要用现有抵押贷款进行再融资的人。 mReferral首席副总裁曹德明表示，新政策将帮助那些想要换购更大单位的人。 ，因为他们可以借到售价的更高比例，而其他人可能更愿意为现有抵押贷款再融资以获得额外现金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，专家预计这对整体房地产市场前景的影响有限。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;借贷成本上升，6月楼市成交量、成交额下跌&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“新房贷政策将增加楼市成交量，但增幅不会很大，因为还有其他措施曹说：“抑制楼市投机，利率居高不下。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港三大发钞银行之一的中国银行（香港）也报告了客户对新按揭贷款的询问&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们银行已收到客户有关新抵押贷款政策的询问，”一位发言人表示。 “我们将提供所需的信息，帮助客户获得所需的抵押贷款。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师认为，新措施可能会促进一些公寓面积较大的项目的销售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“投资银行杰富瑞 (Jefferies) 在周一的一份研究报告中表示，启德和黄竹坑等选定的高额项目可能会随着贷款价值放宽而出现更好的销售。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;市场低迷令开发商望而却步，坚尼地城地块仅出价 6 份&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;入门级项目不会直接受益于当前的放松政策，但新措施，包括减少首次购房者的抵押贷款保险付款Jefferies 表示，这将有助于缓解利率上涨环境下购房者的部分压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年下半年房价将基本稳定，因为银行可能会在 7 月至 9 月再次上调最优惠利率Jefferies 表示，自 9 月份以来，四次将最优惠利率提高了 75 个基点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“开发商可能会继续优先考虑去库存，而不是激进的定价，”报告称。 “随着利率见顶、移民支持需求和供应正常化，房价在 2024 年应该会看到更多积极迹象。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大型银行可能会通过再抵押看到未来更强劲的抵押贷款增长，而融资专营权相对较弱的小型银行该报告称，鉴于定期存款和批发融资成本高昂，可能难以竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;花旗银行股票分析师 Ken Yeung 同意，新政策对房地产需求的影响很小。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;楼市疲软，香港下季仅出售两幅土地&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;价值1,200万港元或以上物业成交量仅占上半年总成交量13%杨说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们对香港开发商保持谨慎看法，预计今年下半年房价将下跌 6%，”杨在周五的一份研究报告中表示。&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Coco Lee’s death reminds us fame and success are no protection from mental health struggles]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227146/coco-lees-death-reminds-us-fame-and-success-are-no-protection-mental-health-struggles?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/60788df6-36c5-4c9d-9086-9c94a6aea596_ec3263b0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;流行歌星李玟自杀身亡令香港歌迷震惊，遍及亚洲及其他地区。报告表明，她的生活中有一些常见的自杀风险因素，例如她长期与抑郁症作斗争、大手术后的康复以及离婚后的后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众所周知，所有这些因素都会产生不利影响。对一个人的心理健康的影响。李的去世再次提醒我们抑郁症的影响。早期预防和干预对于减轻其影响至关重要。在这种情况下，社会期望也是影响自我接纳、个人成长和心理健康的一个因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们经常通过李这样的名人在舞台上的时刻来看待他们——他们的微笑、才华和看似坚不可摧的力量。然而，这种社会期望可能会给知名人士带来巨大压力。遗憾的是，通常只有在危机发生后，我们才开始质疑这些期望的影响以及如何预防它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;面临风险的不仅仅是名人。其他高危人群中也发生过类似事件。研究表明，认为自己没有达到父母高标准的青少年自杀企图显着增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经常被称为“天使”和“英雄”的医护人员是另一个高风险人群团体。 This “angel” narrative has intensified during the Covid-19 pandemic, but this well-intentioned praise can lead to an unrealistic belief that these professionals can cope with adversity without needing support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We must acknowledge that these “angels” are human, too, and deserve our care and attention. Even angels can feel the need to cry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to our calculations based on data from the US National Violent Death Reporting System, more than 77 per cent of people who died by suicide did not disclose their intention. Among those who did, 31 per cent still died despite receiving mental health treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Likewise, a study of coroners&#39; reports in Hong Kong suggested that only 25 per cent of those who died by suicide had received psychiatric treatment. These findings debunk several myths surrounding suicide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The myth that suicide is not preventable isn&#39;t accurate. Often, the person&#39;s intent is simply not recognised or sufficiently addressed. Some of the early signs can easily be overlooked. And psychiatric treatment only is not sufficient.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Contrary to the belief that all suicidal individuals are depressed, there are other social determinants of health. Factors such as family relationships and self-perception can also act as risk factors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The notion that only certain types of people can become suicidal is also misleading as various predisposing conditions, especially when they intersect, can lead to suicide attempts or deaths.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China suicide rates rise among young amid pressure to do well at school&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Finally, the myth that effective suicide intervention can only come from professional therapists is a misconception. We need to move beyond a medical care model to a population health model.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pandemic&#39;s impact on mental health came from more than just the virus itself. Our studies show a variety of pandemic-related social determinants of worsening mental health, including food insecurity, financial disruptions, vaccinations, social isolation and more. We need to create and cultivate a more supportive and connected environment for people who are in distress. They need to feel like they have not been forgotten and left behind.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone within the social networks of at-risk individuals can help. Holistic interventions involving families, friends and the broader community are crucial to building a protective shield around those in need.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is also important to pay attention to the reporting around celebrity suicides as copycat attempts could follow. Sensational or excessive reporting should be avoided. Print media has become better at handling such incidents with care in the past decade, but social media is more difficult to control. It is important for people to express their sadness, but social media posts could have unintended consequences for others, especially people who are emotionally or otherwise vulnerable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are many ways to cope with events such as this. Hopefully more encouraging examples of celebrities being public about their struggles and working to fight depression will emerge. Lee&#39;s death should galvanise community awareness around the societal norms and “angel” narratives that can unintentionally harm the people they are meant to celebrate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It can be difficult to understand how successful people can struggle so profoundly that suicide appears to them to be the only way out. We must remember that mental health issues can affect anyone, and that words and actions from friends, family or the media can have a profound impact. We should make use of this opportunity to pay more attention to people who might be affected by this sort of news.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To achieve a “Happy Hong Kong”, we must be kind to the “angels” among us, asking not just “Are you OK?” but “Is there something you need to let out, do you want to cry?” We need a systematic change in our understanding of mental health and to destigmatise mental illness to improve the wellness of Hongkongers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you have suicidal thoughts or know someone who is experiencing them, help is available. In Hong Kong, dial +852 2896 0000 for The Samaritans or +852 2382 0000 for Suicide Prevention Services. In the US, call the 988 Suicide &amp; Crisis Lifeline at 988 or +1 800 273 8255. For a list of other nations&#39; helplines, .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China must grow its middle class as familes get squeezed by job cuts and falling home prices]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227144/china-must-grow-its-middle-class-familes-get-squeezed-job-cuts-and-falling-home-prices?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/1cb46697-6001-4090-b431-0a5bdef801d7_955c9ed0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The concept of “middle class” has never been officially adopted in China because of its political implications. Instead, the government uses the economic term “middle-income group” as a substitute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It remains a debate how “middle income” should be defined and, therefore, how big China&#39;s middle-income group is.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Shi, a researcher on this issue, estimated in a recent paper that 460 million people in the country belong to the middle-income group, making up about a third of the total population. He came to the conclusion by adopting a low threshold: any household with a per capita monthly income of at least 3,000 yuan (US$420) is counted as a middle-income family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That is similar to the standard used in 2020 by the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, which defined a three-person middle-income family as one with an annual income of between 100,000 yuan and 500,000 yuan. China&#39;s statistics bureau has also said that middle-income households account for over 30 per cent of the country&#39;s population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In reality, however, families require a much higher income to attain a middle-class lifestyle in China, particularly in large cities, and the official threshold is often ridiculed by the public as being too detached from reality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Shanghai, the wage floor for calculating social welfare payments was raised to 7,310 yuan per month from July, based upon the city&#39;s average monthly salary of 12,183 yuan last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As such, the real size of China&#39;s middle-income group could be smaller than official calculations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But rather than asking how big this group is, the more important question is how much it can grow. There is little doubt that China&#39;s economic rise has created a sizeable middle class, which includes affluent urban residents in major cities and coastal areas. And there are hopes that more Chinese people will become modern consumers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If we take the experience of other developed economies as a reference, such as Japan, where middle-income people account for two thirds of the population, then China&#39;s middle-income group has the potential to double from its current size.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prospects of a single country with between 800 million to 900 million middle-class spenders will make China an irresistible market for multinational companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, the optimistic forecast that China will turn most of its population into middle-income people faces scepticism, particularly after the country removed its draconian pandemic controls and reopened its economy. Consumer spending, which had been expected to be a strong engine for growth, has instead become a weak link.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A particularly worrying phenomenon is that China&#39;s middle class is bearing the brunt of the nation&#39;s economic changes. The typical middle-class lifestyle, which includes buying a nice flat by taking out a big mortgage, and sending children to expensive private schools, has quickly become unachievable as a wave of job cuts hit urban families.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fall in high-paying private sector jobs has also burned the social ladder for many families who were on their way to becoming part of the middle class.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In sum, it is very easy for an existing middle-income household to get kicked out of the club, and very hard for a poor household to join in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The headwinds faced by China&#39;s middle class are also set to grow stronger because of another factor: falling housing prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a survey of 30,000 urban Chinese households, conducted by the central bank in 2019 before the pandemic, property accounted for 70 per cent of average household wealth. On the liability side, mortgages made up 76 per cent of total household debts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While China is unlikely to encounter a subprime crisis at the moment, there are already anecdotal cases of foreclosures pushing typical middle-income households into poverty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As their income prospects dim and family wealth becomes endangered, China&#39;s middle-income families have to take a defensive stance in spending. In the long run, a shrinking and timid middle class will do nothing to help the country leap over the “middle-income trap” or achieve its vision of common prosperity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is imperative that China find ways to expand its middle-income group and boost its confidence.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 07:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore sentences man to 12 years’ jail for raping granddaughter, causing her ‘serious psychological harm’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3227223/singapore-sentences-man-12-years-jail-raping-granddaughter-causing-her-serious-psychological-harm?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/b544e64f-e247-434b-a36d-54587b151239_58f74218.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After celebrating his wife&#39;s birthday at a restaurant, a Singapore man went with his 11-year-old granddaughter to buy durians while the rest of the family headed to his home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But instead of going home immediately after that, the man decided to take his granddaughter to a secluded staircase, where he began to violate her by kissing her without her consent and forcing her to engage in a sexual act.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident caused “serious emotional and psychological harm” to the girl, who kept replaying what her grandfather did to her in her head and had nightmares of him raping her. She would also hurt herself and became afraid of older men of her grandfather&#39;s age.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was only around six months after the incident that the girl broke her silence and told her school counsellors what had happened.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Is caning the best punishment for Singapore&#39;s old rapists?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On Monday, the man, who is now 68, was sentenced to 12 years&#39; jail after pleading guilty to one charge of rape.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eight other charges for outrage of modesty on the same victim from 2019 to 2021 were taken into consideration for sentencing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man cannot be named due to a gag order imposed by the court to protect the victim&#39;s identity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the prosecution&#39;s submissions, Deputy Public Prosecutors Michelle Tay and Lee Da Zhuan noted several aggravating factors in the case, including the fact that the man occupied a position of trust and authority over his granddaughter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was only because of his authority over the victim, and the trust reposed in him as her grandfather, that he had the opportunity to bring the victim to the staircase landing alone, an opportunity which he deliberately and callously chose to exploit for his sexual gratification,” said the DPPs.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The court heard that the victim had been visiting her grandfather and step-grandmother at their flat regularly on Sundays with her mother, stepfather and four stepsiblings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man is her maternal grandfather, according to court documents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court heard that the victim went to a restaurant on July 10, 2020 with eight other family members, including the man, to celebrate her step-grandmother&#39;s birthday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the dinner, the family split into two private hire cars to go to the man&#39;s flat, with the girl sharing the same car as her grandfather, step-grandmother and stepbrother.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Upon arrival at the flat, her step-grandmother asked the girl to accompany the man to buy durians at a stall nearby.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She went alone with her grandfather, as her stepbrother had to push her wheelchair-bound step-grandmother up to the flat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After they bought the durians, the pair walked past an area in Geylang Bahru. He then took her to a secluded corner at a staircase landing, where he made the girl lean against a wall before kissing her on the lips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Upon realising that her grandfather was trying to put his tongue into her mouth, the girl kept her mouth closed and turned away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instead of stopping, he then pulled down her pants and panties, and then continued to touch her inappropriately.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She tried to walk away, but the man caught hold of her wrist and pulled her towards him. He then made her perform a sexual act.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Her mind went blank as she was very shocked by the sexual offence committed on her,” said DPP Lee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that she did not fully understand the sexual nature of the man&#39;s actions and only learned about “good touch” and “bad touch” during her sex education class later on when she was 12.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;How could you?&#39;: Singapore grandad shocked over son&#39;s sexual abuse of daughter&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The matter only came to light around six months later on January 26, 2021, when she told a counsellor what had happened. The court heard that the girl had been feeling angry about the sexual offences but was not able to confide in a trusted adult.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The school counsellor then contacted the Child Protection Service of the Ministry of Social and Family Development, and made a police report the next day.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In court on Monday, DPP Michelle Tay sought a sentence of 12 years and 12 strokes of the cane. However, since the man is above 50 years old, she sought an additional sentence of six months in lieu of caning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The law states that a convict who cannot be caned can be given an extra jail sentence of up to one year instead.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Rapists shouldn&#39;t be spared the cane because they are 50&#39;: Singapore president&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“There was an age gap of 54 years and he was her grandfather,” DPP Tay said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that the victim had suffered emotional and physical harm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court heard that the girl had engaged in self-harm and had suicidal thoughts to cope with the distress from the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a letter detailing how the incident impacted her, the girl said: “I had a lot of nightmares about what he did to me and I would cry at night and sometimes in the day.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The girl also wrote that she cannot be around older men his age as she is afraid of what they would do to her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his mitigation plea, the man&#39;s defence counsel, Mohamad Hasbu Haneef Abdul Malik from Trident Law Corporation, sought a lower sentence of at most 10 years&#39; jail instead, noting that there was no pregnancy and no transmission of sexually transmitted diseases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Justice Hoo Sheau Peng noted that the victim did suffer harm after the incident, including suicidal thoughts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She sentenced the man to 11-and-a-half years&#39; jail, with an additional six months in lieu of caning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those convicted of sexual penetration of a minor can be sentenced to between eight and 20 years&#39; jail, as well as at least 12 strokes of the cane.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This article was first published by &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 07:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[BBC sex photo claims are ‘rubbish’, young person’s lawyer tells broadcaster]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227241/bbc-sex-photo-claims-are-rubbish-young-persons-lawyer-tells-broadcaster?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 07:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/2072f5f5-9f88-46fb-a922-beb619da786f_a08ed154.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Allegations that an unnamed BBC presenter paid a young person to pose for explicit photos are “rubbish”, a lawyer acting for the young person has told the broadcaster in a letter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;British media has been gripped in recent days by a report in the Sun newspaper that cited the young person&#39;s mother as saying the presenter paid the now 20-year-old £35,000 (US$44,828) for photos over three years beginning when they were 17.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The presenter, who has not been named by the BBC or the Sun newspaper, was suspended on Sunday following the claims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The BBC reported on Monday, however, that a lawyer for the young person had written to the broadcaster stating that the allegation was “rubbish”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawyer said the young person sent a denial to the Sun newspaper on Friday evening, when it first published the allegation, saying there was “no truth” to it, the BBC said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spokesperson for Rupert Murdoch&#39;s Sun tabloid said in response to the BBC report: “We have reported a story about two very concerned parents who made a complaint to the BBC about the behaviour of a presenter and the welfare of their child.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Their complaint was not acted upon by the BBC. We have seen evidence that supports their concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s now for the BBC to properly investigate.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;BBC suspends male presenter over sexually explicit images claims&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;BBC News said it did not know the identity of the young person and had not spoken directly to them, nor had it seen the Sun&#39;s evidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier on Monday British police said they were assessing information provided by the BBC about the claims, but there was no investigation into a crime at this stage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The age of consent for sex in England is 16, but images of someone under 18 can be considered child pornography. London&#39;s Metropolitan Police said detectives from its specialist crime command held an online meeting with the BBC earlier on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no investigation at this time,” the police said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 07:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[James Lewis, suspect in 1982 Tylenol poisonings that killed 7 in the Chicago area, has died]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227240/james-lewis-suspect-1982-tylenol-poisonings-killed-7-chicago-area-has-died?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 06:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/c1c81fb2-522b-402a-89ee-528e5d860744_a7686433.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The suspect in the 1982 Tylenol poisonings that killed seven people in the Chicago area, triggering a nationwide panic and leading to an overhaul in the safety of over-the-counter medication packaging, has died, police said on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officers, firefighters and EMTs responding to a report of an unresponsive person on Sunday afternoon found James Lewis, 76, dead in his Cambridge, Massachusetts home, Cambridge Police Superintendent Frederick Cabral said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Following an investigation, Lewis&#39; death was determined to be not suspicious,” the statement says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No one was ever charged in the deaths of seven people who took the over-the-counter painkillers laced with cyanide. Lewis served more than 12 years in prison for sending an extortion note to manufacturer Johnson &amp; Johnson, demanding US$1 million to “stop the killing.” He and his wife moved to Massachusetts in 1995 following his release.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Lewis was arrested in New York City in 1982 after a nationwide manhunt, he gave investigators a detailed account of how the killer might have operated. Lewis later admitted sending the letter and demanding the money, but he said he never intended to collect it. He said he wanted to embarrass his wife&#39;s former employer by having the money sent to the employer&#39;s bank account.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lewis, who had a history of trouble with the law, always denied any role in the Tylenol deaths, but remained a suspect and in 2010 gave DNA samples to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI). He even created a website in which he said he was framed. Although the couple lived briefly in Chicago in the early 1980s, Lewis said they were in New York City at the time of the poisonings.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Find those cowards&#39;: 2 dead, 28 wounded in US mass shooting&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In a 1992 interview with Associated Press, Lewis explained that the account he gave authorities was simply his way of explaining the killer&#39;s actions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I was doing like I would have done for a corporate client, making a list of possible scenarios,” said Lewis. He called the killer “a heinous, cold-blooded killer, a cruel monster.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The FBI seized a computer and other items from Lewis&#39; home in February 2009 after Illinois authorities renewed the investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The FBI&#39;s Chicago office at the time cited “advances in forensic technology” and said it, along with the Illinois State Police and local police departments, was conducting a “complete review of all evidence developed in connection” with the killings.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s paltry support for private firms leaves its economic backbone in more dire straits than state firms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3227193/chinas-paltry-support-private-firms-leaves-its-economic-backbone-more-dire-straits-state-firms?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/28f31c7d-9a25-4592-93fd-863061608044_4401f807.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Despite receiving more orders than last year, a literal door maker in China&#39;s southwest is struggling to open enough figurative doors to make ends meet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Besides cutting labour costs, the company – a privately held industry leader in the region – has opted to cut profit margins to grab a bigger market share amid an uneven recovery of the world&#39;s second-largest economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though its revenue has been growing so far this year, the company&#39;s profits remain extremely low, said a manager surnamed Liao.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ve got no other option. The goal now is to survive,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In sharp contrast with these types of private plights, strong cash flow and greater loan capacity have helped state-owned enterprises (SOEs) recover relatively faster this year after Beijing put an abrupt end to zero-Covid controls in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jason Liang, who manages a state-owned trading company in Guangdong, pointed to a recent deal that illustrates how state firms continue to have a leg up on their private counterparts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A very simple example – we are now able to send more than US$10 million worth of products to the warehouse of a big buyer [a supermarket chain] in Australia, where they sell the products first, and then we collect the final payment after 90 or 120 days,” Liang said. “Few private company peers can make such big concessions, which means they can&#39;t compete for orders from such big customers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the backbone of China&#39;s 121-trillion-yuan economy, the private sector – a major source of employment and contributor of fiscal revenue – was hit hardest under zero-Covid and continues to point to worrisome uncertainties about what the future holds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite officials from all levels of government continually trying to sweet-talk and reassure private firms and investors since late last year, many continue to flag suboptimal conditions including weakened demand, potential policy changes, weak support and poor growth prospects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Already this month, Zheng Shanjie, director of the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC), has held two discussions with private entrepreneurs to “listen to the real situation [of private companies] from various sides”, including different industries and regions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And in response to specific appeals and suggestions raised by enterprises, China&#39;s top economic planner has vowed to assess the current policies and unveil new supportive measures to help the private sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;German firms&#39; hot take on China business belies Beijing&#39;s charm offensive&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, from industrial output to investment totals and revenue, a recovery in the private sector has been slower than at the state level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the first five months of this year, fixed-asset investment by private firms fell 0.1 per cent from the previous year, in sharp contrast with the rise of 8.4 per cent among their state-owned rivals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Profits of private industrial enterprises with annual revenues of at least 20 million yuan fell 21.3 per cent to 683.8 billion yuan in the first five months of this year, compared with a drop of 17.7 per cent to 962.5 billion yuan by SOEs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the latest data from the State Administration for Market Regulation, the number of registered private enterprises in China surpassed 50 million in early April and reached 50.9 million by the end of May – a 3.7-fold increase from 10.86 million at the end of 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And private enterprises now account for 92.4 per cent of all companies in China, the official figures show.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts and analysts say that only increased fairness in access to resources and financing, with certain and stable policies, are likely to quell the current confidence crisis among private enterprises. And in the absence of such measures, some say China&#39;s recovery outlook could be delayed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The lack of confidence in private capital has been an issue of great significance that may lead to systemic impacts,” said Liu Yuanchun, president of Shanghai University of Finance and Economics, in an interview with the Finance 40 Forum think tank in late June. “In particular, we should pay attention to the existence space for the private sector, its availability to funds and whether it can enjoy fair competition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should also aim to help SMEs effectively obtain orders and reverse the worsening of profits and balance sheets.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even in the most promising private sectors, such as new energy, investors are not immune to the effects of policy uncertainties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, Billy Wang leased a piece of land spanning nearly half a square kilometre in Guangdong province, to install centralised photovoltaic power panels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang registered the solar-energy project with local authorities but was told two months ago to put plans on hold, as local authorities had tightened restrictions on land use to ensure that enough cropland was available – in line with a nationwide campaign to ensure that China feed its people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So now Wang is at risk of losing his nearly 20-million-yuan investment if the project ends up being axed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lin Caiyi, vice-president of the China Chief Economist Forum Research Institute, said the lack of resources and confidence are behind the disparity in a post-pandemic recovery, and that support for the private sector should not be merely lip service.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China warned of &#39;big&#39; debt risks in drive to narrow urban-rural gap&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The most important thing is to ensure the rule of law. At the beginning of China&#39;s reform and opening up, policies were very stable, thus giving people strong confidence, which led to prosperity in the private sector. However, in recent years, private enterprises have seen great instability and unstable policies,” Lin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Funds flying into SOEs, such as in property financing, have been much more than those to private firms,” she added. “The private sector is underprivileged in obtaining resources. Despite pledges to treat them equally and fair, concrete moves are still lacking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On the other hand, SOEs can rely on state support as a last resort in difficulties, while entrepreneurs have to take risks and bear losses all by themselves. Only once they are confident will they be willing to invest. Currently, however, the general expectations are quite unsettling.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a Fitch report released in early May, steady new contract signings and a large backlog of orders in water resources management, hydropower, renewable energy, environmental protection and municipal development have helped ensure that state-owned engineering and construction companies are achieving above-industry-average growth rates in 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That will lead to private peers ceding more market share to state-owned enterprises, Fitch expects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Wenkui, a researcher with the Development Research Centre of the State Council, warned that this imbalance in recovery will affect China&#39;s overall economic growth and potentially hinder the nation&#39;s long-term modernisation plans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said in an interview with Thepaper.cn in late May that the prolonged delay of payments by local governments to private companies become more severe during the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In addition, endless inspections and rectification conducted by some local governments, which were random but compulsory, would harm basic rights and interests of private enterprises and individuals,” Zhang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Market-oriented reform based on the rule of law should be the very core of China&#39;s efforts to build a business-friendly market environment, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid disparities in the business recoveries, coupled with a beleaguered property market and weak export outlook, many private entrepreneurs are bracing for fierce competition in the second half of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2023 is the most difficult year since I started my business,” said Joe Li, who has run an underwear-manufacturing business in Guangdong for 25 years. “Competition in the second half of the year will be fiercer.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How will China&#39;s SMEs shape up amid troubling return of triangular debt?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Despite bouncing back with their best performance since the first quarter of 2021, more than one-third (37.6 per cent) of small firms still closed or suspended operations in the first quarter of 2023, according to a survey of more than 11,000 micro- and small businesses by the Centre for Enterprise Research at Peking University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The survey findings, released in May, said more business owners were confronted with high costs and fierce competition, while calls were on the rise for supportive policies to reduce costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We had been very optimistic at the beginning of this year, expecting sales to at least double last year,” said Jeff Jiao, a sales engineer of Shenzhen-based consumer robots company, “but … there was no any growth in sales in the first half of the year.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zeng Zhao, who runs a Shenzhen-based tech company developing educational software, said the current state of China&#39;s economy also affects innovation, as small tech firms find it “very difficult” to acquire financing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Domestic demand is no longer an attractive selling point to lure investors,” he said. “Private enterprises do not have enough qualifications nor collateral for bank loans, and it is not easy to get a loan, so the capital ends up going to state-owned enterprises.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his Finance 40 Forum interview, Liu with the Shanghai-based university called for a “redefining of fiscal policy” to directly subsidise the private sector while further cutting taxes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should have new channels to directly inject lifeblood and subsidises into private sectors, in addition to indirectly aiding them,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also suggested that authorities should place more orders with the private sector in government procurements, and be more innovative in setting laws and regulations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;David Fang, who runs a business making and exporting baking tools in Yiwu, Zhejiang province, said his business operations have “turned out to be harder” despite a strong inflow of potential buyers to the city this year and a rise in orders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Competition is fiercer, while profits are falling,” Fang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like China&#39;s most dynamic market players, Fang is trying to do his homework while weathering the headwinds. This includes cutting jobs, prioritising innovation, shifting away from low-profitability products, and turning inward with an eye on the domestic market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is a market worth billions of yuan, and it&#39;s worth taking great effort to explore and expand,” Fang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Beata Mo&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Volcano erupts near Iceland’s capital Reykjavik, gushing lava and billowing smoke]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227239/volcano-erupts-near-icelands-capital-reykjavik-gushing-lava-and-billowing-smoke?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 05:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/e8f1a747-0cbd-4031-b56f-5658b863e387_42538606.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A volcano erupted near Iceland&#39;s capital on Monday, the country&#39;s meteorological office said, marking the third time in two years that lava has gushed out in the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local media footage shows a massive cloud of smoke rising from the ground as well as a substantial flow of lava at the site around 30km (19 miles) from Reykjavik.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to an Agence France-Presse reporter, the smoke can be seen from the road connecting the capital to the international airport, with cars pulled over and people taking pictures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The eruption is taking place in a small depression just north of Litli Hrutur (&#39;Little Ram&#39; in Icelandic) from which smoke is escaping in a northwesterly direction,” the meteorological office said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are three fissures with lava basically running in all directions,” Thorvaldur Thordarson, Professor in Volcanology at University of Iceland, told Agence France-Presse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the fissures are in total around 200 to 300 metres long and “it is a low intensity, effusive eruption.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This means “it&#39;s not causing widespread threats due to explosive activity” but “if the eruption continues for long enough it could be a threat to infrastructure.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thousands of small earthquakes were recorded in the area in the week leading up to the eruption, signalling that the magma below the ground was moving and an eruption was imminent.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Thousands evacuated in Philippines as volcano spews rocks, toxic gases, ash&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Icelandic authorities advised against going to the site, located in difficult terrain without road connection, before they have assessed the situation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The magma broke through the ground just a few kilometres from two previous eruptions in the past two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first was on March 19, 2021 in the Geldingadalur valley and lasted six months, while the second occurred on August 3, 2022 in the Meradalir valley, lasting three weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the 2021 eruption, the region had remained dormant for eight centuries, but vulcanologists believe the new cycle of increased activity could last several years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The effusive eruptions that have occurred in this area so far have not been very dangerous, nor have they had any impact on air traffic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 2021 and 2022 eruptions attracted hundreds of thousands of visitors hoping to catch a rare glimpse of an active volcano.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thordarson said the eruption could last anywhere from “a few days” to more than half a year like in 2021, or even longer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Iceland has 33 volcanic systems currently considered active, the highest number in Europe. It has an eruption every five years on average.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The North Atlantic island straddles the mid-Atlantic Ridge, a crack in the ocean floor separating the Eurasian and North American tectonic plates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April 2010, some 100,000 flights were cancelled, leaving more than 10 million travellers stranded, following the massive eruption of the Eyjafjallajokull volcano.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Indonesia&#39;s Merapi volcano spews hot ash clouds in new eruption&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Other volcanoes, such as Askja in the uninhabited highlands of central Iceland, have recently shown signs of activity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the country&#39;s most dangerous volcanoes is Katla, near the south coast. It last erupted in 1918, with an unusually long pause suggesting an imminent reawakening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 1783 eruption of the Laki volcanic fissure in the south of the island is considered by some experts to be the most devastating in Iceland&#39;s history, causing its biggest environmental and socio-economic catastrophe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Between 50 to 80 per cent of Iceland&#39;s livestock was killed, leading to a famine that left a quarter of the country&#39;s population dead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meteorological impact of the eruption also had repercussions for several years, with some experts suggesting it may have played a part in triggering the French Revolution.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Foxconn exits US$20 billion Indian semiconductor joint venture, slowing country’s global chip hub march]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3227238/foxconn-exits-us20-billion-indian-semiconductor-joint-venture-slowing-countrys-global-chip-hub-march?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/7ac5ab82-2110-4384-8362-5de02a9779de_6287ccad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Electronic components giant Foxconn Technologies, best known for assembling iPhones and other Apple products, on Monday announced it was withdrawing from a multibillion-dollar semiconductor joint venture with a Mumbai-based metals and mining conglomerate, dealing a blow to India&#39;s microchip manufacturing ambitions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The blockbuster US$20 billion partnership with Vedanta Ltd came together last year in a bid to manufacture semiconductors in Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi&#39;s home state of Gujarat. The proposed semiconductor fabrication plant sought initially to produce some 40,000 40-nanometre chips per month for mobile phones, consumer electronics, automotives and network equipment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, Taiwan-headquartered Foxconn said in a statement that it had “worked hard” with Vedanta for over a year “to bring a great semiconductor idea to reality”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But now the multinational had decided to explore “more diverse development opportunities”, it said, and had “determined not to move forward on the joint venture with Vedanta”, adding that the project was now a fully owned entity of the company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though Foxconn did not disclose a reason for its exit, Rajeev Chandrasekahar, an Indian minister for entrepreneurship, skill development, electronics and technology, said via Twitter that as both companies lacked experience in semiconductor technology, it was expected they would source fab tech from a tech partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Vedanta-Foxconn venture had originally submitted a proposal for a 28nm fab, Chandrasekahar tweeted, but the two could not source an appropriate tech partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More recently Vedanta had submitted a 40nm fab proposal “backed by [a] tech licensing agreement” from a major global semiconductor company that was “currently being evaluated”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chandrasekahar believed Foxconn&#39;s decision would have “no impact on India&#39;s semiconductor fab goals”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;At China-led summit, India refuses to back Beijing&#39;s infrastructure vision&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Last year the Modi government raised questions over an application submitted by the Foxconn-Vedanta venture seeking federal funds under a US$10 billion incentive scheme, Reuters reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Arun Mampazhy, a semiconductor analyst, said it was less surprising that the venture had fallen through and more “that it survived for more than 15 months”. To qualify for federal and state incentives, “there has to be either a partnership with or a production-grade license from a high-volume chip fab”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Foxconn does not qualify as one,” said Mampazhy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid the setback, Vedanta on Monday pledged its commitment to establishing a semiconductor fab in India, saying it would “redouble its efforts to fulfil” Modi&#39;s “vision” for semiconductors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have lined up other partners to set up India&#39;s first foundry. We will continue to grow our semiconductor team,” the company said in a statement on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vedanta had already secured a license for production-grade technology for 40nm chips “from a prominent integrated device manufacturer”, it said, adding: “We will shortly acquire a license for production-grade 28nm as well”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mampazhy said Vedanta&#39;s claim of now owning a license for 40nm technology from a high-volume chip fab “rumoured to be STMicroelectronics” – a Dutch multinational company – meant it could still win approval for government incentives “if the project cost quoted by Vedanta and the equity structure with the technology provider as well as any new business partners” were vetted by an Indian government advisory group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Calling for a “patient, measured and circumspect” approach given the “very complex nature of semiconductor manufacturing”, India&#39;s communications minister Ashwini Vaishnaw in April said the country was working to “ensure a robust ecosystem” to become a major global hub in semiconductor manufacturing over the next 10 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India, the world&#39;s fifth-largest economy, forecast its semiconductor market to be worth US$63 billion by 2026 under Modi&#39;s “Make-in-India” scheme as American firms like Apple look to diversify their supply chains away from China.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What new defence, tech deals could mean for India-US ties amid China tensions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Last year, Beijing&#39;s stringent Covid-19 restrictions led to an exodus of workers at Foxconn&#39;s largest assembly line in the world in Zhengzhou, China. Bloomberg reported that Apple had lost in production about 6 million iPhone units due to the disruption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Foxconn, which is building other factories for Apple products in the Indian city of Bangalore as well as the state of Telangana, said on Monday it would continue to “establish a diversity of local partnerships that meet the needs of stakeholders”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;American companies are also trying to avoid any potential impact on their business from rising tensions between the US and China over Taiwan, a self-ruled island that Beijing claims sovereignty over and aims to reunite with the mainland, by force if necessary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the great-power rivalry has helped New Delhi lure new investors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, US President Joe Biden and Modi hailed the signing of a memo of understanding relating to semiconductor supply chain and innovation partnership as the two countries coordinate semiconductor incentive programmes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;American memory chip giant Micron Technology, which Beijing in May banned from critical infrastructure projects to “safeguard national security”, has already announced plans to invest up to US$825 million to build a new semiconductor assembly and test facility in India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Separately, Lam Research, an American provider of wafer fabrication equipment and services to the semiconductor industry, has proposed to train 60,000 Indian engineers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And US-based semiconductor manufacturer Applied Materials has pledged to invest US$400 million to establish a collaborative engineering centre in India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s quest to ascend the semiconductor food chain could be undermined by a scarcity of workers with skills and experience “specific to the semiconductor industry”, according to A2 Global, a Florida-based electronics and supply chains solutions company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a blog entry published in May, A2 cited “complex and opaque” regulations in India as well as hurdles in accessing required financing among several challenges in the South Asian country.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;India&#39;s Tata Group said to get 5 per cent of Apple&#39;s total iPhone orders in 2023&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“India is nowhere close to China when it comes to a strong industrial base, especially for sophisticated hardware manufacturers such as semiconductors,” Anu Anwar of Harvard University&#39;s John K. Fairbank Centre for Chinese Studies told American media outlet The Wire China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s infrastructure was “a few decades behind [that of] China, and the business environment is a nightmare”, Anwar said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Monday&#39;s joint venture news will not have a “significant and long-term impact” on India&#39;s semiconductor ambitions because both Foxconn and Vedanta lacked prior experience, according to Aadil Brar, a visiting scholar at National Chengchi University in Taipei. In all the other deals announced during Modi&#39;s recent visit to Washington, at least one company has chips experience like Micron, he noted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Brar said the failed venture showcased “the difficulties of setting up a complex industry” like a semiconductor fab initiative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The failure of the Foxconn-Vedanta joint venture will raise doubts about Micron&#39;s plans to set up a fab in India,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Micron has a long history in manufacturing semiconductors with knowledge of the semiconductor ecosystem from design to fabrication plants, he said, describing its deal in India as “on more solid footing – at least for now”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 05:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘This is a historic day’: Turkey agrees to back Swedish Nato bid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227237/historic-day-turkey-agrees-back-swedish-nato-bid?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 04:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/26bfd47b-2137-43dd-82bb-a95e36e44382_b5aa9c50.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Turkey&#39;s President Recep Tayyip Erdogan agreed on Monday to forward Sweden&#39;s application to join Nato to his parliament for approval, the alliance&#39;s head Jens Stoltenberg said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After talks in Vilnius with Erdogan and Sweden&#39;s Prime Minister Ulf Kristersson, Stoltenberg said Turkey had agree to move forward, declaring: “This is a historic day.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Erdogan has agreed to forward the Accession Protocol for Sweden to the Grand National Assembly as soon as possible and work closely with the assembly to ensure ratification,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Surprise move as Erdogan links Sweden&#39;s Nato bid to Turkey&#39;s EU hopes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A separate joint statement was issued, outlining the agreement between Sweden and Turkey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turkey has been holding up Sweden&#39;s application to join the Atlantic alliance, accusing Stockholm of harbouring Kurdish activists Ankara regards as terrorists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And on Monday, Erdogan upped the stakes further, demanding that the European Union revive Turkey&#39;s stalled EU membership bid as a precondition for Sweden joining Nato.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the statement issued after the three-way talks stated that Turkey and Sweden would work closely in “counterterrorism coordination” and also boost bilateral trade ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Sweden will actively support efforts to reinvigorate Turkiye&#39;s EU accession process, including modernisation of the EU-Turkiye Customs Union and visa liberalisation,” the statement said, using the UN&#39;s official spelling of Turkey.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 04:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI as silver bullet? Bangladesh futureproofs its education with frugal innovation instead]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3226970/ai-silver-bullet-bangladesh-futureproofs-its-education-frugal-innovation-instead?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/6a8f82c9-fdfe-4d10-acc5-1944d1afcc73_a1492d55.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;世界再次被最新的技术热潮席卷。人工智能 (AI) 被视为伟大的转折点，许多人认为它将带来一个要么丰富，要么毁灭的新时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着道德恐慌降临，这种歇斯底里席卷了教育界。机构； ChatGPT 之于写作和研究就像计算器之于算术一样。同样，乐观的评论家宣称人工智能是学习个性化的灵丹妙药，可以在世界范围内创造公平的竞争环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人工智能对教育的真正影响还有待观察。作为孟加拉国创新计划 a2i 的顾问，我不禁有一种似曾相识的感觉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在人工智能狂热之前，区块链被宣传为巨大的颠覆性力量，它将重新分配财富并在网上带来信任和所有权。在教育领域，区块链被视为解决从认证认证到考试验证等诸多弊病的灵丹妙药。然而，区块链对教育的影响虽然真实，但却是有限的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们不应该把注意力集中在最新的炒作技术上，而应该将注意力集中在简单、具有成本效益的实施上，这些实施可以真正改变教育的现状。我们对待教育的方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在孟加拉国，我们有一种“节俭创新”的理念，这需要对我们的教育系统进行低成本的改变，从而取得不成比例的成果。疫情期间就是一个例子。尽管学校关闭了 18 个月，但课程没有停止超过两周。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校一关闭，政府就开始将免费的议会电视频道变成远程频道。学习频道。结果令人震惊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Covid-19 之前，孟加拉国有一个一刀切的学习计划。在线教育意味着每个学生的学习都变得个性化。环境而非设计引发了向个性化学习的转变。这为我们今天在孟加拉国实现“智能学习”方法的愿景提供了信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孟加拉国在调整教育公共服务方面的速度比许多发达国家快得多。原因很简单。与其他人口众多的新兴经济体一样，在孟加拉国，风险要高得多。有了受过良好教育、年轻且具备数字化能力的劳动力队伍，一个国家就可以跨越发展阶段。但受教育程度低且无所事事的年轻人可能会破坏一个国家的稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孟加拉国有超过 4500 万年龄在 15 至 29 岁的年轻人。根据其到 2041 年成为数字化国家的愿景，建立了坚实的基础今天，面向未来的技能将被证明至关重要。毫不奇怪，如今孟加拉国十分之九的求职者需要具备数字技能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当然，孟加拉国向更加混合的学习方法的转变并不是从大流行开始的。向数字化学习方法迈进的举措早在 2010 年就开始了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;培养具有数字素养的一代的需要催生了一种更注重解决问题而不是记住事实的学习方法。学校也正在转向实时评估学生，而不仅仅是在紧张的考试条件下进行评估。这有助于改善学习反馈，并使教师能够提供更加个性化的学习计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;依靠同理心并更新教育，以保持人类相对于人工智能的优势&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该方法扩展到教师及其学生训练也。接触到全国各地的大量教师，尤其是农村地区的教师，可能是一项挑战。因此，引入了混合方法，包括通过 MuktoPaath 电子学习平台进行在线培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过实时仪表板监控培训传播情况，据观察，更多来自农村地区的教师完成了课程与城市地区相比，显示了技术在增加培训机会方面的力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然孟加拉国在推动创新、混合学习方法方面处于领先地位，但它绝不是独一无二的。卢旺达在培训医护人员方面采取的混合方法促进了艾滋病毒/艾滋病护理。肯尼亚桥梁国际学院是采用混合学习方法的低成本私立学校，其学生在小学毕业考试中始终取得比全国平均水平高得多的成绩。混合式教育使用简单的数字工具来实现真正的社会流动性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要点很简单。在许多情况下，发展中国家别无选择，只能加速建立适合迅速到来的未来的教育体系。然而，这并不是因为对某一特定技术的痴迷。相反，它是通过一系列数字工具的低成本但高影响力的融合来实现的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在教育方面，没有灵丹妙药，即使对于人工智能也是如此。相反，像我国这样的国家正在关注那些已经被证明有效的解决方案，而不仅仅是承诺有效的解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russian shelling kills 7 at Ukraine aid point; regional governor slams attack as ‘war crime’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3227236/russian-shelling-kills-7-ukraine-aid-point-regional-governor-slams-attack-war-crime?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 03:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/9c5a9c3c-d20f-4c57-acfc-510968deede1_b74f2b6a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯对乌克兰南部奥里希夫镇援助中心的炮击已造成七人死亡紧急服务部门周一表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地区州长尤里·马拉什科称其为“战争罪”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们袭击了住宅区的人道主义援助运送点，”马拉什科&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“四人当场死亡：分别为43岁、45岁和47岁的女性，以及一名47岁的男性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;今年有多少俄罗斯人死亡乌克兰？数据揭示了严格保守的秘密&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;紧急服务部门表示，死亡人数此后有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“救援人员从废墟下移出了三具没有生命迹象的尸体。 The number of dead has risen to seven”, Ukraine&#39;s emergency services wrote on Telegram.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Orikhiv, with a pre-war population of around 14,000 people, is in the frontline southeastern region of Zaporizhzhia, which Russian leader Vladimir Putin claimed to have annexed last year despite not having full military control over it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine&#39;s prosecutor general said in a statement the strike had occurred a day earlier at 1:20pm local time and that 13 people were injured, in addition to those killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It released images showing a red-brick two-storey building partially collapsed and surrounded by debris and snapped roof beams.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Orikhiv is near the front line where Ukrainian soldiers last month were pushing to recapture heavily fortified positions from Russian forces.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[China warns its citizens to beware of ‘entrapment’ by US police]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3227235/china-warns-its-citizens-beware-entrapment-us-police?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 03:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/5390ab4b-a7c1-437e-b979-dce299eddd8d_db4c42fd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国向前往美国的公民发出不同寻常的警告，谨防“被困” ”，尽管最近双方接触有所加强，但双边紧张局势仍在持续。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“前往美国旅行的中国公民应更加警惕，谨防落入美国的陷阱和陷阱。北京外交部周一在其领事司官方微信账户上发布的安全警告中表示，“逮捕、诱捕”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然北京定期提醒公民注意枪支和枪支在美国的种族暴力事件中，很少明确指出任意拘留的危险。中国本身也经常被指控对本国人民进行此类拘留。它还面临着为追捕中国人而进行域外警察行动的指控——政府否认了这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一的警告是在第二任拜登财政部长珍妮特·耶伦高调访问北京之后发出的。继国务卿安东尼·布林肯之后，政府内阁成员最近几周也将访问。耶伦宣称世界上最大的两个经济体之间的关系更接近于“更加稳固的基础”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国呼吁中国进一步努力的一个领域是遏制非法合成毒品贸易，以帮助应对芬太尼危机。 China&#39;s statement on Monday alluded to disagreements in that regard.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statement cited arbitrary US arrests and the cross-border abduction of Chinese citizens, characterising the actions as based on fentanyl issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, the Justice Department announced the arrest of two individuals and the unsealing of three indictments charging China-based companies and their employees with fentanyl-related crimes.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Was China&#39;s &#39;rainbow reception&#39; for Janet Yellen warmer than Blinken&#39;s &#39;snub&#39;?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Foreign Ministry statement also blasted the US for “malicious smearing of China&#39;s pursuit of fugitives.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, the Department of Justice accused 44 individuals living in China and elsewhere in Asia of harassing Chinese dissidents in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China also asked its citizens in the US to pay close attention to local security situations, citing frequent incidents of gun violence and discrimination against Asians.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Kevin Spacey may have drugged alleged victim before sexual assault, UK court told]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227233/kevin-spacey-may-have-drugged-alleged-victim-sexual-assault-uk-court-told?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 01:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/11/5164ae72-e6c6-455a-8448-58505778a2ca_8f39dfb3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;凯文·史派西的一名据称受害者周一告诉伦敦法庭，他相信奥斯卡奖- 获奖的美国演员在他昏倒后给他下了药，然后对他进行口交。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;史派西正在伦敦南华克皇家法院受审，罪名是对四名男子实施了十几项历史性性犯罪，当时这些男子在他们的监狱里长大。 20 多岁到 30 多岁，2001 年至 2013 年间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 63 岁的老人否认了所有指控，他的律师帕特里克·吉布斯 (Patrick Gibbs) 在审判开始时表示，陪审团将听到一些“该死的谎言” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;审判于周一进入第三周，听取了第四名申诉人的证词，他将史派西描述为“卑鄙的性掠夺者”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名男子无法身份不明，声称 2000 年代末史派西在史派西位于伦敦的公寓里昏倒时对他进行了性侵犯，然后对他进行了口交。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子在屏风后亲自提供证据，否认了吉布斯的建议他同意了，并说他在性行为前“睡着了，或者，我相信，被下了药”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉布斯说，“在戏剧界众所周知，史派西先生喜欢与男人调情” ”，据称受害者接受了这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;律师表示，在史派西据称将脸埋在胯部后，申诉人继续与史派西交谈，这意味着他“在公寓里看起来很舒服”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;“滑稽”演员凯文·史派西试图给我打扮，一名男子告诉法庭&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;所谓的受害者否认这是真的，说：“我感觉自己被鲨鱼围住了”。他还形容史派西“残暴、卑鄙（和）恶心”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示，他已在英国对史派西提起民事诉讼，寻求约 40 万英镑（约 51 万美元）的赔偿，但他补充道： “我想要的是刑事司法。”该男子表示，如果史派西向他道歉，他将“放弃一切”，但他认为这是“值得怀疑的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称的受害者他告诉警方，他在 20 多岁时写信给史派西寻求关于自己刚刚起步的演艺生涯的建议，并在酒吧喝酒时接到史派西的电话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;史派西问他是否愿意“见面喝杯啤酒，我说‘是的，当然’，”该男子告诉警察。他补充说，他“对与偶像见面的想法感到震惊”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在向陪审员播放的警方录音采访中表示，他们在伦敦市中心见面，然后前往史派西的公寓，两人在那里喝了啤酒，吃了披萨，还抽了一些大麻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称的受害者说，他感谢史派西的帮助，而这位演员“张开双臂，他‘来这里’，但我没有，我想有点奇怪”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说史派西当时“基本上只是用脸摩擦我的胯部”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方询问该男子是否想离开。他说他感到“脆弱”，但补充道：“仍然存在着那个琐碎的疑问……也许我在这里很混蛋，也许这就是戏剧世界。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还说他确实这么做了。不想“惹恼演艺界那么有权势的人”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子告诉警方，他随后睡着了，他说这很不寻常，几个小时后醒来时，史派西“只是对我进行口交......我醒来时发现这件事发生了”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，他告诉史派西停止，之后演员告诉他离开，不要告诉任何人发生了什么事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;h3>;法庭告知，史派西“最喜欢的攻击方式”是“抓住男人的胯部”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;后来在接受采访时，该男子表示，他被告知史派西喜欢“年轻、直的男人” ”，但随后并不关心，因为他“当时并不知道他（史派西）是一个掠夺者”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉布斯说，史派西的电话记录显示，演员在凌晨 1 点之前给所谓的受害者打电话。据称，他在被指控的袭击发生当天就离开了史派西的公寓，这表明他在与史派西之间“进行了一些非常亲密的接触后”几乎立即离开了史派西的公寓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;申诉人在法庭上从屏风后面提供证据，回答说：“不，那是不对。我早上就醒了。”他还说：“没有发生任何双方同意的事情。”吉布斯还表示，该男子在涉嫌袭击后不久就给史派西发短信。投诉人表示，他想录制史派西承认所发生事情的录音，但他们没有再见面。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 01:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US-China relations: Yellen, Blinken meetings won’t fix weakening foundation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227081/us-china-relations-yellen-blinken-meetings-wont-fix-weakening-foundation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.11 01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/34d843c4-2990-4ab4-b5b6-47edca670d7b_e5af44cf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“我们相信，确保我们美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦在上周对北京进行为期四天的访问之前表示：“高层之间有直接、明确的沟通渠道。”在首次访问中国时，她发誓尽管在一系列问题上存在分歧，但仍将帮助促进“稳定和建设性的关系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦明确表示，有“足够的空间”中美双边贸易以及具有全球意义的合作倡议，特别是针对气候变化的合作倡议。她表示，美国不会对中国采取零和博弈，而是致力于建立长期的贸易和投资关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的此行是在国务卿安东尼·布林肯访华后不久进行的。上个月对北京的访问强调了为稳定世界上最重要的双边关系而做出的不断努力。美国最高气候特使约翰·克里预计将于本月晚些时候访问，双方将探讨就共同关心的领域恢复双边对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两个超级大国之间的长期缓和仍然是一项艰巨的任务，不过，由于针锋相对的制裁，美国经济战略的保护主义倾向日益明显，加上美国民众对中国的不信任感日益增强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公平地说，耶伦的访问对许多人来说是令人鼓舞的。尽管她对保护美国企业在华利益的必要性提出了挑衅的立场，但她还是与中国高层技术官僚进行了亲切的会面。其中包括会见李强总理，他谈到在经历了风雨飘摇的一年后，双边关系可能出现彩虹；以及会见中国经济沙皇和副总理何立峰，他以倡导对外国投资进一步开放而闻名。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;至关重要的是，耶伦强调美国将如何“寻求多元化，而不是与中国经济脱钩”，而是通过更加精准的“去风险”战略，专注于增强其供应链弹性和国家安全。她访问的最终目的是为两国关系奠定基础，阻止世界两个主要大国之间互动的危险螺旋式上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管没有宣布重大外交突破，但她的访问为两国关系的进一步发展铺平了道路。美国总统乔·拜登和国家主席习近平举行双边峰会。这可能会在 9 月份在新德里举行的 20 国集团峰会或 11 月份在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织会议期间到来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使在经济方面，也存在三个相互关联的因素，这些因素具有重要意义。两国领导人谈判长期缓和的能力受到限制。首先，美国已经转向“美国优先”的经济战略，这超出了特朗普政府的做法。耶伦在中国之行期间表示，“转向市场改革符合中国的利益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，拜登政府对经济采取了更加保护主义的态度。早在 2020 年，未来的国家安全顾问、当时的拜登高级助手杰克·沙利文 (Jake Sullivan) 与人合着了一份报告，内容是美国需要如何采取积极的经济战略，既保护中产阶级，又确保国家保持同样的规模。在尖端行业中尽可能领先。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;抛售房产还是减少假期？中美中产阶级为艰难的2023年做准备&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自上台以来，拜登政府监督了三项关键立法的通过：两党基础设施​​法、芯片和科学法案以及降低通货膨胀法案法案，所有这些都动员了数万亿美元来增强美国的经济基础。在高度两极分化的政治环境中通过如此大规模的立法，证明了两党在美国应对中国挑战的必要性上达成了罕见的共识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了加强其经济基础外，拜登政府还掀起了针对中国尖端产业的制裁浪潮。正如美国顶级智库战略与国际研究中心2022年的报告所言，我们所看到的无异于“美国积极扼杀中国科技产业大部分的新政策”。&lt;/p即使拜登政府明年失去权力，也几乎没有迹象表明美国经济战略将出现重大重启。埃尔布里奇·科尔比（Elbridge Colby）等共和党战略家在制定特朗普政府的国防战略中发挥了重要作用，他们呼吁制定一项针对中国经济和军事实力基础的整体战略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这带来了第二个重大结构性挑战：公众对近期中美关系缓和的怀疑加深。看来美国政策精英对中国的看法得到了更广泛民众的认同。 3 月份公布的盖洛普民意调查发现，只有 15% 的美国受访者对中国的看法非常好或大多好，其中三分之二的受访者认为中国对美国的重大利益构成“严重威胁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前美国公众对中国的看法甚至低于冷战时期美国公众对苏联的看法。随着明年的大选，拜登政府将面临越来越大的压力，要求其对中国保持强硬立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普对中国的关税让美国付出了代价，但看起来可能会持续下去&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;第三个，也许也是最关键的因素是美国经济战略对地缘政治战线的影响。北京一再坚称，恢复制度化的双边对话取决于美国取消制裁，这些制裁不仅针对中国的经济领军企业，还针对国防领导层。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为回应，拜登政府坚称外交应该没有先决条件。 ，几乎没有任何重大妥协的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;结果是，尽管两个超级大国继续加强在南海、台湾的海军存在，但仍然缺乏功能齐全的军事外交海峡和更广阔的西太平洋。 In short, leaders in both the US and China will have to expend significant political capital for a desperately needed diplomatic breakthrough in the near future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>