<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Russia’s top general Gerasimov shown in video, first time since Wagner mutiny]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3227154/russias-top-general-gerasimov-shown-video-first-time-wagner-mutiny?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 15:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/3c7a44b7-3e08-4f51-aa3f-64667ff10232_385480c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯最高将领、总参谋长瓦列里·格拉西莫夫正在命令下属在周一发布的一段视频中，他要摧毁乌克兰的导弹基地，这是自 6 月 24 日雇佣兵叛变失败以来，他首次公开露面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坐在军事指挥室的白色皮革座椅上，主持与高级将领的会议视频通话中，67 岁的格拉西莫夫正在下达命令，其中包括向俄罗斯强大的军事情报部门 (GRU) 下达命令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格拉西莫夫被告知乌克兰导弹袭击了莫斯科从乌克兰吞并的克里米亚2014 年，罗斯托夫和卡卢加地区的会议于周日受阻，并讨论俄罗斯应如何应对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防部表示，录像显示格拉西莫夫周日在开会。视频将他描述为俄罗斯武装部队总参谋长和莫斯科驻乌克兰部队指挥官，这是他在兵变之前担任的职位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频显示，弗拉基米尔·普京总统保留了他的两支最强大的军队国防部长谢尔盖·绍伊古和格拉西莫夫仍然坚守岗位，尽管雇佣军领导人叶夫根尼·普里戈任要求解雇他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任 6 月 24 日的兵变旨在与绍伊古和格拉西莫夫算账，他称他们是无能的叛徒他将克里姆林宫领导人拉入了一场失败的战争，这场战争暴露了俄罗斯军队的腐败和腐败。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我很害怕”：白俄罗斯当地人担心瓦格纳战士可能到来&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;在视频中，格拉西莫夫询问并听取了航空航天部队谢尔盖·苏罗维金将军的副手维克托·阿夫扎洛夫的报告，自叛变以来，维克多·阿夫扎洛夫一直没有公开露面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚苏罗维金在叛乱前担任俄罗斯驻乌克兰军队副司令，多次受到普里戈任的赞扬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯媒体因其冷酷无情而被昵称为“世界末日将军”。苏罗维金正式成为航空航天部队总司令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们注意到，航空航天部队已经完成了这项任务，”格拉西莫夫说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他询问了航空航天部队部队和格鲁乌军事情报部门确定“导弹和其他敌方打击武器的储存地点和发射位置，以计划先发制人的打击”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防部发布的视频显示了视频的参与者通话内容模糊不清，但明确显示了苏罗维金的副手阿夫扎洛夫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦格纳的全副武装部队控制了俄罗斯南部城市顿河畔罗斯托夫，然后迅速移动到距离莫斯科 200 公里（124 英里）以内的地方，一路上几乎没有遇到军队的抵抗。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯电视节目显示普里戈任的“宫殿”正在采取行动抹黑他&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据白俄罗斯总统亚历山大·卢卡申科斡旋的协议，普里戈任取消了兵变.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自叛乱结束以来，普里戈任也没有公开露面。卢卡申科上周表示，这位瓦格纳领导人在访问他的国家后已返回俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任能够轻松进出俄罗斯，这引发了人们对与普京的协议条款的质疑。 ，他公开同意允许瓦格纳创始人与任何想加入他的战士一起前往白俄罗斯，并撤销针对他们武装叛变的刑事案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭博社的补充报道&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[After Yellen’s China trip saw these demands made and missteps avoided, Beijing calls to ‘beef up’ US cooperation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3227139/after-yellens-china-trip-saw-these-demands-made-and-missteps-avoided-beijing-calls-beef-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/27039598-ecd7-40b4-810d-7518bcde0fe7_19022d81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京敦促华盛顿取消对中国企业的经济制裁，并呼吁共同努力解决与美国财长耶伦会谈时讨论全球挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国的发展对美国来说是机遇而不是挑战。这意味着好处，而不是风险。”财政部周一在一份声明中表示，在为期四天的访问期间，中国财政部在与耶伦的会谈中总结了中国的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是第二次高层访问乔·拜登的内阁官员在不到一个月的时间里对中国进行了访问，世界上最大的两个经济体正在努力避免失误，试图防止受损的关系进一步恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在会谈中，中国重申了要求美国取消关税、停止遏制中国企业、确保双边投资公平待遇、放松出口管制、取消对涉疆产品的禁令。” “中方希望美方针对双边经济关系中的重大关切采取切实措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“加强双边合作是务实、正确的选择。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;随着美中关系跌至新低，外交秘密渠道仍然有效吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;耶伦周日在北京出发前表示，她访问期间与中国新任经济官员进行的 10 小时双边会谈有所帮助为稳定紧张关系奠定更坚实的基础，她预计未来会有更多接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管她做出乐观的评估，但分歧仍然存在，美国将继续对中国获取先进技术施加国家安全限制&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国已将 1,000 多家中国企业列入制裁名单或出口管制，并正在考虑对美国在华投资实施新的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京方面多次猛烈抨击近年来，由于技术限制、国家安全、人权和台湾等一系列热点问题，华盛顿涉嫌滥用国家安全和广泛的双边关系，跌至新低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她重申，美国并不寻求与中国脱钩，因为这样做对两国来说都是灾难性的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财政部声明补充说，美国表示“无意强迫各国选边站队” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“两国需要坦诚交流，就双边经济的重要问题达成共识，为经济关系注入稳定性和积极性。”声明补充道&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;并呼吁协调应对经济、气候变化、债务减免等全球性挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“面对严峻的全球性挑战，中国希望包括美国在内的发达国家采取行动”它补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“差异不应导致隔阂，而应成为密切交流和沟通的动力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia to host German troops for first time ever as Berlin’s focus shifts East amid rising China tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3227147/australia-host-german-troops-first-time-ever-berlins-focus-shifts-east-amid-rising-china-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 15:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/3644fae9-f521-4a7d-b40b-35096c5c1951_b5fed183.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;德国将首次向澳大利亚派遣军队作为联合演习的一部分与来自其他 12 个国家的约 30,000 名军人一起，突显柏林在亚太地区与中国的紧张关系日益加剧的情况下日益关注该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，德国在亚洲的军事存在不断增强。太平洋，即使这意味着在其安全和经济利益之间走钢丝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于经济上的相互依存性，对于我们德国以及欧盟来说，这是一个极其重要的地区”，陆军参谋长阿方斯·迈斯 (Alfons Mais) 在周一发表的采访中表示，就在第一批德国军队出发前往澳大利亚前几个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是柏林最重要的贸易伙伴，欧洲 40% 的对外贸易流经中国南海，是亚太地区领土争端焦点的航道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年，一艘德国军舰近20年来首次驶入南海。去年，柏林派出 13 架军机前往澳大利亚参加联合演习，这是空军和平时期最大规模的部署。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迈斯表示，多达 240 名德国士兵将参加“护身符”演习，其中包括 170 名伞兵和 40 名海军陆战队员7月22日至8月4日举行的军刀演习是澳大利亚和美国之间最大规模的演习，每两年举行一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“德国中国城”的失败如何反映了欧盟对北京看法的转变&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德国人将与来自美国、印度尼西亚、日本、韩国、法国和英国等国家的士兵一起进行丛林战和登陆作战训练。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的目标是证明我们是可靠且有能力的合作伙伴，为稳定该地区基于规则的秩序做出贡献”，迈斯说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及德国首次向澳大利亚部署军队旨在向中国传达什么信息时，他强调柏林无意对抗&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位中将表示，“了解其他人对世界的看法通常是有意义的”，并补充说，当前的安全挑战比 1990 年之前要不那么明确。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“冷战很容易，这是一个两极世界。今天，我们不能再只关注欧洲……我们必须把自己定位得更广泛。”陆军参谋长强调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迈斯计划参观澳大利亚的德国军队和莱茵金属公司组装拳击手装甲运输车的工厂7 月中旬为两国军队提供车辆，然后前往日本和新加坡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“日本是一个拥有深化双边军事合作潜力的合作伙伴，”他说。至于护身军刀，德国军队已经接到命令返回澳大利亚参加2025年的下一次演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong legislature to launch search for new secretary general to replace veteran Kenneth Chen who retires in 2024]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3227141/hong-kong-legislature-launch-search-new-secretary-general-replace-veteran-kenneth-chen-who-retires?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/5f5d84f8-e441-4452-99e8-b593117d4c16_d74aa589.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港特区政府秘书处将展开招聘工作，物色新任主管立法会主席陈伟安将于明年退休。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会主席梁君彦周一承认陈伟安在过去11年里领导600名秘书处人员的努力，特别是克服“他指的是上一届立法会任期，该任期充满了一些争议，包括 2016 年六名议员因宣誓时的滑稽行为而被取消资格，以及猛烈攻击。 2019 年反政府抗议期间，立法会大楼的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“陈带领他的团队克服了无数挑战，”梁说。 “他还在任期内推动了立法机关的现代化，并采用了各种数字服务来提高其效率和透明度。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港改革区议会法案获得支持，削减直选席位&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;梁振英表示，58岁的陈将于明年8月退休，并补充说立法机关将聘请一家顾问公司牵头招聘工作，从内部和外部物色新秘书长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他强调陈的继任者必须熟悉行政和立法部门的工作，具有出色的领导能力，并具有丰富的公共行政经验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈表示很荣幸能够为立法机关服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“过去11年，我们遇到了很多前所未有的挑战。我很感激整个秘书处能够团结一致克服这些困难。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港区议会改革引发对直选未来的反思&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;陈在来年，他将继续他的工作，包括倡导立法机关采用更多技术并监督立法会综合体的扩建。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前教育部副部长陈宝莲接替吴文华出任秘书长。 2012. 秘书处为立法会提供行政支持和服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Uzbekistan president cements power with election win]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3227143/uzbekistan-president-cements-power-election-win?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 15:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/43af3006-84cf-4ec9-ac65-3c689e2f24f6_eff8ad7b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;乌兹别克斯坦总统沙夫卡特·米尔济约耶夫 (Shavkat Mirziyoyev) 赢得了第三个任期，这将使他继续掌管根据周一的初步结果，到 2030 年，乌兹别克斯坦将成为一个受到严格控制、富含天然气的中亚国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 65 岁的领导人承诺向外国投资和旅游业开放乌兹别克斯坦，并在中亚地区实施关键的国内改革。人口最多的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;初步结果显示，米尔济约耶夫与三名鲜为人知的候选人竞选，最终以 87% 的得票率赢得了周日的选举。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他此前曾担任总理在 2016 年赢得第一个任期并于 2021 年连任之前，他曾在强硬派前任伊斯兰·卡里莫夫 (Islam Karimov) 的领导下担任部长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的宪法公投为他再连任两届总统任期铺平了道路，并增加了他的授权五年减七，这意味着他可以继续掌权到 2037 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌兹别克斯坦是前苏联加盟共和国，拥有毗邻阿富汗的战略位置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;米尔济约耶夫曾接受过工程师培训，他描绘了他自己是一位创建“新乌兹别克斯坦”的改革者，并表示他希望很快将国内生产总值翻一番，达到 1600 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他将连任竞选的重点放在经济和教育上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他结束了乌兹别克斯坦棉田的强迫劳动做法，并释放了在卡里莫夫统治四分之一世纪期间被监禁的政治犯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非政府组织表示，人权状况比卡里莫夫统治时期要好，但仍有很多需要改进的地方，而且当局没有表现出允许真正反对派出现的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧洲安全与合作组织 (OSCE) 表示，这场运动一直“低调，反映出缺乏反对派” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 7 月，针对取消卡拉卡尔帕克斯坦地区自决权的计划爆发了抗议活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;骚乱和随后对穷人的镇压西北地区造成至少 21 人死亡。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[40,000 Hongkongers attended free Harbour Chill Carnival featuring Cantopop singer Kelly Chen, girl group Otome Syndream]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3227145/40000-hongkongers-attended-free-harbour-chill-carnival-featuring-cantopop-singer-kelly-chen-girl?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 15:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/79c5f485-b4ad-4977-86a8-91073ad86737_25cefd67.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;四万人参加了周末举行的 Harbour Chill 嘉年华，其中包括免费音乐会、香港香港旅游发展局周一透露，这标志着政府组织的一项耗资 4,000 万港元（510 万美元）的计划的启动，该计划旨在提振城市精神。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该活动于 2017 年在湾仔海滨举行。周六和周日，第一天出现了一些小问题，观众抱怨只有前排观众才能清楚地看到表演者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些歌迷称，音乐会的海上舞台是一艘驳船，低于视平线，迫使他们爬上障碍物，以便更好地观看粤语流行歌手陈慧琳的首场演出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;音乐会的第二天晚上，香港日本歌手乙女梦梦 (Otome Syndream) 登场。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;狂欢节的前两天是为期五个周末的节目的一部分，吸引了约 40,000 人，其中 4,000 人是音乐会观众。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈柏宇和陈柏宇在音乐会的第一晚表演，而周日的活动则邀请了中国乐队桃园VX点，这是他们首次来到这座城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;《邮报》周日探访湾仔海滨，数百名音乐会观众在观众区等候。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主办方允许已登记门票的居民比演出时间提前约一小时入场。演出开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港维港音乐会引起轰动，但有人说浮动舞台太远&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;汤米·谭永德，26岁工程师，也是音乐迷女团的他说，他花了10分钟才拿到两张票，从远处看演出没有问题，但觉得走到舞台上很乏味。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不知道为什么主办单位安排观众从湾仔码头入场，但舞台却位于红磡海底隧道入口附近。顶着烈日，我们花了15分钟才走到观众区。”谭说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但我很高兴，因为我可以免费和朋友们一起欣赏偶像的音乐。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;46岁的家庭主妇张怡婷也出席了首晚的演唱会，她表示，在看到成龙的表演后，她很高兴能欣赏本地创作歌手冯运谦的表演。星期六。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我昨晚在这里。我的朋友今晚很友善地给了我一张票。今天比较开心，人少了，也没有人发疯、爬栏去看偶像。”张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然我希望舞台能近一点，可以看到偶像。”他们英俊的脸庞。但音乐会是免费的。即使你付了钱在红馆听一场音乐会，也不能保证你能近距离接触表演者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冯和台湾乐队宇宙人参加了活动的后半场。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;25 岁的美容顾问黄月仪 (Aimee Wong Yuet-yee) 与 28 岁的男友刘宗盛 (Jonathan Lau) 一起出席，她表示这场演唱会是一次浪漫的“款待”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我爱冯的音乐。这就是为什么我想注册门票。舞台有点远，但我仍然可以看到他并靠在我男朋友身上欣赏他的音乐。这次活动免费、独特且浪漫。”黄说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港人受邀与 Tyson Yoshi 一起参加耗资 4,000 万港元的海港嘉年华&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;首两个演唱会周末的 14,000 张免费门票上周二，半小时内就被抢购一空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，居民们还聚集在播放海滨表演的大屏幕前，享用着为嘉年华设立的六个小吃摊提供的小吃和饮料。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;38 岁的营销专家杨美凤 (Tanya Yeung Mei-fung) 与丈夫和两个儿子一起来到现场，她坐在屏幕旁边的草地上。她表示，食物的选择非常有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次活动是‘欢乐香港’活动的一部分，但食物的选择非常有限。政府本可以从西九龙艺术公园带来这些餐车来同时宣传这两件事。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有街头表演，包括杂技、舞蹈、X游戏、滑板码头旁还有中国滑板运动员陈野和香港小轮车运动员李森森在码头旁的功夫表演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次嘉年华是旅游局主办的“快乐香港”旅游活动的一部分，未来四个周末将在湾仔海滨继续进行，歌手作曲家黄婉芝和流行说唱宠儿 Tyson Yoshi 预计将表演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;董事会执行董事郑定逸 (Dane Cheng Ting-yat) ，感谢居民和游客的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次活动是一个新的实验。我们会收集反馈并进行相应调整，努力提供更好的体验。”程说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为期一天的户外流行文化节，四月份的类似活动，由 Danny Summer、Elisa Chan Kit-ling 主演和犹大罗海玲以及旅游活动的一部分，吸引了超过20,000名观众和围观者。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How many Russians have died in Ukraine? Data sheds light on closely held secret]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227140/how-many-russians-have-died-ukraine-data-sheds-light-closely-held-secret?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/f8a142a3-bf65-4b8a-967e-d1eeed9a6468_24cb0c98.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;根据第一家独立媒体报道，近 50,000 名俄罗斯男子在乌克兰战争中丧生对俄罗斯战争死难者的统计分析。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两家独立的俄罗斯媒体 Mediazona 和 Meduza 与德国图宾根大学的数据科学家合作，利用俄罗斯政府数据揭示了莫斯科最保守的秘密之一 -入侵乌克兰造成的真正人员伤亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为此，他们依赖于 Covid-19 大流行期间流行的统计概念，即超额死亡率。他们根据继承记录和官方死亡率数据，估计 2022 年 2 月至 2023 年 5 月期间 50 岁以下男性死亡人数比正常情况下多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科和基辅都没有及时提供有关军事损失的数据，而且各自都在煞费苦心地扩大对方的伤亡。俄罗斯已公开承认有超过 6,000 名士兵死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;活动人士和独立记者称，俄罗斯媒体压制了有关军事损失的报道。记录死者已成为一种反抗行为，这样做的人会面临骚扰和潜在的刑事指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管面临这些挑战，Mediazona 和 BBC 俄语组与志愿者网络合作，利用社交媒体俄罗斯各地墓地的媒体帖子和照片，以建立已确认的战争死亡人数数据库。截至 7 月 7 日，他们已经确认了 27,423 名死去的俄罗斯士兵的身份。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰发誓不会在俄罗斯使用集束弹药&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这些只是我们知道名字的士兵，他们的每个案件的死亡人数均经过多个来源核实，”帮助监督调查的 Mediazona 编辑德米特里·特雷什查宁 (Dmitry Treshchanin) 说。 “我们对 Meduza 所做的估计使我们能够看到‘隐藏’的死亡人数，俄罗斯政府如此痴迷地试图隐藏死亡人数，但没有成功。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了得出更全面的统计，来自 Mediazona 的记者Meduza 获得了向俄罗斯当局提交的继承案件记录。他们来自国家遗嘱认证登记处的数据包含 2014 年至 2023 年 5 月期间超过 1100 万人死亡的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据他们的分析，2022 年针对 15 岁至 49 岁男性的遗产案件比男性多了 25,000 起继承案件。预期的。截至 2023 年 5 月 27 日，超额病例数已飙升至 47,000 例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一激增与白宫 5 月份的评估大致一致，即自 12 月以来已有超过 20,000 名俄罗斯人在乌克兰被杀，尽管低于美国和英国情报部门对俄罗斯总体死亡人数的评估。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2月份，英国国防部表示，大约有 40,000 至 60,000 名俄罗斯人可能在战争中丧生。美国国防情报局泄露的评估显示，战争第一年，俄罗斯阵亡人数为 35,000 至 43,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们的数字可能准确，也可能不准确。” Mediazona 编辑 Treshchanin 在一封电子邮件中说道。 “即使他们有俄罗斯国防部的消息来源，其自己的数据也可能不完整。要将军队、罗斯瓦迪亚、艾哈迈特营、各个私营军事连队的所有伤亡统计到一起是极其困难的，其中瓦格纳是最大的，但不是唯一的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“囚犯伤亡，首先由瓦格纳招募，现在由国防部招募，也是一个非常模糊的主题，具有很大的操纵潜力。统计实际上可以给出更好的结果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国蒂宾根大学的数据科学家 Dmitry Kobak 发表了有关俄罗斯 Covid-19 死亡人数过多的研究报告，他独立地获得了按年龄和性别细分的死亡率数据来自俄罗斯官方统计机构 Rosstat 的 2022 年数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他发现 2022 年 50 岁以下男性死亡人数比预期多 24,000 人，这一数字与遗传数据分析相符。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;白俄罗斯领导人透露了瓦格纳领导人普里戈任的下落&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Covid-19 大流行使我们更难弄清楚，如果没有战争，自 2022 年 2 月以来俄罗斯将有多少人死亡。这两项分析都通过将男性死亡率与女性死亡率进行指数化，纠正了新冠病毒对死亡率的持续影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥地利国际应用系统分析研究所的学者谢尔盖·谢尔博夫（Sergei Scherbov）警告说，“数字上的差异仅由于随机性，男性和女性之间的死亡人数就会有很大差异”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我并不是说男性死亡人数不会过多，而是说从统计角度来看，死亡人数的这种差异可能只是偶然的结果，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;失踪但未被正式确认死亡的俄罗斯人，以及在自封的顿涅茨克和卢甘斯克共和国部队中作战的乌克兰公民，不包括在这些计数中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科巴克承认仍然存在一些不确定性，特别是对于老年男性的死亡而言。此外，很难知道有多少失踪的俄罗斯士兵实际上已经死亡。但他表示，这两个因素都不可能产生巨大影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种不确定性有成千上万，”他说。 “结果总体上是合理的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meduza 是一家独立的俄罗斯媒体机构，已流亡运营八年，总部位于拉脱维亚里加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 4 月，俄罗斯当局将 Meduza 指定为“外国代理人”，使其更难获得广告收入。2023 年 1 月，克里姆林宫将 Meduza 列为非法“不良组织”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科还将独立媒体 Mediazona 列为俄罗斯全面入侵乌克兰后，其网站被“外国特工”封锁。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 14:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Tampering with someone’s life’: anger in China over ‘too light’ penalty for teen who sabotaged online university application of rival]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226761/tampering-someones-life-anger-china-over-too-light-penalty-teen-who-sabotaged-online-university?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/a40657a8-9ed6-4124-a8b4-c8516f1e0696_4918571d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一名青少年承认篡改大学申请后被拘留五天&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名向姓少年和被黑客攻击的王姓学生是中国中部湖北省的同一个班级。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两人都参加了今年的全国大学入学考试，在中国称为高考。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方收到王女士的投诉，称她的在线大学申请在7月2日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，她登录官方申请系统仔细检查了自己的详细信息，发现她选择申请的大学已被删除，并被“垃圾学校”字样取代。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;警方追踪到使用王某账户的IP地址，找到了王某的同学向某，后者访问并更改了她的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在警方劝说下，向某第二天承认了这一点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他承认自己偷拍了王某的考生号，然后多次尝试猜测她的密码，才成功登录她的账户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国新闻网站观察者网报道称，向某阻挠王某申请的动机是两人不合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后，当地高等教育招生办公室允许王某更正她的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;向某被处以行政拘留五天的处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的高考每年约有 1000 万中学毕业生参加，由于学生之间相互竞争以获得中国高等教育的高等教育学位，因此竞争非常激烈&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大学申请期在高考成绩公布之后，学生及其家长几乎和考试本身一样重视，他们力求选择与自己分数相匹配的最佳学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;一旦选择，截止日期后不得更改，除非重新参加考试，否则没有第二次选择其他大学的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大陆社交媒体观察家已被被形容为“太轻”的处罚激怒了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“篡改他人生活只判五天？” ”有人问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这和杀人没有什么区别。 “这可能会改变那个人的生活。”另一位人士表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人确实会犯错误，但有些错误永远无法被原谅。”第三位人士表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国的统治下《治安管理处罚法》规定，侵入计算机系统的，最高可处10日以下拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪道德，中国政法大学刑事诉讼法教授”，告诉湖北电视台，此案可能会促使人们对应用系统以及其容易受到黑客攻击的程度进行审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些网上观察者还建议应用系统使用更复杂的身份验证方法，例如短信验证和安全锁定，以防止未来的黑客攻击。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 14:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Global Impact: Japan, nuclear watchdog under intense scrutiny over discharge of Fukushima nuclear-contaminated water]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3227113/global-impact-japan-nuclear-watchdog-under-intense-scrutiny-over-discharge-fukushima-nuclear?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/42497c22-137e-4ed6-8958-f60096f6738d_40449811.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;《全球影响》是一份每周精选的时事通讯，其中包含源自中国的新闻主题，具有重大意义对世界各地新闻播音员的宏观影响。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周，国际原子能机构 (IAEA) 表示，日本计划将 2011 年福岛核灾难产生的放射性水排入海洋，符合国际安全标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但全球核监管机构的批准不但没有减轻邻国和活动人士的担忧，反而招致了强烈反对，尤其是中国，甚至日本国内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际原子能机构总干事拉斐尔·马里亚诺·格罗西 (Rafael Mariano Grossi) 在会上表示在东京举行的新闻发布会上，该机构的“全面、中立、客观、科学合理”的评估表明，日本计划的排放符合安全标准和全球工业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国原子能机构表示，超过 70 per cent of nuclear-contaminated water at the Fukushima nuclear power plant fails to meet discharge limits after going through a filtration system and requires further treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its secretary general, Deng Ge, said that even if international standards are met, the IAEA cannot prove that the discharge is the only or the best option for the disposal of nuclear-contaminated water.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s foreign ministry weighed in by stating that the nuclear watchdog&#39;s report “failed to fully reflect views from experts that participated in the review”, and that its conclusion “was not shared by all experts”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And on Friday, China&#39;s customs extended a ban on food imports from 10 Japanese prefectures, while food from other parts of Japan will face strict 100 per cent screening, including edible aquatic products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Farther south, Hong Kong&#39;s Environment and Ecology Bureau said more risk assessments would be undertaken, while import controls on marine produce might be introduced, including tougher labelling requirements for Japanese food.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not letting their own government off the hook, Japanese activists said they are very disappointed by the IAEA decision, arguing that Tokyo has gone back on its promise that the water would not be released until the plan received the public&#39;s widespread acceptance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even though South Korea said that it respects the nuclear watchdog&#39;s endorsement of Japan&#39;s plan to release treated water into the ocean, Seoul also made it clear that it would issue its own assessment of the IAEA&#39;s findings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The IAEA report and an earlier offer by South Korean Prime Minister Han Duck-soo to drink treated Fukushima water had clearly done little to convince the country&#39;s activists, fisheries and seafood industries , even its consumers, many of whom had stockpiled sea salt and other seafood items.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, South Korea&#39;s top opposition leader Lee Jae-myung even challenged Japanese officials to drink the treated radioactive water if the water is as safe as the officials claimed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, Pacific island nations also called on Japan to delay the release of water from the destroyed Fukushima nuclear power plant over fears that fisheries will be contaminated.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With more countries conducting their own risk assessments and the further reverberations that can be expected, buckle up for a choppy and tempestuous ride ahead in the days leading up to the release of the radioactive water, which reportedly could happen as early as next month.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;60-Second Catch-up&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China imposes de facto ban on Japanese seafood imports amid anger over Fukushima water release plan&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over 70 per cent of Fukushima waste water fails discharge limits and needs more treatment, says China&#39;s nuclear watchdog&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As activists slam IAEA&#39;s approval of Fukushima water dump, others say criticism is &#39;Japan bashing&#39;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Opinion: Our fragile oceans should not be a dumping ground for Fukushima&#39;s radioactive waste water&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Explainer: What to know about Japan&#39;s plan to release treated radioactive water from Fukushima nuclear plant into the sea&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong to carry out more research on Japan&#39;s plan to discharge radioactive waste water from Fukushima nuclear plant into sea, despite UN watchdog&#39;s go-ahead&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Opinion: 5 questions for Japan on its plan to dump Fukushima nuclear plant waste water into the sea&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Deep dives&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scientists from Hong Kong have unveiled a cheap and efficient device designed to test for radioactive contaminants in marine areas.&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;The development team on Tuesday explained the devices, small, gel-filled containers created to check levels of heavy metals in marine areas and dubbed “artificial mussels”, were modified to track the presence of radioactive contaminants instead.&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hongkongers could lose their appetite for Japanese food if the country discharged treated waste water from the Fukushima plant into the ocean, some of the city&#39;s catering sector leaders have said , as lawmakers ramped up calls for a hardliner approach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japanese media outlets on Wednesday reported the scheme could go ahead as early as August, a day after the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) said the plan “would have a negligible radiological impact on people and the environment”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan is pushing ahead with plans to release more than 1 million tonnes of water that it claims have been cleansed of harmful radionuclides from the crippled reactors at the Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power station, despite opposition from neighbouring nations, local residents and environmental groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Japanese government insists its Advanced Liquid Processing System ( ALPS) has eliminated virtually all the radionuclides from the heavily diluted water that will be released into the Pacific Ocean from a 1km-long pipe that has been constructed at the site, with a number of global nuclear energy experts concurring that release of the treated water is the best available option.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japanese officials have urged the Hong Kong government to consider scientific evidence before deciding whether to tighten curbs on importing seafood from the country if it opts to discharge treated radioactive water into the sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country&#39;s consulate in Hong Kong and visiting officials on Friday sought to allay concerns over plans to dispose of water used to cool melted nuclear fuel at Japan&#39;s Fukushima Daiichi power plant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A survey has found Hongkongers plan to buy less food imported from Japan and are more hesitant to visit the country due to Tokyo&#39;s plan to discharge waste water from the Fukushima nuclear plant into the sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong Federation of Trade Unions (FTU) urged city authorities on Friday to tighten restrictions on food imported from Japan, as it released the results of its survey of 601 adults carried out this month on the controversial discharge plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korean Prime Minister Han Duck-soo has offered to drink the waste water from Japan&#39;s crippled nuclear reactors after it has been treated, challenging opposition lawmakers to bring the water to him for a public display of consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han made the remarks at the National Assembly on Monday as critics accused President Yoon Suk-yeol&#39;s government of turning a blind eye to Japan&#39;s plan to release contaminated waste water from the Fukushima nuclear power plant into the ocean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong may toughen labelling requirements for Japanese food if the country goes ahead with releasing contaminated waste water from the Fukushima power plant into the ocean, the city&#39;s environment minister has told lawmakers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Environment and Ecology Tse Chin-wan on Tuesday also said the scope and duration of any ban on Japanese seafood imports had yet to be decided.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Hong Kong&#39;s environment minister on Sunday warned that a potential ban on contaminated Japanese seafood imports could cover more than five prefectures already under restrictions, adding city authorities would boost screening resources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Environment and Ecology Tse Chin -wan told a television programme that the exact location and number of banned import areas in Japan depended on test results from the International Atomic Energy Agency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Global Impact is a weekly curated newsletter featuring a news topic originating in China with a significant macro impact for our newsreaders around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sign up now!&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 14:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[At least 22 die in India as extra-heavy monsoon rains trigger severe flooding, landslides]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3227101/least-22-die-india-extra-heavy-monsoon-rains-trigger-severe-flooding-landslides?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/d4dfcf20-486e-4130-9821-d7c2e5cbe61a_6cc8f214.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Torrential rains across northern India have killed at least 22 people, as well as causing landslides and flash floods in the region, authorities and local media said on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Schools in New Delhi were closed after heavy rains lashed the national capital over the weekend, with 15.3cm of rainfall recorded in one day – the most for 40 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities in the Himalayan states of Himachal Pradesh and Uttarakhand also asked people not to venture out of their homes unless necessary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least 22 people died in floods and landslides in the northern states of Himachal Pradesh, Uttarakhand, Uttar Pradesh, Jammu and Kashmir and Punjab on Sunday, the Times of India newspaper reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the northern state of Himachal Pradesh, flash floods over the weekend brought down a bridge and swept away several shanty dwellings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities used helicopters to rescue people stranded on roads and bridges because of the rain, Asian News International footage showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;People fear venturing out&#39;: dozens die as intense heat sweeps northern India&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Streets across the northern states, including in Punjab, Delhi and Uttarakhand were flooded. In some areas, rescuers used rubber rafts to rescue people stranded inside their homes, local media said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Please stay inside your homes because more heavy rain is expected in the next 24 hours,” Himachal Pradesh Chief Minister Sukhvinder Singh Sukhu said in an appeal on social media late on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many districts in Himachal Pradesh received a month&#39;s rainfall in a day at the weekend, said a senior weather department official.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Delhi, Punjab, and Himachal Pradesh have received 112 per cent, 100 per cent and 70 per cent more rainfall than average so far in the current monsoon season that started on June 1, according to the department.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The weather department predicted more heavy rain for the coming days. Residents also have to deal with flooded roads, traffic jams and power cuts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by dpa&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine goes on Nato membership offensive ahead of summit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227134/ukraine-goes-nato-membership-offensive-ahead-summit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 13:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/73ee9fe7-09a8-41a4-b91f-08093ea990ec_d74a3bbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukraine went on the offensive in its push to join the Nato defence alliance ahead of this week&#39;s Nato summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky told US broadcaster ABC News that he wants “all the decisions to be made during the summit” not ahead of time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t want to go to Vilnius for fun if the decision has been made beforehand,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two-day Nato summit begins in Vilnius, the Lithuanian capital on Tuesday and will focus, in part, on how to bring Ukraine, which is under attack from Russia, closer to the alliance and what security guarantees it can be given after Russia&#39;s war of aggression ends.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ukraine should get clear security guarantees while it is not in Nato,” Zelensky told ABC. “And this is a very important point. Only under these conditions would our meeting make sense.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky returned from Turkey on Saturday – the 500th day of Russia&#39;s full-scale invasion – after a regional tour to drum up support ahead of the summit with Western allies, who have pledged billions in military aid.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine vows it will not use cluster munitions in Russia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A formal invitation to join the 31-member defence alliance is not likely to happen in Vilnius however.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden, who arrived on Sunday in Britain on his way to the Nato summit, said he hoped the military alliance leaders would “lay out a rational path for Ukraine to be able to qualify to be able to get into Nato”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to CNN, he said there were also “other qualifications that need to be met, including democratisation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think there is unanimity in Nato about whether or not to bring Ukraine into the Nato family now, at this moment, in the middle of a war,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bringing Ukraine in now, Biden said, would mean “war with Russia” because of the Nato commitment to collective defence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also in the spotlight in Vilnius will be Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, the main obstacle to Sweden&#39;s attempts to join Nato alongside neighbour Finland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan accuses Sweden of being too lenient on anti-Islamic demonstrations and militant Kurdish groups that have waged a long insurgency in Turkey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sweden recently changed its anti-terrorism legislation and lifted an arms embargo on Turkey. But a man burned a Koran outside a mosque in Stockholm last week, and Erdogan signalled that this would pose another hurdle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He equated “those who permitted the crime” to those who perpetrated it.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Koran burning in Sweden angers Muslim world&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Turkey and the US are also at an impasse over the sale of F-16 fighter jets. Erdogan wants the upgraded planes, but Biden says Sweden&#39;s Nato membership has to be dealt with first.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Underscoring the prominence of Turkey at the upcoming summit, Biden held a lengthy call with Erdogan aboard Air Force One on the way to London. During the conversation, Biden “conveyed his desire to welcome Sweden into Nato as soon as possible,” according to the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It&#39;s not the first time that Erdogan has sought to use a Nato summit for Turkish gain. In 2009, he held up the nomination of Anders Fogh Rasmussen as secretary general but agreed to the move after securing some senior posts for Turkish officials at the alliance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Max Bergmann, a former State Department official who leads the Europe Programme at the Centre for Strategic and International Studies, said there&#39;s growing frustration among allies toward Erdogan, building on concerns about his ties to Russian President Vladimir Putin, democratic backsliding and sanctions evasion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They&#39;ve tried playing nice,” Bergmann said. “The question is whether it&#39;s time to get much more confrontational.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hungary&#39;s prime minister, Viktor Orban, is also delaying his country&#39;s approval of Sweden&#39;s membership. In response, Idaho Senator Jim Risch, the top Republican on the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, is blocking a US$735 million US arms sale to Hungary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least one potentially difficult issue is off the summit agenda. Rather than seek consensus on a new Natp leader, members agreed to extend the tenure of Jens Stoltenberg, who&#39;s held the job since 2014, for a year. It&#39;s his fourth extension.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most members wanted a woman to be the next secretary general, and Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen had been considered a favourite. But Poland insisted on a candidate from the Baltic states because there had already been two Nordic secretaries general in a row. (Stoltenberg was a Norwegian prime minister and Rasmussen was a Danish prime minister.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others are sceptical of accepting a nominee from the Baltics, whose leaders tend to be more provocative in their approach to Russia, including supporting Ukraine&#39;s desire to rapidly join Nato.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;dpa, Agence France-Presse and Associated Press&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese pharma tech giant Wuxi Biologics plans to spin off international business in Hong Kong IPO]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3227127/chinese-pharma-tech-giant-wuxi-biologics-plans-spin-international-business-hong-kong-ipo?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 12:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/3fa8b833-5e13-4946-8c6b-3d38906970a9_524a0b29.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Wuxi Biologics, China&#39;s largest biologic drugs services company, is planning to spin off its international business, Wuxi XDC, in an initial public offering in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wuxi Biologics holds a 60 per cent controlling stake in Wuxi XDC, which will remain its subsidiary after the spin-off, according to a filing submitted to the stock exchange on Sunday. The company did not disclose the amount it hopes to raise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wuxi plans to expand its offering beyond so-called antibody-drug conjugates (ADCs) to “strengthen our in -house discovery and development capabilities and manufacturing capacity”, the filing said. ADCs are biopharmaceutical drugs designed as a targeted therapy for treating cancer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Capital raised from the IPO will go towards building new manufacturing facilities in Singapore, expanding production capacity in China, strategic investments and acquisitions as well as working capital and other general corporate purposes, according to the exchange filing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wuxi XDC saw net profit increase 16.5 per cent in the first quarter of the year to 80.7 million yuan (US$11.16 million) compared to the same period last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Morgan Stanley, Goldman Sachs and JPMorgan have been named joint advisers for the IPO.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shares of parent company Wuxi Biologics, which listed in Hong Kong 2017, jumped as much as 3 per cent in early morning trading on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The announcement comes as a string of biotech companies file to list their shares in Hong Kong. Insilico Medicine, which is based in the city, has set its sights on a US$200 million IPO, according to sources, while Sichuan Kelun-Biotech Pharmaceutical is ready to list on Tuesday, with the aim of raising US$208.6 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s biotechnology ecosystem has grown significantly since the introduction of legislation called chapter 18A, which allows pre-revenue biotech companies to list in the city, said Louis Lau, a partner at KPMG China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The city has become a very attractive option for IPO applicants engaged in specialist technologies,” said Lau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said this is also attributable to Hong Kong&#39;s position as “connector” to mainland China and international markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong is the world&#39;s second-largest fundraising hub for biotechnology after the Nasdaq, and the largest in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lau said uncertainty arising from tensions between the US and China gives Hong Kong an edge over the US market.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 13:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine should shun US cluster bombs, learn from Cambodia’s ‘painful experience’: PM Hun Sen]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3227129/ukraine-should-shun-us-cluster-bombs-learn-cambodias-painful-experience-pm-hun-sen?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 13:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/a337c8a5-960b-4b5e-8342-a4f83832b47d_1a3a25f9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Sen, whose country still grapples with deadly war remnants, has urged Ukraine not to use cluster bombs, after Washington announced plans to send the weapons to Kyiv to fight Russian troops.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Humanitarian groups have strongly condemned the US decision to supply cluster munitions, which can go undetonated and potentially endanger civilians for years to come.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It would be the greatest danger for Ukrainians for many years or up to a hundred years if cluster bombs are used in Russian-occupied areas in the territory of Ukraine,” Hun Sen tweeted on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He cited Cambodia&#39;s “painful experience” of US cluster munitions dropped in the early 1970s, a foreign legacy that has left tens of thousands maimed or killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It has been more than half a century. There have been no means to destroy them all yet,” Hun Sen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As my pity for the Ukrainian people, I appeal to the US president as the supplier and the Ukrainian president as the recipient not to use cluster bombs in the war because the real victims will be Ukrainians.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington said it had received assurances from Kyiv that it would seek to minimise the risk to civilians, with US President Joe Biden admitting that supplying Ukraine with the weapons was a “difficult decision”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United States dropped millions of bombs on Cambodia and Laos during the Vietnam War in the 1960s and 1970s in an attempt to hit communist bases.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why people are risking their lives to clear Cambodia&#39;s landmines&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;And following 30 years of civil war which ended in 1998, Cambodia is among the most heavily mined countries in the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The effects of the US bombing campaign and minefields left from conflict have long been felt, with around 20,000 Cambodians killed over the last four decades after stepping on landmines or unexploded ordnance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Clearance work continues to this day, with the government vowing to clear all mines and unexploded ordnance by 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, a group of Ukrainian deminers visited Cambodian minefields to learn from decades of bitter experience.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 13:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[6 dead in attack at kindergarten in China’s Guangdong province]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3227130/6-dead-attack-kindergarten-chinas-guangdong-province?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 13:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/94fb67c0-d451-4adc-92d8-8fecc6b88f88_faf5ef89.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Six people were killed and one was injured in an attack at a kindergarten in China&#39;s southern Guangdong province on Monday morning, according to local authorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A statement from the Lianjiang Public Security Bureau said the “intentional assault case” happened at about 7.40am in Hengshan town, Lianjiang City. A male suspect, surnamed Wu, 25, was detained at about 8am by local police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a report from Chinese media platform Cover News, the attacker used a knife.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More to follow&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 13:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chunks of concrete fall off Hong Kong industrial building, hitting Mercedes-Benz car on road below]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227131/chunks-concrete-fall-hong-kong-industrial-building-hitting-mercedes-benz-car-road-below?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 13:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/e0e45fed-abf0-4fe6-a082-f5acaa32514d_d7fd95c2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chunks of concrete fell off the facade of an industrial building in Hong Kong&#39;s Mong Kok district on Monday, landing on the roof of a Mercedes-Benz car and the road below.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident – the third such case in the district in eight days – occurred on Tong Mi Road shortly before 10.30am.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong buildings authority under fire over falling concrete from block&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A police spokesman said a piece of concrete fell off an industrial building and hit a car below and no casualties were reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The slow lane of the road section was closed to traffic, according to the force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The site is about 700 metres from the 17-storey Po On Building, on Mong Kok Road, from which fist-sized lumps of concrete broke off from an illegal canopy outside a rooftop flat on July 2 and 5.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;2 arrested&#39; after building canopy collapses, injuring Hong Kong driver&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the July 2 incident, the falling concrete hit a truck, injuring its driver. Police arrested two men on suspicion of allowing an object to fall from the building.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 13:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Scientists to reveal Anthropocene ‘golden spike’, defining the human era]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3227124/scientists-reveal-anthropocene-golden-spike-defining-human-era?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 12:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/66c34b16-993b-45f3-9ba0-106c6d8703b0_15cf8c0a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Since 2009, a cloistered band of hard-rock geologists and other scientists have toiled on a mission of great consequence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday they will deliver the last of their findings – the location of ground-zero for the Anthropocene, the proposed geological epoch borne of humanity&#39;s outsized impact on the planet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In essence, the Anthropocene Working Group was mandated by the high priests of Earth&#39;s geological timeline to answer three questions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first, roughly, is this: would aliens sifting through Earth&#39;s layered rocks and sediment a million years from now discern a human signature distinctive enough to mark a clear geological boundary?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If they did, when would it start?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yes, the Working Group concluded, human appetites and activity have evicted the planet – and its inhabitants – from the stability of the Holocene epoch, which began 11,700 years ago as the last ice age ended.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Extinct-in-wild species in conservation limbo amid 6th mass extinction&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The world is getting uncomfortably hot and its life-support systems are failing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The threshold for the “epoch of humans” first proposed in 2002 by chemistry Nobel Paul Crutzen, they said, should be the mid-20th century.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is when a sharp surge in greenhouse gas concentration, microplastic pollution, invasive species, radioactive traces from atomic bomb testing, and a dozen other markers of our species&#39; growing influence added up to what scientists now call the Great Acceleration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That leaves the question of the “golden spike” – the single lake deposit, coral reef, ice core or other geological repository of evidence that best embodies the Anthropocene.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “winner” will be announced Tuesday in joint press conferences at the Max Planck Society in Berlin and a meeting of working group scientists in Lille, France.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Presented as recommendations, the fruit of the Working Group&#39;s long labours must now be validated by a gauntlet of sceptical, hard-nosed scientists at the International Commission on Stratigraphy (ICS) and, higher up the food chain, the International Union of Geological Sciences (IUGS).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The chances of that happening are slim, according to almost everyone involved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At one level, the issues under debate are narrow to the point of pedantry – rock experts quibbling over whether the Anthropocene merits inclusion in the International Chronostratigraphic Chart, the planet&#39;s official 4.6-billion-year timeline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some geologists say it doesn&#39;t meet the technical criteria, even as they acknowledge a rupture with the past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, marking the end of the Holocene and the start of a new epoch would force us to ponder humanity&#39;s devastating impact.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why more people want a world without humans – it&#39;s not all climate change&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For the first time in Earth&#39;s history, a single species has not only radically changed the planet&#39;s morphology, chemistry and biology, but is aware of having done so.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Crutzen, who earned a Nobel for identifying the man-made chemicals destroying the protective ozone layer, hoped the concept and reality of the Anthropocene would focus minds on the challenges ahead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It could well be a paradigm shift in scientific thinking,” he said at a symposium in 2011.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A dozen years later, many of the scientists who look at how the strands of the Earth system intersect agree.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s the recognition that, &#39;Oh my God, we have tipping points. Oh my God, the Holocene is the only state that can support us&#39;,” Johan Rockstrom, head of the Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The paradigm shift is the realisation that we&#39;re leaving the Holocene and entering the Anthropocene.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other scientists, however, remain unconvinced, including powerful gatekeepers lobbying against the Anthropocene being adopted as a formal epoch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The conditions which brought about glaciation” – a dozen mini-ice ages over the last million years – “haven&#39;t changed, so we might expect that the Holocene is simply another interglacial,” Phil Gibbard, Secretary of the ICS, told the “Geology Bites” podcast last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;World&#39;s first mass extinction was from a lack of oxygen: researchers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He suggested the planet could continue in that pattern for another 50 million years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for the Anthropocene, Gibbard has suggested calling it an “event” covering millennia of human alterations of the environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In geology, he noted, an event can be anything from a single raindrop pitting a lump of clay to the Great Oxidation Event that transformed Earth&#39;s atmosphere some 2.2 billion years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Jan Zalasiewicz, a journeyman geologist who rose to the challenge of leading the Anthropocene Working Group through a forest of evidence and minefield of resistance for more than a decade, that&#39;s not good enough.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Failure to formally ratify the concept, he said, would leave the impression that the Holocene conditions that allowed human civilisation to flourish are still there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Clearly they are not,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am concerned that if the word &#39;Anthropocene&#39; continues to mean different things to different people, then it will lose its significance and simply fade away.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the end, Zalasiewicz said, we can only follow the evidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Science is basically trying to establish what&#39;s real as opposed to what&#39;s not,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And the Anthropocene is real.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong will face higher food safety risks if Japan releases Fukushima waste water as planned, government adviser warns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227125/hong-kong-will-face-higher-food-safety-risks-if-japan-releases-fukushima-waste-water-planned?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 12:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/4ab00bc2-64ca-489a-a0ca-e5832c0f36f2_118182ba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong will face higher food safety risks if Japan releases treated radioactive waste water into the ocean as planned, a leading government adviser has warned, while revealing the administration will announce strengthened monitoring measures within two weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Professor Kenneth Leung Mei-yee, chairman of the Advisory Council on Food and Environmental Hygiene, on Monday also raised concerns about a report published by the International Atomic Energy Agency last week on the plan to discharge water from the damaged Fukushima nuclear power plant into the Pacific Ocean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our concern is that we have no data on whether sea creatures are really safe even at low radiation doses,” Leung told a radio programme on Monday. “If they are exposed to radiation every day … there could be some negative reactions, which will affect their fertility and reproduction.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung noted the level of radiation absorbed by animals would be higher the further up they were on the food chain. They could undergo pathological changes or suffer from cancer if they were exposed to too much radiation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said creatures that lived at the bottom of the sea and filter feeders, such as some shellfish, could also be exposed to relatively high levels of radiation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In this case, their radiation amount could be so high that it will increase the food safety risk,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Leung urged the public not to worry as the highest risk from the nuclear meltdown of the power plant caused by an earthquake and tsunami in 2011 had already passed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung said authorities would reveal further details about a scheme to monitor Japanese seafood within the next two weeks, as there were reports the discharge of water could begin as early as August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As there are plans for waste water to be discharged into the ocean, the government will strengthen our monitoring mechanism, which means escalating our current measures,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Environment and Ecology Tse Chin-wan last month warned that a potential ban on contaminated Japanese seafood imports could cover more than five prefectures already under restrictions, adding authorities would boost screening resources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The five prefectures are Fukushima, Chiba, Gunma, Ibaraki and Tochigi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said a cross-disciplinary task force would immediately ban the import of aquatic products from Fukushima and nearby high-risk prefectures once the nation began discharging the waste water.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong still wary of Japan radioactive water discharge plan, despite UN go-ahead&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Asked if the city should follow Beijing&#39;s policy to ban food imports from 10 prefectures, Leung said Hong Kong used a risk-based approach for its monitoring system. He added the waters in eastern Japan had a higher risk, so restricting seafood from surrounding prefectures was appropriate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whether other prefectures should also be covered would depend on whether the government could obtain more data to see if products from those areas were also affected.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What to know about Japan&#39;s plan to release Fukushima waste water into the sea&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The treated water from the plant will be diluted with seawater and released through an underwater tunnel. It is expected to take up to 30 years to dispose of the 1.37 million tons of contaminated water.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu on Friday said the city would consider banning seafood and agricultural products from “high-risk regions” in Japan, as well as strengthen its monitoring on products from other areas in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japanese restaurant operator Lam Shing-sheung told the same radio programme that existing import restrictions following the Fukushima disaster did not affect their sourcing, as they had access to ingredients from other parts of the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Hongkongers&#39; trust in Japanese food could drop&#39; if waste water plan goes ahead&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said he could only gauge the full impact on the industry when the authorities announced the measures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Lam said businesses had already been affected even before the waste water was discharged, as the country&#39;s plan had given customers a negative impression.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam said about 10 to 20 per cent of customers were ordering less sashimi. Higher-end Omakase restaurants, which typically serve customers high-quality sashimi straight from Japan, had seen business drop by as much as 30 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Omakase refers to a type of meal served in a Japanese restaurant where the dishes are selected by the chef and made from ingredients that are fresh that day.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[European Chamber of Commerce urges Beijing to extend expat employee tax breaks for housing, education amid fears of exodus of talent]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3227116/european-chamber-commerce-urges-beijing-extend-expat-employee-tax-breaks-housing-education-amid?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 11:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/64deb490-7183-4a42-a611-9576c9bfaaf2_efd4bbea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The European Chamber of Commerce (EUCham) in China is lobbying Beijing to extend tax exemptions on a range of employee benefits such as housing and children&#39;s education amid fears their expiry could exacerbate an exodus of foreign talent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the end of 2018, China announced that tax breaks for certain expatriate allowances would be phased out by the beginning of 2022. Under pressure from multinational companies, the government made a last-minute decision in late 2021 to extend the exemptions for two more years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is estimated that a foreign company would have to pay an extra 800,000 yuan (US$110,800) in taxes for a foreign employee with two children if the exemptions were scrapped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some European companies may choose to reduce their headcount in mainland China if Beijing refuses to retain the policy, according to Carlo Diego D&#39;Andrea, vice-president of the EUCham in China and chairman of its Shanghai chapter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As the extension will expire at the end of this year, the European Chamber has continued to advocate for the continuation of this policy at both a central and local level,” he told the Post. “Foreign investors would likely reconsider or significantly reduce the number of cross-border assignments to China due to the additional financial burden.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the business lobby group had sent a letter to China&#39;s Ministry of Finance in May, urging it to consider the EUCham&#39;s recommendations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The chamber&#39;s Shanghai chapter has also urged local authorities to provide timely updates on the tax policy during several meetings with the Shanghai Commission of Commerce between in recent months, D&#39;Andrea said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the end of 2021, the government agreed to extend the transition period for the removal of the tax breaks to the end of 2023, after multinational companies strongly advocated for a continuation of the policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April 2021, more than a third of multinational firms in Shanghai said they were considering moving all or part of their operations out of China in the event that the non-taxable allowances were scrapped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The reduction in foreign nationals may result in an increasing disconnect between companies&#39; European headquarters and China operations, in addition to potentially impacting the investment strategy of companies in China that require experienced executives on the ground,” said D&#39;Andrea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A business confidence survey by the EUCham that was released in June found that one in every 10 members had already relocated or planned to relocate their Asian headquarters away from China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a visit to Europe last month, Chinese Premier Li Qiang told business leaders in Germany that a failure to cooperate is the greatest risk to the global economy, in an apparent effort to promote economic and other bilateral relations with the continent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai has been facing a “brain drain” since it imposed a two-month citywide Covid-19 lockdown in April and May of 2022. Hundreds of foreign professionals have left the mainland&#39;s commercial and financial hub while the number of expats coming to work in the city has decreased dramatically, said Hong Lingyun, a senior executive with recruitment services firm Joinlink Consulting in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The tax burden on foreign companies or employees will be huge if a further extension [of the tax exemption] is not implemented,” said Hong. “The Chinese government is advised to address the matter as early as possible to retain foreign professionals.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Is the tide turning against K-pop? 5 highlights from the weekend]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3227115/tide-turning-against-k-pop-5-highlights-weekend?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 11:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/43f2fde7-9007-498a-a733-5d394eee6b9a_62bfd2fb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;We have selected five stories from last weekend&#39;s coverage across Hong Kong, mainland China, the wider Asia region and beyond that resonated with our readers and shed light on topical issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you would like to see more of our reporting, please consider .&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Faced with dwindling opportunities, some migrant workers roll the dice on where China&#39;s sluggish economic recovery will create the most jobs. But often they end up unable to rent a bed, forcing them to wander the streets at night.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Australia isn&#39;t awash with desperate for-sale signs, but mortgage stress is mounting and defaults may soon follow – especially if unemployment spikes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Characters that the British author met in Hong Kong made it into one of the ex-spy&#39;s Cold War novels, and so did an error that taught him a valuable lesson.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Some fans of K-pop are turning to Thai music and dramas, lured by creative plot lines, “less repetitive” songs, and the “more well-rounded” talent. But even as the “T-wave” spreads, some note that Thailand&#39;s pop-culture industry still has a long way to go.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;After the sudden death of her husband, Heather Ashley found healing through immersion in ice-cold seas, and breathwork, as advocated by the Wim Hof Method. Cold water therapy is proven to lower cortisol, which causes inflammation, one of the Western world&#39;s biggest killers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mexico’s military to take over airports as president tackles corruption, mismanagement]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3227111/mexicos-military-take-over-airports-president-tackles-corruption-mismanagement?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 10:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/c739fac9-83ba-4292-8c20-3e6f7973f6e5_7827344c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Mexico&#39;s armed forces are taking control of the capital&#39;s main airport, and the government plans to give the military control of nearly a dozen more across the country as the president takes aim at corruption and mismanagement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador has been setting the armed forces to a wide range of nontraditional tasks since he was elected in 2018, creating concerns about the separation of the military from civilian life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A new airport was built by the army outside Mexico City a year ago at a cost of US$4.1 billion. It is run by the military but little used. Lopez Obrador says the old airport, the country&#39;s busiest, will be run by the navy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The navy took charge of security at Mexico City International Airport, or Benito Juarez, more than a year ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It will soon have control of everything else, from customs and immigration to handling luggage and cleaning bathrooms, with the imminent publication of a presidential order to make that official.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The list of problems at Mexico City Airport has long included major drug shipments and illegal migration.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Mexico finally sells presidential plane once called an &#39;insult to the people&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Infrastructure was in disrepair, and a number of close calls were reported on the runways in recent years as the airport increasingly had trouble handling flights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The airport also had a reputation for stolen luggage, mismanaged airline schedules, business without contracts and corruption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Lopez Obrador has gone to the armed forces for help throughout his term, giving them some immigration duties and control of ports and customs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They are also building major infrastructure projects such as a tourist train through the Yucatan Peninsula and a new airport in the same area. They even run plant nurseries and tourist trips to a former penal colony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The airport, which is used by some 4 million travellers each month, will be “a company within a naval military entity,” Rear Admiral Carlos Velazquez Tiscareno, the airport&#39;s 73-year-old director, said in a recent interview. But, he said, “this is not going to look like a military department”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unlike the capital&#39;s other airport, Felipe Angeles, where National Guard troops take passenger tickets at the gate, at Benito Juarez the only uniformed military are the 1,500 marines deployed since February 2022 for security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rest of the airport personnel will be civilians but “with clearer rules … that govern with more order and discipline,” Velazquez Tiscareno said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The navy will form a company called Casiopea to run the airport and six others that have “deficiencies” and are “in the hands of organised crime,” Velazquez Tiscareno said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among them will be Matamoros, across the border from Texas, and Playa del Carmen on the Gulf of Mexico.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lopez Obrador has already said that he plans to have a dozen airports in the hands of the army or navy by the end of his administration in 2024. And by the end of this year, the military is scheduled to begin operating its own commercial airline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Mexico City takeover runs contrary to international aviation recommendations that clearly distinguish between military and civilian, said Rogelio Rodriguez Garduno, an aviation law expert at Mexico&#39;s National Autonomous University. But the legal consequences of the move remain unclear.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>