<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Mystery of headless man found in Japanese love hotel, police seek small person wearing wide-brimmed hat]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3227184/mystery-headless-man-found-japanese-love-hotel-police-seek-small-person-wearing-wide-brimmed-hat?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 17:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/3d0ccb8d-1d04-498a-8439-2b63f6399d8e_687e52a5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本一家情人酒店发现一具男子无头尸体。他最后一次活着被发现时，与一名穿着女装的人一起进入大楼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据当地报纸报道，这名男子被警方确认为 Hitoshi Ura，于 7 月 2 日被发现死于一家情人酒店内。日本时报.这起事件发生在日本北部岛屿北海道的札幌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，在情趣酒店附近，警察走近行人，寻找可能导致逮捕肇事者的证据。日本报纸《朝日报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《朝日报》报道，接待员告诉警方，7 月 1 日晚上 10 点 50 分，64 岁的 Ura 与另一人一起进入酒店。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《朝日新闻》报道，大约三个小时后，接待员被告知此人将先离开酒店，而乌拉将独自留在房间里。报告没有说明浦拉是否是通知接待员的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本北海道在渔民被斩首后发布紧急熊警报&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;第二天，警方在日本北海道的浴室里发现了赤身裸体的浦拉。据《日本时报》援引调查人员的话说，他在一间客房内被斩首。警方称，报告称死因是失血性休克。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《朝日新闻》报道，陪同浦良进入情趣酒店的人身材很小。该人戴着宽边黑色帽子，穿着深色衣服，拎着一个大手提箱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，警方注意到 Ura 的手机和个人物品失踪。 7月4日，他的车在停车场被发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“调查正在进行中。据《朝日报》报道，札幌中央警察局侦探金森大树 (Daiki Kanamori) 表示：“我们正在努力收集尽可能多的信息，希望能够逮捕肇事者。”日本的酒店通常设有主题客房并按小时收费。这些情侣酒店经常被那些寻找隐蔽场所进行性接触的情侣使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据 Statista 报道，日本目前约有 4,900 家情趣酒店在营业。据共同社报道，这些酒店不要求居住在日本的客人在办理入住时提供身份证明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本情趣酒店中的死亡事件很少见，但以前也有过此类事件的报道。 2021年，一男一女被发现死在东京的一家情趣酒店内。警方报告称，这名 30 多岁的女子杀死了这名 20 多岁的男子。然后她自杀了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年，一名 46 岁男子和一名 16 岁女孩被发现死在东京郊外埼玉县的一家情趣酒店内。警方称他们是自杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本国家警察没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Two-thirds of applicants get first choice of Hong Kong secondary school through central allocation system, Education Bureau says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3227176/two-thirds-applicants-get-first-choice-hong-kong-secondary-school-through-central-allocation-system?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 17:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/0e55f25a-68df-47a7-ba17-dee007b04920_542fd4d1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;三分之二的申请者通过教育当局表示，中央分配制度比去年略有下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学生将于周二得知结果，但失望的家庭可能会发现今年更难接近他们喜欢的学校 -被称为“敲门”——教育局上周宣布，由于学籍下降，将减少名额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教育局周一表示，有 50,508 名小六儿童，比去年多了 1,060 名。去年加入下一学年的中学学位分配制度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学生分两阶段分配中学学位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一批青少年获得入学学位基于学术和面试表现等酌情因素。在此阶段，学生可以直接向任意两所学校申请，结果将于三月公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在自由裁量阶段未能获得入学名额的孩子将被安排在基于计算机的中央分配系统中，在那里可以根据家庭住址在其“学校网”（学区）中选择最多 30 所学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 66% 的学生通过中央分配系统获得第一选择，低于最后一名创今年历史新高的 71%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;80% 的学生要么在自由裁量阶段获得录取，要么在中央分配中获得首选，低于去年的 83%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;约 91% 的 12 岁学生被分配到两个自行选择的名额之一或集中分配的前三个名额之一，低于去年的 94%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港学校被告知将中一班级的“上门”名额数量减半&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该局证实了《华盛顿邮报》早些时候的报道，上周三表示，学校只能使用中一预留的两个名额中的一个&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经深思熟虑及听取持份者意见后，教育局决定每所中学只设一名复读生名额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;”从 2023-24 学年开始，一个班级可以用来招收非复读生。”学校上周被告知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该局补充说，新政策确保了这些名额将用于其最初用途。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校一致认为，减少上门名额将有助于防止学生转学的“音乐椅效应”，这种效应可能会因学生人数下降而威胁到一些教育机构的生存。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教育局表示，所有参与中央分配程序的学生应于周二前往小学领取中学分配和录取通知书。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港当局计划削减上门帮助不受欢迎学校的地方&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;家长也会收到短信通知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教育官员补充说，中学的报名期将于周四和周五进行。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;边境附近一所学校的校长、教育界议员朱国强表示，二月份取消所有旅行限制后，中国大陆学生回国是原因之一。压低了择校成功率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“疫情发生后，一些学生跨境报考北区小六”，他解释道。 “据我所知，由于竞争激烈，本区有超过200名小六学生被分配到九龙中学就读，比去年还多。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朱补充了另一个原因。比率下降是因为更多的家长和学生在选择传统上受欢迎的学校时更加积极，因为他们可能认为移民浪潮意味着竞争会减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS： &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Crossing between Hong Kong, mainland China partially closed over cracked roads; truck drivers heading north face 1-hour travel delay]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3227164/crossing-between-hong-kong-mainland-china-partially-closed-over-cracked-roads-truck-drivers-heading?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/735af950-808d-425b-a457-c1c541acd34f_b3140dad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周一从香港开往中国大陆的卡车司机面临额外一个小时的行程一天前，文锦渡过境点因罕见的地面沉降造成的“紧急情况”而部分关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日的照片显示，道路出现裂缝，碎片遍布三个过境点。北行车道。三个摊位前面的地面也下陷，导致两个摊位的屋顶破裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频还显示车辆检查站漏水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但香港的一名成员香港运输部门周一表示，检查站的关闭对司机影响不大，因为只有北行交通受到影响，延误时间在 20 分钟至 1 小时之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;大量香港司机过境上路。 &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;本地教育工作者表示，由于暑假临近，该事件不会影响跨境学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;货柜运输总工会主席陈迪修表示跨境学生- 边境卡车司机改用香园围口岸，距离文锦渡检查站约 20 分钟车程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“周一早上，边境检查站交通拥堵。司机将需要额外一个小时才能完成前往大陆的行程，”他说。 “事件并未影响内地至香港的生鲜食品供应……司机仍可在当天内完成工作。”运输署形容事件为“紧急情况”，并表示交叉-往北行驶的边境巴士将改道至香园围管制站。并把巴士之间的等候时间从30分钟调整至约45分钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凤溪第一小学朱伟林校长表示，事件不会对跨境学生造成影响，因为周一是学校假期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有特定年级的学生需要在暑假开始前返回校园，包括周二获得中学分配结果的小六学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“由于该事件不影响南行出行，学生仍可乘坐校车等公共交通工具前往学校。”朱说。 “但他们需要额外的时间回家。通常情况下，到达检查站只需 10 分钟，但他们需要 20 至 30 分钟才能到达另一个检查站。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新计划下香港人开车进入中国内地需要了解什么&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;校长补充说，希望暑假期间能修复北行车道道路，减少对学生过境的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深圳市人民出入境口岸办公室政府周日晚上表示，地面沉降发生在下午 6 点左右，促使当局停止为游客和卡车提供跨境服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府补充说，恢复服务的日期将在修复完成后公布。&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s newly appointed Cardinal Stephen Chow says elevation has given him ‘new mission’, calls for greater reconciliation in city]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3227172/hong-kongs-newly-appointed-cardinal-stephen-chow-says-elevation-has-given-him-new-mission-calls?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 17:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/bd447406-90ca-4b4a-9f34-c4d6cc82ea68_86609919.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港新任红衣主教周秀恩表示，升职给了他周先生仍是天主教主教，等待 9 月底教宗的任命，他表示，他对新任主教感到有责任感。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说：“感觉这是上帝通过教皇赋予我的使命。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周先生被广泛认为是政治中立的，他也强调了弥合社会分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为香港应该有更多的和解，让香港人有机会休息、和解、平静下来。这就是我希望做的事情，”他说。 “这需要多方合作才能实现。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及是否会继续呼吁对参与 2019 年反政府抗议活动的人进行宽大处理时，周表示，给予年轻人至关重要希望，特别是那些犯下罪行的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从教皇方济各周日在罗马圣彼得广场每周公开露面期间宣布他晋升为红衣主教以来，这位 63 岁的老人一直在接受媒体采访。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港周星驰主教被教宗方济各任命为枢机主教团成员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他将成为继已故的施洗约翰·吴正中（91岁）之后第四位来自香港的枢机主教-老陈日君和83岁的汤汉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教宗两年前任命周主教为天主教香港教区主教，使他成为担任该职位的最年轻的主教之一自杨名祥于 2019 年去世后，第一位华人主教于 1969 年被任命以来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周应圣主教李山主教的邀请，于 4 月对北京进行了为期五天的访问北京教区，标志着自 1997 年英国回归中国以来，香港天主教高级神职人员首次访问首都。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港陈枢机在梵蒂冈私人接见教宗方济各&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;他当时表示，这次访问突显了香港教会的使命，即充当桥梁，促进两地信徒之间的交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主教还呼吁加强联系该市教区和教会与中国大陆的对应机构之间。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong accountant swindled out of HK$1 million in digital Tether coins in bogus cryptocurrency deal]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3227158/hong-kong-accountant-swindled-out-hk1-million-digital-tether-coins-bogus-cryptocurrency-deal?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/6429cab8-ab6d-40d4-9d0a-09ad9adfe42f_3a7f5a81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港警方正在追捕一名会计师诈骗100万港元的诈骗犯&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;侦探们正在调查该诈骗集团是否在漆咸道南其士大厦的地下室设立了这家商店，以欺骗这名 29 岁的女子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;一位熟悉该案的消息人士周一表示，该会计师在 Instagram 上看到了一篇关于以更高汇率交易数字货币的帖子，并提供了联系方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港、内地警方在香港逮捕了 17 人。与149起网络诈骗案有关联&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她想出售Tether数字货币，并联系了一名冒充商店员工的诈骗犯。周日晚上，她被要求到店进行交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在店里开会时，骗子冒充店员，将一捆港币1,000元钞票放在柜台上付款。消息人士称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，该女子按照指示将 128,040 个 Tether 币转入指定电子钱包账户，换取 100 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“之后她“完成转账后，‘员工’让受害人在店外等候，因为他需要上厕所。”消息人士称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当该男子没有回来时，她意识到自己被骗了，她无法联系到他。随后，她于周日晚上 10 点左右报警。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;投资诈骗激增，香港会计师损失 2700 万港元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;另一位消息人士称，“钞票”留在柜台上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消息人士称：“除了这捆纸币顶部和底部有两张真钞外，其他都是假钞。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些钞票被称为培训钞，看起来是真的。上面印着“练习券”三个大字。它们没有水印等安全功能，据说是中国大陆银行工作人员用来进行培训和计数练习的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港退休人员在加密货币投资骗局中损失 700 万港元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >; 警方搜查了该地区，但没有逮捕任何人。警方还仔细研究了安全摄像头的录像以收集证据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方已将此案列为诈骗案。油尖刑事调查组侦探正在处理此案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年5月4日，一名加密货币交易者在尖沙咀弥敦道店内进行虚假交易，被诱骗转移150万港元的数字货币沙咀。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方打击洗黑钱集团拘捕19人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;30岁商人与两名同事在里面遇见一名冒充买家的男子进行交易&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;受害人按照指示，将150万港元的电子货币转入指定的电子钱包。 “买家”声称需要去员工室拿钱，然后退出了会议。相反，该男子从后门离开了商店。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当“买家”没有回来并且三人发现他们被锁在房间里时，受害者和她的同事意识到这是一个骗局。他们随后报了警。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港建筑师在加密货币投资骗局中骗取了2450万港元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据警方称，调查发现一家空壳公司在一个月前租下了该店铺。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年8月，一名商人在诈骗集团租用的红磡办公室进行虚假加密货币交易，转出约158万港元的数码货币，换取两捆假钞。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年一月至三月，警方共处理了 8,886 起诈骗举报，比去年同期的 5,378 起增加了 65%。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt; div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Auckland’s bold housing reforms an example for Australia’s unaffordable market]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/article/3227121/aucklands-bold-housing-reforms-example-australias-unaffordable-market?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/2b904e1d-cf59-4832-bb17-ab9b6d8e6de4_c10d2762.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;乍一看，澳大利亚房地产市场的表现明显好于新西兰。两国央行都是发达经济体中最强硬的央行之一，以引发经济衰退为代价大幅加息以抑制通胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这使得今年澳大利亚房价的突然回升一直是人们关注的焦点。更引人注目。自 2 月份触底以来，房价已上涨 3.4%，将峰谷跌幅缩小至仅 5.7%。根据 CoreLogic 的数据，在最大、最昂贵的市场悉尼，房价飙升了 6.7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，新西兰的房价尚未见底，已下跌 15%。连续几个月。上个月，它们的跌幅达到八个月来的最大幅度，使去年的跌幅达到 10.6%。根据 CoreLogic 的数据，在该国最大的城市奥克兰，房价自峰值以来已暴跌 16.8%，是悉尼从高峰到低谷的跌幅的两倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，尽管澳大利亚的房地产市场已证明价格的反弹只会加剧人们对承受能力恶化的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;短期低迷的主要原因之一是供应不足。根据 CoreLogic 的数据，上个月，首府城市的新挂牌房屋数量比前五年平均水平低 10%，而库存水平比一年中这个时候的平均水平低四分之一以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;供应租赁市场的限制尤为严重，利率急剧上升抑制了出于投资目的购买房产的需求。 4 月份，全国出租房屋数量略低于 92,000 套，低于大流行开始时的 180,000 多套，比过去十年的平均水平低 38%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚的住房危机是福也是祸。建房出租行业的诅咒&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;净海外移民激增推动的需求快速超过供应，导致租金大幅上涨，尤其是公寓租金。去年，首府城市的租金上涨了16.2%，悉尼的涨幅高达18.8%。租金价格上涨的压力主要是由于中高密度住房供应持续不足，这是保障性住房存量下降的关键因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不幸的是，租金负担能力恶化，特别是对于低收入家庭来说，已经变得深度政治化。上个月，反对党推迟了对执政党工党签署的100亿澳元（合67亿美元）社会和经济适用住房基金的立法批准，主要是因为绿党坚持在全国范围内实施为期两年的租金冻结。&lt;/租金管制只会抑制投资，从而进一步减少出租房屋的供应，从而使情况变得更糟。然而，澳大利亚住房政策上的政治分歧加剧了人们对规划体系的拖延和低效的关注，这是该国住房危机的根源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此背景下，澳大利亚政府推出了大胆的分区改革。奥克兰政府旨在鼓励发展中密度住房的举措引人注目。 2016 年，一套统一的土地使用规则，即奥克兰统一规划 (AUP)，导致该市大部分住宅用地进行了升级分区，引发了住宅建设热潮，使该市免受租金和价格大幅上涨的影响。新西兰其他地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥克兰大学的 Ryan Greenaway-McGrevy 进行的研究表明，城市分区法的自由化不仅导致了升级分区地区的建筑激增，还转移了在公共基础设施良好的成熟郊区建造附属多户住宅（而不是单户独立住宅）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Greenaway-McGrevy 5 月份发表的一篇论文的调查结果还表明，改革改善了租金负担能力，目前两居室和三居室住宅的租金比规划系统没有变化的情况下低 14% 至 35%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AUP 帮助为新西兰的跨党派就住房改革达成共识。 2021年10月，工党政府和反对党国家党联手通过了改革规划法的立法，以鼓励在所有主要城市建造中等密度住房。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管新西兰的租赁市场仍然紧张，但租金正在上涨每年增长约 4%，比澳大利亚慢得多。新西兰CoreLogic研究主管尼克·古道尔(Nick Goodall)表示，租金收益更符合“家庭收入而不是房东的成本”。古道尔表示，尽管在增加供应方面取得了进展，特别是在奥克兰，但“很难消除多年供应不足造成的损害”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新西兰房价失控是新西兰人造成的，而不是来自中国或新加坡的外国买家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这更是澳大利亚尽快接受奥克兰式规划改革的理由。墨尔本格拉坦研究所指出，澳大利亚是发达经济体中少数几个人均住房存量在过去二十年停滞不前的国家之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在向议会上院提交的一份报告中格拉坦研究所本月在维多利亚州讨论解决住房危机的方法时敦促维多利亚政府放宽规划法，允许在现有郊区建造更多中密度住房。格拉坦研究所高级研究员 Joey Moloney 表示：“澳大利亚没有哪个州政府像奥克兰这样大胆。”这需要城市规划和发展的重大转变，最重要的是，需要政治意愿与邻避人群较量，他们迄今为止成功地阻碍了热门郊区的中高密度住房计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使在新西兰，跨党派对住房的共识也正在崩溃。十月举行议会选举。这使得奥克兰的规划改革显得更加大胆。澳大利亚城市最好效仿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blackpink, Barbie and Beijing’s South China Sea claims collide in Vietnam]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227132/blackpink-barbie-and-beijings-south-china-sea-claims-collide-vietnam?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/fabb2783-21c6-4d46-b835-ed859c0343ea_d1413260.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;首先是华纳兄弟的芭比电影中的潦草地图，现在 Blackpink 是面对越南民族主义者的愤怒，他们呼吁抵制韩国流行音乐超级组合即将在河内举行的巡演，因为流行文化越来越多地受到地缘政治的附带损害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目光敏锐的社交媒体用户上周注意到，组织 Blackpink 将于 7 月 29 日至 30 日在越南举行演唱会的中国公司 iMe Entertainment 的网站上展示了一张地图，显示了北京在南海争议性的“九段线”主张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这条线，描述中国对大部分有争议水道的领土主张，已成为引起其他国家（尤其是越南和菲律宾）愤怒的避雷针，这些国家对此存在激烈争议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题经常激起愤怒，尤其是越南人的愤怒。民族主义者——正如 Blackpink 音乐会组织者所经历的惨痛教训一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“滚出我们的国家……我们不需要一场不尊重海洋主权的演出和岛屿。请离开越南，”一位用户在 Blackpink 官方 Facebook 宣布访问河内的消息中评论道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“停止传播非法地图，”另一位用户说道，而第三位用户则评论道：“我也听说[组织]公司是中国公司，并且支持越南敌人……我本想省钱去听音乐会，但现在我不再去了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016 年联合国支持的仲裁海牙仲裁庭驳回了北京的九段线主张，称其没有法律依据。中国拒绝了这一裁决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;河内与北京在这一领域有着长期的争议历史，主要集中在南沙群岛（即越南的长沙群岛）以及西沙群岛（即黄沙群岛）。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Blackpink 的越南演唱会在南中国海地图的热水中举行&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;1988 年，双方在南沙群岛的部分地区发生了一场短暂的海上冲突，越南损失了 64 名士兵，并控制了多个岛礁和岛屿。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自那以后的几年里，越南政府已成为中国在南海活动最尖锐的批评者之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南外交部发言人范秋恒 (Pham Thu Hang) ，称发起人 iMe 网站上的地图“不可接受”和“热点问题”。她说：“在越南推广和使用以九段线为主题的产品或出版物是违法的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自问题出现以来，iMe 网站已关闭进行维护。周四，即门票发售前一天，iME 首席执行官 Brian Chow 为“不幸的误解”道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“网站上的地图图像并不代表领土他在一份声明中表示，“我们知道尊重任何国家的主权和文化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“iME 迅速审查并承诺更换不符合 iME 要求的图像。”适合越南人。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种强烈抗议使越南政府陷入困境，因为越南政府坚持对西沙群岛和南沙群岛的主权，但与中国有着密切的经济和政治联系.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 iMe 争议开始之前，旅游官员就大肆宣扬 Blackpink 演唱会的潜在积极影响，尤其是对于一个很少接待主要国际音乐明星的国家来说，而评论中则写着“欢迎来到越南”，其中有几位政府官方账户在韩国流行音乐组合的 Facebook 页面上留下了庆祝表情符号。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国和越南承诺在南海“行为准则”上开展合作&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;7 月之前然而，越南文化部于 1 月 5 日下令检查 iMe 网站，以核实九段线的存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但目前尚未有抵制的迹象。音乐会门票于周五如期发售，几分钟内就有超过 122,000 人加入数字队列。到周日中午，很多票种已经售空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;芭比电影就没那么幸运了。越南国家电影鉴定与分级委员会于 7 月 3 日禁止该片上映，理由是“其中有描绘中国九段线的场景”。这部众星云集的大片原定于 7 月 21 日上映，但连锁影院很快将其从“即将上映”页面上删除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这部电影在菲律宾也受到了批评，一位参议员呼吁免责声明称九段线是“虚构”，应在放映前加入。马尼拉电影电视审查和分级委员会目前正在调查此事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然河内因对芭比之类的电影反应如此强烈而受到广泛嘲笑，但东南亚国家研究院越南政治研究员 Nguyen Khac Giang – 新加坡尤索夫伊萨研究所表示，随着越南与中国的地缘政治叙事作斗争，这种反应是可以理解的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“接触这条线可能不会让人们支持中国有争议的主张，但会让他们意识到这一点，”他”说。“这不是好莱坞电影中第一次发生这样的事情，”阮说，并补充说，“它的存在不仅令人烦恼，而且河内认为它是中国精心策划的计划，旨在建立一种叙事并创造一种合法性认知”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该禁令在越南受到热烈欢迎，人们指责芭比娃娃背后的主要工作室华纳兄弟“迎合” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该工作室发表了一份声明，称“芭比乐园的地图是一幅异想天开、充满童趣的蜡笔画。这些涂鸦描绘了芭比从芭比乐园到现实世界的虚构旅程。它无意发表任何类型的声明。”越南回应称将维持这一禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有 89,000 名粉丝的芭比越南官方 Facebook 页面发帖称：“我们爱芭比，但我们首先爱我们的国家。我们不支持任何侵犯我们领土主权的行为。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南政府在打击被认为冒犯国家情感的流行文化方面有着悠久的历史。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它禁止了这部动画电影和汤姆猫去年 3 月，荷兰主导的《神秘海域》包含了对九段线的描绘——2018 年的《摘金奇缘》中的场景中也删去了类似的图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;越南禁止芭比娃娃电影展示北京对南海的主张&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但社交媒体用户对芭比娃娃和 Blackpink 的反应相对较新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为越南公众情绪多年来没有发生显着变化，但已经发生了变化。社交媒体的兴起和中国在南海日益咄咄逼人的活动进一步强化了这一点。”江说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他最终相信越南和菲律宾做出了正确的决定，反对有关这些言论的描述。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从河内和马尼拉的角度来看，不存在任何争议——你不能简单地在广阔的海域上任意划线并声称它是你的，”他说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南当局周一要求 Netflix 24 小时内将中国电视节目《飞往你的航班》从其越南平台上删除，这表明这场战斗还远未结束，因为该节目在多个节目中展示了九段线。多集中的场景。 In June 2021, the streaming service pulled the Australian show from its Vietnam offerings for similar reasons.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s ‘anxiety’ seen driving efforts to improve ties with South Korea, Japan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227159/chinas-anxiety-seen-driving-efforts-improve-ties-south-korea-japan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/6a4767c1-293a-4dcb-b8f4-b1ede67ca59a_2921b56f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China is expected to focus on economic cooperation to improve strained ties with South Korea and Japan, but it is unlikely to stop its two neighbours from tilting further towards the United States, observers say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The assessment came after China&#39;s top diplomat, Wang Yi, last week stressed the need for Seoul and Tokyo to “regroup and restart” cooperation with Beijing and urged them not to be swayed by “a certain major power outside the region”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Asia is our common home, and the three countries are close neighbours that cannot be moved away,” Wang told a trilateral forum in Qingdao. “China, Japan and South Korea should maintain strategic focus, grasp the trend of the times, draw on historical wisdom, and firmly maintain the correct direction of trilateral cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The key is our emphasis on peaceful development … and understanding the different paths chosen by each other.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang&#39;s attendance at the forum was unusual – Beijing usually sends its foreign minister or ambassador to the event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That reflects Beijing&#39;s concern over China&#39;s worsening economic situation and pressure from the US, according to Choo Jae-woo, a professor of Chinese studies at Kyung Hee University in Seoul.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[This] does not fit his level,” Choo said. “It clearly shows China&#39;s anxiety and impatience [with the situation].”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the first time a member of China&#39;s powerful Politburo has attended since the first forum in 2011.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang also focused on trilateral ties when he met former Japanese foreign minister Yohei Kono in Beijing on Thursday, emphasising the need to “eliminate external interference” and to jointly maintain peace and stability in Asia, according to a Chinese foreign ministry statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday in Beijing, Chinese foreign vice-minister Sun Weidong met his South Korean counterpart Choi Young-sam, with the two sides agreeing to strengthen bilateral ties based on “mutual respect and reciprocity”, according to the South Korean foreign ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s push to improve trilateral cooperation with South Korea and Japan comes as they move closer to Washington as it seeks stronger security and economic ties to counter Beijing&#39;s influence in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, China&#39;s ambassador to South Korea Xing Haiming was summoned by Seoul after he warned in a speech that those who bet against China losing out to the US “will certainly regret it later”. Beijing responded with a diplomatic dressing down of South Korea&#39;s envoy in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China also criticised South Korean President Yoon Suk-yeol in April after he said rising tensions between Taipei and Beijing were caused by “attempts to change the status quo by force”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan&#39;s plan to discharge radioactive water from the Fukushima nuclear power plant into the Pacific Ocean has also caused friction, with China and South Korea. While Seoul on Friday said the plan met global standards, Beijing remains doubtful over its safety.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Japan has not fully consulted with the international community, especially stakeholders,” Chinese foreign ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin said on Thursday, adding that this reflected “the selfishness and arrogance of the Japanese side”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China once again urges Japan to take a responsible attitude towards the marine environment and human life and health, stop forcing the plan to discharge nuclear-contaminated water into the sea, and refrain from imposing unpredictable risks on the international community.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relations have also been strained over the case of a Japanese businessman detained in Beijing in March over his alleged involvement in espionage activities in China. Tokyo has called for the man&#39;s release.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Observers say Washington&#39;s growing influence on its Asian allies is driving Beijing&#39;s efforts to ease tensions with Seoul and Tokyo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shi Yinhong, an international relations professor at Renmin University in Beijing, said China wanted to boost ties with its two neighbours to prevent them from moving closer to the US, but that was unlikely to happen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China has always appealed for cooperation among these countries, but if you consider the increasing confrontation between China, Japan and South Korea, I don&#39;t believe that this kind of appeal at this time will have any lasting positive result,” Shi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you look at the current situation between China and Japan and between China and South Korea, you will immediately realise that it&#39;s not possible to achieve any substantial and lasting progress.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Could China&#39;s hardball tactics drive Seoul further towards Washington?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Still, Beijing is expected to push economic cooperation at a trilateral summit which South Korea has proposed could be held this year in Seoul. It was last held in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“South Korea and Japan are willing to improve ties because of their economic dependence on China,” Choo said, adding that areas including free-trade agreements were likely to be on the agenda at the summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he noted it was still uncertain whether the event would go ahead, and that fraught ties with its neighbours were hampering Beijing&#39;s efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Trilateral cooperation in the future will be challenging. The South Korean government is seeking a breakthrough but it&#39;s still struggling,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s changing economic relationships with South Korea and Japan could also be a challenge for Beijing. While they used to occupy different parts of the value chain, they are starting to overlap and China is becoming a competitor in areas such as cars and shipbuilding.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shi said there was also a stalemate because of Beijing&#39;s stance on South Korean and Japanese foreign policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China doesn&#39;t want this kind of situation, but at the same time it does not want to make any concessions,” Shi said. “The situation will continue on this course, and the objective of sustainable and lasting cooperation will move further away.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia’s top general Gerasimov shown in video, first time since Wagner mutiny]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3227154/russias-top-general-gerasimov-shown-video-first-time-wagner-mutiny?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 15:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/3c7a44b7-3e08-4f51-aa3f-64667ff10232_385480c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯最高将领、总参谋长瓦列里·格拉西莫夫正在命令下属在周一发布的一段视频中，他要摧毁乌克兰的导弹基地，这是自 6 月 24 日雇佣兵叛变失败以来，他首次公开露面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坐在军事指挥室的白色皮革座椅上，主持与高级将领的会议视频通话中，67 岁的格拉西莫夫正在下达命令，其中包括向俄罗斯强大的军事情报部门 (GRU) 下达命令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格拉西莫夫被告知乌克兰导弹袭击了莫斯科从乌克兰吞并的克里米亚2014 年，罗斯托夫和卡卢加地区的会议于周日受阻，并讨论俄罗斯应如何应对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防部表示，录像显示格拉西莫夫周日在开会。视频将他描述为俄罗斯武装部队总参谋长和莫斯科驻乌克兰部队指挥官，这是他在兵变之前担任的职位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频显示，弗拉基米尔·普京总统保留了他的两支最强大的军队国防部长谢尔盖·绍伊古和格拉西莫夫仍然坚守岗位，尽管雇佣军领导人叶夫根尼·普里戈任要求解雇他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任 6 月 24 日的兵变旨在与绍伊古和格拉西莫夫算账，他称他们是无能的叛徒他将克里姆林宫领导人拉入了一场失败的战争，这场战争暴露了俄罗斯军队的腐败和腐败。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我很害怕”：白俄罗斯当地人担心瓦格纳战士可能到来&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;在视频中，格拉西莫夫询问并听取了航空航天部队谢尔盖·苏罗维金将军的副手维克托·阿夫扎洛夫的报告，自叛变以来，维克多·阿夫扎洛夫一直没有公开露面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚苏罗维金在叛乱前担任俄罗斯驻乌克兰军队副司令，多次受到普里戈任的赞扬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯媒体因其冷酷无情而被昵称为“世界末日将军”。苏罗维金正式成为航空航天部队总司令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们注意到，航空航天部队已经完成了这项任务，”格拉西莫夫说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他询问了航空航天部队部队和格鲁乌军事情报部门确定“导弹和其他敌方打击武器的储存地点和发射位置，以计划先发制人的打击”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防部发布的视频显示了视频的参与者通话内容模糊不清，但明确显示了苏罗维金的副手阿夫扎洛夫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦格纳的全副武装部队控制了俄罗斯南部城市顿河畔罗斯托夫，然后迅速移动到距离莫斯科 200 公里（124 英里）以内的地方，一路上几乎没有遇到军队的抵抗。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯电视节目显示普里戈任的“宫殿”正在采取行动抹黑他&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据白俄罗斯总统亚历山大·卢卡申科斡旋的协议，普里戈任取消了兵变.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自叛乱结束以来，普里戈任也没有公开露面。卢卡申科上周表示，这位瓦格纳领导人在访问他的国家后已返回俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任能够轻松进出俄罗斯，这引发了人们对与普京的协议条款的质疑。 ，他公开同意允许瓦格纳创始人与任何想加入他的战士一起前往白俄罗斯，并撤销针对他们武装叛变的刑事案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭博社的补充报道&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[After Yellen’s China trip saw these demands made and missteps avoided, Beijing calls to ‘beef up’ US cooperation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3227139/after-yellens-china-trip-saw-these-demands-made-and-missteps-avoided-beijing-calls-beef-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/27039598-ecd7-40b4-810d-7518bcde0fe7_19022d81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京敦促华盛顿取消对中国企业的经济制裁，并呼吁共同努力解决与美国财长耶伦会谈时讨论全球挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国的发展对美国来说是机遇而不是挑战。这意味着好处，而不是风险。”财政部周一在一份声明中表示，在为期四天的访问期间，中国财政部在与耶伦的会谈中总结了中国的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是第二次高层访问乔·拜登的内阁官员在不到一个月的时间里对中国进行了访问，世界上最大的两个经济体正在努力避免失误，试图防止受损的关系进一步恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在会谈中，中国重申了要求美国取消关税、停止遏制中国企业、确保双边投资公平待遇、放松出口管制、取消对涉疆产品的禁令。” “中方希望美方针对双边经济关系中的重大关切采取切实措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“加强双边合作是务实、正确的选择。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;随着美中关系跌至新低，外交秘密渠道仍然有效吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;耶伦周日在北京出发前表示，她访问期间与中国新任经济官员进行的 10 小时双边会谈有所帮助为稳定紧张关系奠定更坚实的基础，她预计未来会有更多接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管她做出乐观的评估，但分歧仍然存在，美国将继续对中国获取先进技术施加国家安全限制&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国已将 1,000 多家中国企业列入制裁名单或出口管制，并正在考虑对美国在华投资实施新的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京方面多次猛烈抨击近年来，由于技术限制、国家安全、人权和台湾等一系列热点问题，华盛顿涉嫌滥用国家安全和广泛的双边关系，跌至新低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她重申，美国并不寻求与中国脱钩，因为这样做对两国来说都是灾难性的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财政部声明补充说，美国表示“无意强迫各国选边站队” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“两国需要坦诚交流，就双边经济的重要问题达成共识，为经济关系注入稳定性和积极性。”声明补充道&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;并呼吁协调应对经济、气候变化、债务减免等全球性挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“面对严峻的全球性挑战，中国希望包括美国在内的发达国家采取行动”它补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“差异不应导致隔阂，而应成为密切交流和沟通的动力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia to host German troops for first time ever as Berlin’s focus shifts East amid rising China tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3227147/australia-host-german-troops-first-time-ever-berlins-focus-shifts-east-amid-rising-china-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 15:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/3644fae9-f521-4a7d-b40b-35096c5c1951_b5fed183.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;德国将首次向澳大利亚派遣军队作为联合演习的一部分与来自其他 12 个国家的约 30,000 名军人一起，突显柏林在亚太地区与中国的紧张关系日益加剧的情况下日益关注该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，德国在亚洲的军事存在不断增强。太平洋，即使这意味着在其安全和经济利益之间走钢丝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于经济上的相互依存性，对于我们德国以及欧盟来说，这是一个极其重要的地区”，陆军参谋长阿方斯·迈斯 (Alfons Mais) 在周一发表的采访中表示，就在第一批德国军队出发前往澳大利亚前几个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是柏林最重要的贸易伙伴，欧洲 40% 的对外贸易流经中国南海，是亚太地区领土争端焦点的航道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年，一艘德国军舰近20年来首次驶入南海。去年，柏林派出 13 架军机前往澳大利亚参加联合演习，这是空军和平时期最大规模的部署。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迈斯表示，多达 240 名德国士兵将参加“护身符”演习，其中包括 170 名伞兵和 40 名海军陆战队员7月22日至8月4日举行的军刀演习是澳大利亚和美国之间最大规模的演习，每两年举行一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“德国中国城”的失败如何反映了欧盟对北京看法的转变&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德国人将与来自美国、印度尼西亚、日本、韩国、法国和英国等国家的士兵一起进行丛林战和登陆作战训练。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的目标是证明我们是可靠且有能力的合作伙伴，为稳定该地区基于规则的秩序做出贡献”，迈斯说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及德国首次向澳大利亚部署军队旨在向中国传达什么信息时，他强调柏林无意对抗&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位中将表示，“了解其他人对世界的看法通常是有意义的”，并补充说，当前的安全挑战比 1990 年之前要不那么明确。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“冷战很容易，这是一个两极世界。今天，我们不能再只关注欧洲……我们必须把自己定位得更广泛。”陆军参谋长强调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迈斯计划参观澳大利亚的德国军队和莱茵金属公司组装拳击手装甲运输车的工厂7 月中旬为两国军队提供车辆，然后前往日本和新加坡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“日本是一个拥有深化双边军事合作潜力的合作伙伴，”他说。 As for Talisman Sabre, the German troops already have orders to return to Australia for the next exercise in 2025.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong legislature to launch search for new secretary general to replace veteran Kenneth Chen who retires in 2024]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3227141/hong-kong-legislature-launch-search-new-secretary-general-replace-veteran-kenneth-chen-who-retires?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/5f5d84f8-e441-4452-99e8-b593117d4c16_d74aa589.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港特区政府秘书处将展开招聘工作，物色新任主管立法会主席陈伟安将于明年退休。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会主席梁君彦周一承认陈伟安在过去11年里领导600名秘书处人员的努力，特别是克服“他指的是上一届立法会任期，该任期充满了一些争议，包括 2016 年六名议员因宣誓时的滑稽行为而被取消资格，以及猛烈攻击。 2019 年反政府抗议期间，立法会大楼的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“陈带领他的团队克服了无数挑战，”梁说。 “他还在任期内推动了立法机关的现代化，并采用了各种数字服务来提高其效率和透明度。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港改革区议会法案获得支持，削减直选席位&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;梁振英表示，58岁的陈将于明年8月退休，并补充说立法机关将聘请一家顾问公司牵头招聘工作，从内部和外部物色新秘书长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他强调陈的继任者必须熟悉行政和立法部门的工作，具有出色的领导能力，并具有丰富的公共行政经验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈表示很荣幸能够为立法机关服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“过去11年，我们遇到了很多前所未有的挑战。 I am grateful the whole secretariat could overcome them one after another in unity,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong district council reforms spark soul-searching on future of direct elections&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chen said in the coming year he would continue with his work including advocating for the legislature to adopt more technology and overseeing the Legco complex&#39;s expansion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen, a former deputy education minister, succeeded Pauline Ng Man-wah as secretary general in 2012. The secretariat provides administrative support and services to Legco.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Uzbekistan president cements power with election win]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3227143/uzbekistan-president-cements-power-election-win?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 15:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/43af3006-84cf-4ec9-ac65-3c689e2f24f6_eff8ad7b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Uzbek President Shavkat Mirziyoyev has won a third term that will keep him in charge of the tightly controlled, gas-rich Central Asian state until 2030, according to preliminary results Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 65-year-old has promised to open up Uzbekistan to foreign investment and tourism and implement key domestic reforms in Central Asia&#39;s most populous country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mirziyoyev, who was running against three largely unknown candidates, won Sunday&#39;s election with 87 per cent of the vote, the preliminary results showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He previously served as prime minister under his hardline predecessor Islam Karimov before winning his first term in 2016 and getting re-elected in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A constitutional referendum this year paved the way for him to serve two more presidential terms and increased the mandate from five years to seven, meaning he could stay in power until 2037.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A former Soviet republic, Uzbekistan has a strategic location neighbouring Afghanistan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mirziyoyev, who trained as an engineer, portrays himself as a reformer creating a “New Uzbekistan” and has said he wants to double gross domestic product to US$160 billion soon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He focused his re-election campaign on the economy and education.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has ended the practice of forced labour in Uzbekistan&#39;s cotton fields and released political prisoners jailed during Karimov&#39;s quarter-century rule.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;NGOs say human rights are better than under Karimov but there is still much to improve, and the authorities have shown no sign of allowing a real opposition to emerge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe (OSCE) said the campaign has been “low-key, mirroring lack of opposition to the incumbent”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July 2022, protests erupted over a plan to remove the right to self-determination from the region of Karakalpakstan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unrest and subsequent crackdown in the poor northwestern territory left at least 21 people dead.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[40,000 Hongkongers attended free Harbour Chill Carnival featuring Cantopop singer Kelly Chen, girl group Otome Syndream]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3227145/40000-hongkongers-attended-free-harbour-chill-carnival-featuring-cantopop-singer-kelly-chen-girl?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 15:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/79c5f485-b4ad-4977-86a8-91073ad86737_25cefd67.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;四万人参加了周末举行的 Harbour Chill 嘉年华，其中包括免费音乐会、香港香港旅游发展局周一透露，这标志着政府组织的一项耗资 4,000 万港元（510 万美元）的计划的启动，该计划旨在提振城市精神。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该活动于 2017 年在湾仔海滨举行。周六和周日，第一天出现了一些小问题，观众抱怨只有前排观众才能清楚地看到表演者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些歌迷称，音乐会的海上舞台是一艘驳船，低于视平线，迫使他们爬上障碍物，以便更好地观看粤语流行歌手陈慧琳的首场演出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;音乐会的第二天晚上，香港日本歌手乙女梦梦 (Otome Syndream) 登场。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;狂欢节的前两天是为期五个周末的节目的一部分，吸引了约 40,000 人，其中 4,000 人是音乐会观众。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈柏宇和陈柏宇在音乐会的第一晚表演，而周日的活动则邀请了中国乐队桃园VX点，这是他们首次来到这座城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;《邮报》周日探访湾仔海滨，数百名音乐会观众在观众区等候。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主办方允许已登记门票的居民比演出时间提前约一小时入场。演出开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港维港音乐会引起轰动，但有人说浮动舞台太远&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;汤米·谭永德，26岁工程师，也是音乐迷女团的他说，他花了10分钟才拿到两张票，从远处看演出没有问题，但觉得走到舞台上很乏味。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不知道为什么主办单位安排观众从湾仔码头入场，但舞台却位于红磡海底隧道入口附近。顶着烈日，我们花了15分钟才走到观众区。”谭说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但我很高兴，因为我可以免费和朋友们一起欣赏偶像的音乐。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;46岁的家庭主妇张怡婷也出席了首晚的演唱会，她表示，在看到成龙的表演后，她很高兴能欣赏本地创作歌手冯运谦的表演。星期六。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我昨晚在这里。我的朋友今晚很友善地给了我一张票。今天比较开心，人少了，也没有人发疯、爬栏去看偶像。”张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然我希望舞台能近一点，可以看到偶像。”他们英俊的脸庞。但音乐会是免费的。即使你付了钱在红馆听一场音乐会，也不能保证你能近距离接触表演者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冯和台湾乐队宇宙人参加了活动的后半场。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;25 岁的美容顾问黄月仪 (Aimee Wong Yuet-yee) 与 28 岁的男友刘宗盛 (Jonathan Lau) 一起出席，她表示这场演唱会是一次浪漫的“款待”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我爱冯的音乐。这就是为什么我想注册门票。舞台有点远，但我仍然可以看到他并靠在我男朋友身上欣赏他的音乐。这次活动免费、独特且浪漫。”黄说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港人受邀与 Tyson Yoshi 一起参加耗资 4,000 万港元的海港嘉年华&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;首两个演唱会周末的 14,000 张免费门票上周二，半小时内就被抢购一空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，居民们还聚集在播放海滨表演的大屏幕前，享用着为嘉年华设立的六个小吃摊提供的小吃和饮料。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;38 岁的营销专家杨美凤 (Tanya Yeung Mei-fung) 与丈夫和两个儿子一起来到现场，她坐在屏幕旁边的草地上。她表示，食物的选择非常有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次活动是‘欢乐香港’活动的一部分，但食物的选择非常有限。政府本可以从西九龙艺术公园带来这些餐车来同时宣传这两件事。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有街头表演，包括杂技、舞蹈、X游戏、滑板码头旁还有中国滑板运动员陈野和香港小轮车运动员李森森在码头旁的功夫表演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次嘉年华是旅游局主办的“快乐香港”旅游活动的一部分，未来四个周末将在湾仔海滨继续进行，歌手作曲家黄婉芝和流行说唱宠儿 Tyson Yoshi 预计将表演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;董事会执行董事郑定逸 (Dane Cheng Ting-yat) ，感谢居民和游客的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次活动是一个新的实验。 We will collect feedback and adjust it accordingly, striving to provide a better experience,” Cheng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The one-day outdoor Pop Culture Festival, a similar event in April featuring Danny Summer, Elisa Chan Kit-ling and Judas Law Hoi-ling and also part of the tourism campaign, attracted more than 20,000 audience members and onlookers.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How many Russians have died in Ukraine? Data sheds light on closely held secret]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227140/how-many-russians-have-died-ukraine-data-sheds-light-closely-held-secret?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/f8a142a3-bf65-4b8a-967e-d1eeed9a6468_24cb0c98.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;根据第一家独立媒体报道，近 50,000 名俄罗斯男子在乌克兰战争中丧生对俄罗斯战争死难者的统计分析。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两家独立的俄罗斯媒体 Mediazona 和 Meduza 与德国图宾根大学的数据科学家合作，利用俄罗斯政府数据揭示了莫斯科最保守的秘密之一 -入侵乌克兰造成的真正人员伤亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为此，他们依赖于 Covid-19 大流行期间流行的统计概念，即超额死亡率。他们根据继承记录和官方死亡率数据，估计 2022 年 2 月至 2023 年 5 月期间 50 岁以下男性死亡人数比正常情况下多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科和基辅都没有及时提供有关军事损失的数据，而且各自都在煞费苦心地扩大对方的伤亡。俄罗斯已公开承认有超过 6,000 名士兵死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;活动人士和独立记者称，俄罗斯媒体压制了有关军事损失的报道。记录死者已成为一种反抗行为，这样做的人会面临骚扰和潜在的刑事指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管面临这些挑战，Mediazona 和 BBC 俄语组与志愿者网络合作，利用社交媒体俄罗斯各地墓地的媒体帖子和照片，以建立已确认的战争死亡人数数据库。截至 7 月 7 日，他们已经确认了 27,423 名死去的俄罗斯士兵的身份。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰发誓不会在俄罗斯使用集束弹药&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这些只是我们知道名字的士兵，他们的每个案件的死亡人数均经过多个来源核实，”帮助监督调查的 Mediazona 编辑德米特里·特雷什查宁 (Dmitry Treshchanin) 说。 “我们对 Meduza 所做的估计使我们能够看到‘隐藏’的死亡人数，俄罗斯政府如此痴迷地试图隐藏死亡人数，但没有成功。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了得出更全面的统计，来自 Mediazona 的记者Meduza 获得了向俄罗斯当局提交的继承案件记录。他们来自国家遗嘱认证登记处的数据包含 2014 年至 2023 年 5 月期间超过 1100 万人死亡的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据他们的分析，2022 年针对 15 岁至 49 岁男性的遗产案件比男性多了 25,000 起继承案件。预期的。截至 2023 年 5 月 27 日，超额病例数已飙升至 47,000 例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一激增与白宫 5 月份的评估大致一致，即自 12 月以来已有超过 20,000 名俄罗斯人在乌克兰被杀，尽管低于美国和英国情报部门对俄罗斯总体死亡人数的评估。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2月份，英国国防部表示，大约有 40,000 至 60,000 名俄罗斯人可能在战争中丧生。美国国防情报局泄露的评估显示，战争第一年，俄罗斯阵亡人数为 35,000 至 43,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们的数字可能准确，也可能不准确。” Mediazona 编辑 Treshchanin 在一封电子邮件中说道。 “即使他们有俄罗斯国防部的消息来源，其自己的数据也可能不完整。要将军队、罗斯瓦迪亚、艾哈迈特营、各个私营军事连队的所有伤亡统计到一起是极其困难的，其中瓦格纳是最大的，但不是唯一的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“囚犯伤亡，首先由瓦格纳招募，现在由国防部招募，也是一个非常模糊的主题，具有很大的操纵潜力。统计实际上可以给出更好的结果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国蒂宾根大学的数据科学家 Dmitry Kobak 发表了有关俄罗斯 Covid-19 死亡人数过多的研究报告，他独立地获得了按年龄和性别细分的死亡率数据来自俄罗斯官方统计机构 Rosstat 的 2022 年数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他发现 2022 年 50 岁以下男性死亡人数比预期多 24,000 人，这一数字与遗传数据分析相符。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;白俄罗斯领导人透露了瓦格纳领导人普里戈任的下落&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Covid-19 大流行使我们更难弄清楚，如果没有战争，自 2022 年 2 月以来俄罗斯将有多少人死亡。这两项分析都通过将男性死亡率与女性死亡率进行指数化，纠正了新冠病毒对死亡率的持续影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥地利国际应用系统分析研究所的学者谢尔盖·谢尔博夫（Sergei Scherbov）警告说，“数字上的差异仅由于随机性，男性和女性之间的死亡人数就会有很大差异”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我并不是说男性死亡人数不会过多，而是说从统计角度来看，死亡人数的这种差异可能只是偶然的结果，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;失踪但未被正式确认死亡的俄罗斯人，以及在自封的顿涅茨克和卢甘斯克共和国部队中作战的乌克兰公民，不包括在这些计数中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科巴克承认仍然存在一些不确定性，特别是对于老年男性的死亡而言。此外，很难知道有多少失踪的俄罗斯士兵实际上已经死亡。但他表示，这两个因素都不可能产生巨大影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种不确定性有成千上万，”他说。 “结果总体上是合理的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meduza 是一家独立的俄罗斯媒体机构，已流亡运营八年，总部位于拉脱维亚里加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 4 月，俄罗斯当局将 Meduza 指定为“外国代理人”，使其更难获得广告收入。2023 年 1 月，克里姆林宫将 Meduza 列为非法“不良组织”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科还将独立媒体 Mediazona 列为俄罗斯全面入侵乌克兰后，其网站被“外国特工”封锁。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 14:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Tampering with someone’s life’: anger in China over ‘too light’ penalty for teen who sabotaged online university application of rival]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226761/tampering-someones-life-anger-china-over-too-light-penalty-teen-who-sabotaged-online-university?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/a40657a8-9ed6-4124-a8b4-c8516f1e0696_4918571d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一名青少年承认篡改大学申请后被拘留五天&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名向姓少年和被黑客攻击的王姓学生是中国中部湖北省的同一个班级。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两人都参加了今年的全国大学入学考试，在中国称为高考。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方收到王女士的投诉，称她的在线大学申请在7月2日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，她登录官方申请系统仔细检查了自己的详细信息，发现她选择申请的大学已被删除，并被“垃圾学校”字样取代。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;警方追踪到使用王某账户的IP地址，找到了王某的同学向某，后者访问并更改了她的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在警方劝说下，向某第二天承认了这一点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他承认自己偷拍了王某的考生号，然后多次尝试猜测她的密码，才成功登录她的账户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国新闻网站观察者网报道称，向某阻挠王某申请的动机是两人不合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后，当地高等教育招生办公室允许王某更正她的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;向某被处以行政拘留五天的处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的高考每年约有 1000 万中学毕业生参加，由于学生之间相互竞争以获得中国高等教育的高等教育学位，因此竞争非常激烈&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大学申请期在高考成绩公布之后，学生及其家长几乎和考试本身一样重视，他们力求选择与自己分数相匹配的最佳学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;一旦选择，截止日期后不得更改，除非重新参加考试，否则没有第二次选择其他大学的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大陆社交媒体观察家已被被形容为“太轻”的处罚激怒了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“篡改他人生活只判五天？” ”有人问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这和杀人没有什么区别。 It could change that person&#39;s life,” said another.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is true that people make mistakes, but some mistakes can never be forgiven,” said a third person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under China&#39;s Law on Penalties for Administration of Public Security, a person who hacks a computer system could receive up to 10 days in detention.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Daode, a professor of criminal procedure law at the China University of Political Science and Law, told Hubei Television that the case could prompt a review of the application system and how vulnerable it is to hacking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some online observers also suggested the application system use more complicated authentication methods, such as SMS verification and a security lockout, to prevent future hacks.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 14:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Global Impact: Japan, nuclear watchdog under intense scrutiny over discharge of Fukushima nuclear-contaminated water]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3227113/global-impact-japan-nuclear-watchdog-under-intense-scrutiny-over-discharge-fukushima-nuclear?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/42497c22-137e-4ed6-8958-f60096f6738d_40449811.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;《全球影响》是一份每周精选的时事通讯，其中包含源自中国的新闻主题，具有重大意义对世界各地新闻播音员的宏观影响。 Sign up &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This week, the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) said that Japan&#39;s plan to release radioactive water from the Fukushima nuclear disaster in 2011 into the ocean meets international safety standards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But instead of allaying concerns of neighbouring countries and activists, the stamp of approval from the global nuclear watchdog has drawn howls of disapproval, particularly from China, and even within Japan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;IAEA director general Rafael Mariano Grossi said at a news conference in Tokyo that his agency&#39;s “comprehensive, neutral, objective and scientifically sound” evaluation showed that Japan&#39;s planned discharge was consistent with safety standards and global industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The China Atomic Energy Authority said that more than 70 per cent of nuclear-contaminated water at the Fukushima nuclear power plant fails to meet discharge limits after going through a filtration system and requires further treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its secretary general, Deng Ge, said that even if international standards are met, the IAEA cannot prove that the discharge is the only or the best option for the disposal of nuclear-contaminated water.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s foreign ministry weighed in by stating that the nuclear watchdog&#39;s report “failed to fully reflect views from experts that participated in the review”, and that its conclusion “was not shared by all experts”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And on Friday, China&#39;s customs extended a ban on food imports from 10 Japanese prefectures, while food from other parts of Japan will face strict 100 per cent screening, including edible aquatic products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Farther south, Hong Kong&#39;s Environment and Ecology Bureau said more risk assessments would be undertaken, while import controls on marine produce might be introduced, including tougher labelling requirements for Japanese food.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not letting their own government off the hook, Japanese activists said they are very disappointed by the IAEA decision, arguing that Tokyo has gone back on its promise that the water would not be released until the plan received the public&#39;s widespread acceptance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even though South Korea said that it respects the nuclear watchdog&#39;s endorsement of Japan&#39;s plan to release treated water into the ocean, Seoul also made it clear that it would issue its own assessment of the IAEA&#39;s findings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The IAEA report and an earlier offer by South Korean Prime Minister Han Duck-soo to drink treated Fukushima water had clearly done little to convince the country&#39;s activists, fisheries and seafood industries, even its consumers, many of whom had stockpiled sea salt and other seafood items.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, South Korea&#39;s top opposition leader Lee Jae-myung even challenged Japanese officials to drink the treated radioactive water if the water is as safe as the officials claimed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, Pacific island nations also called on Japan to delay the release of water from the destroyed Fukushima nuclear power plant over fears that fisheries will be contaminated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With more countries conducting their own risk assessments and the further reverberations that can be expected, buckle up for a choppy and tempestuous ride ahead in the days leading up to the release of the radioactive water, which reportedly could happen as early as next month.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;60-Second Catch-up&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China imposes de facto ban on Japanese seafood imports amid anger over Fukushima water release plan&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over 70 per cent of Fukushima waste water fails discharge limits and needs more treatment, says China&#39;s nuclear watchdog&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As activists slam IAEA&#39;s approval of Fukushima water dump, others say criticism is &#39;Japan bashing&#39;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Opinion: Our fragile oceans should not be a dumping ground for Fukushima&#39;s radioactive waste water&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Explainer: What to know about Japan&#39;s plan to release treated radioactive water from Fukushima nuclear plant into the sea&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong to carry out more research on Japan&#39;s plan to discharge radioactive waste water from Fukushima nuclear plant into sea, despite UN watchdog&#39;s go-ahead&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Opinion: 5 questions for Japan on its plan to dump Fukushima nuclear plant waste water into the sea&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Deep dives&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scientists from Hong Kong have unveiled a cheap and efficient device designed to test for radioactive contaminants in marine areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The development team on Tuesday explained the devices, small, gel-filled containers created to check levels of heavy metals in marine areas and dubbed “artificial mussels”, were modified to track the presence of radioactive contaminants instead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hongkongers could lose their appetite for Japanese food if the country discharged treated waste water from the Fukushima plant into the ocean, some of the city&#39;s catering sector leaders have said, as lawmakers ramped up calls for a hardliner approach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japanese media outlets on Wednesday reported the scheme could go ahead as early as August, a day after the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) said the plan “would have a negligible radiological impact on people and the environment”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan is pushing ahead with plans to release more than 1 million tonnes of water that it claims have been cleansed of harmful radionuclides from the crippled reactors at the Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power station, despite opposition from neighbouring nations, local residents and environmental groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Japanese government insists its Advanced Liquid Processing System (ALPS) has eliminated virtually all the radionuclides from the heavily diluted water that will be released into the Pacific Ocean from a 1km-long pipe that has been constructed at the site, with a number of global nuclear energy experts concurring that release of the treated water is the best available option.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japanese officials have urged the Hong Kong government to consider scientific evidence before deciding whether to tighten curbs on importing seafood from the country if it opts to discharge treated radioactive water into the sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country&#39;s consulate in Hong Kong and visiting officials on Friday sought to allay concerns over plans to dispose of water used to cool melted nuclear fuel at Japan&#39;s Fukushima Daiichi power plant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A survey has found Hongkongers plan to buy less food imported from Japan and are more hesitant to visit the country due to Tokyo&#39;s plan to discharge waste water from the Fukushima nuclear plant into the sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong Federation of Trade Unions (FTU) urged city authorities on Friday to tighten restrictions on food imported from Japan, as it released the results of its survey of 601 adults carried out this month on the controversial discharge plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korean Prime Minister Han Duck-soo has offered to drink the waste water from Japan&#39;s crippled nuclear reactors after it has been treated, challenging opposition lawmakers to bring the water to him for a public display of consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han made the remarks at the National Assembly on Monday as critics accused President Yoon Suk-yeol&#39;s government of turning a blind eye to Japan&#39;s plan to release contaminated waste water from the Fukushima nuclear power plant into the ocean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong may toughen labelling requirements for Japanese food if the country goes ahead with releasing contaminated waste water from the Fukushima power plant into the ocean, the city&#39;s environment minister has told lawmakers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Environment and Ecology Tse Chin-wan on Tuesday also said the scope and duration of any ban on Japanese seafood imports had yet to be decided.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s environment minister on Sunday warned that a potential ban on contaminated Japanese seafood imports could cover more than five prefectures already under restrictions, adding city authorities would boost screening resources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Environment and Ecology Tse Chin-wan told a television programme that the exact location and number of banned import areas in Japan depended on test results from the International Atomic Energy Agency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Global Impact is a weekly curated newsletter featuring a news topic originating in China with a significant macro impact for our newsreaders around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sign up now!&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 14:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[At least 22 die in India as extra-heavy monsoon rains trigger severe flooding, landslides]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3227101/least-22-die-india-extra-heavy-monsoon-rains-trigger-severe-flooding-landslides?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 14:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/d4dfcf20-486e-4130-9821-d7c2e5cbe61a_6cc8f214.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Torrential rains across northern India have killed at least 22 people, as well as causing landslides and flash floods in the region, authorities and local media said on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Schools in New Delhi were closed after heavy rains lashed the national capital over the weekend, with 15.3cm of rainfall recorded in one day – the most for 40 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities in the Himalayan states of Himachal Pradesh and Uttarakhand also asked people not to venture out of their homes unless necessary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least 22 people died in floods and landslides in the northern states of Himachal Pradesh, Uttarakhand, Uttar Pradesh, Jammu and Kashmir and Punjab on Sunday, the Times of India newspaper reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the northern state of Himachal Pradesh, flash floods over the weekend brought down a bridge and swept away several shanty dwellings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities used helicopters to rescue people stranded on roads and bridges because of the rain, Asian News International footage showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;People fear venturing out&#39;: dozens die as intense heat sweeps northern India&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Streets across the northern states, including in Punjab, Delhi and Uttarakhand were flooded. In some areas, rescuers used rubber rafts to rescue people stranded inside their homes, local media said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Please stay inside your homes because more heavy rain is expected in the next 24 hours,” Himachal Pradesh Chief Minister Sukhvinder Singh Sukhu said in an appeal on social media late on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many districts in Himachal Pradesh received a month&#39;s rainfall in a day at the weekend, said a senior weather department official.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Delhi, Punjab, and Himachal Pradesh have received 112 per cent, 100 per cent and 70 per cent more rainfall than average so far in the current monsoon season that started on June 1, according to the department.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The weather department predicted more heavy rain for the coming days. Residents also have to deal with flooded roads, traffic jams and power cuts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by dpa&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine goes on Nato membership offensive ahead of summit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227134/ukraine-goes-nato-membership-offensive-ahead-summit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 13:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/73ee9fe7-09a8-41a4-b91f-08093ea990ec_d74a3bbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukraine went on the offensive in its push to join the Nato defence alliance ahead of this week&#39;s Nato summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky told US broadcaster ABC News that he wants “all the decisions to be made during the summit” not ahead of time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t want to go to Vilnius for fun if the decision has been made beforehand,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two-day Nato summit begins in Vilnius, the Lithuanian capital on Tuesday and will focus, in part, on how to bring Ukraine, which is under attack from Russia, closer to the alliance and what security guarantees it can be given after Russia&#39;s war of aggression ends.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ukraine should get clear security guarantees while it is not in Nato,” Zelensky told ABC. “这是非常重要的一点。 Only under these conditions would our meeting make sense.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky returned from Turkey on Saturday – the 500th day of Russia&#39;s full-scale invasion – after a regional tour to drum up support ahead of the summit with Western allies, who have pledged billions in military aid.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine vows it will not use cluster munitions in Russia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A formal invitation to join the 31-member defence alliance is not likely to happen in Vilnius however.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden, who arrived on Sunday in Britain on his way to the Nato summit, said he hoped the military alliance leaders would “lay out a rational path for Ukraine to be able to qualify to be able to get into Nato”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to CNN, he said there were also “other qualifications that need to be met, including democratisation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think there is unanimity in Nato about whether or not to bring Ukraine into the Nato family now, at this moment, in the middle of a war,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bringing Ukraine in now, Biden said, would mean “war with Russia” because of the Nato commitment to collective defence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also in the spotlight in Vilnius will be Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, the main obstacle to Sweden&#39;s attempts to join Nato alongside neighbour Finland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan accuses Sweden of being too lenient on anti-Islamic demonstrations and militant Kurdish groups that have waged a long insurgency in Turkey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sweden recently changed its anti-terrorism legislation and lifted an arms embargo on Turkey. But a man burned a Koran outside a mosque in Stockholm last week, and Erdogan signalled that this would pose another hurdle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He equated “those who permitted the crime” to those who perpetrated it.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Koran burning in Sweden angers Muslim world&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Turkey and the US are also at an impasse over the sale of F-16 fighter jets. Erdogan wants the upgraded planes, but Biden says Sweden&#39;s Nato membership has to be dealt with first.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Underscoring the prominence of Turkey at the upcoming summit, Biden held a lengthy call with Erdogan aboard Air Force One on the way to London. During the conversation, Biden “conveyed his desire to welcome Sweden into Nato as soon as possible,” according to the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It&#39;s not the first time that Erdogan has sought to use a Nato summit for Turkish gain. In 2009, he held up the nomination of Anders Fogh Rasmussen as secretary general but agreed to the move after securing some senior posts for Turkish officials at the alliance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Max Bergmann, a former State Department official who leads the Europe Programme at the Centre for Strategic and International Studies, said there&#39;s growing frustration among allies toward Erdogan, building on concerns about his ties to Russian President Vladimir Putin, democratic backsliding and sanctions evasion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They&#39;ve tried playing nice,” Bergmann said. “The question is whether it&#39;s time to get much more confrontational.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hungary&#39;s prime minister, Viktor Orban, is also delaying his country&#39;s approval of Sweden&#39;s membership. In response, Idaho Senator Jim Risch, the top Republican on the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, is blocking a US$735 million US arms sale to Hungary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least one potentially difficult issue is off the summit agenda.成员们没有就新的 Natp 领导人寻求共识，而是同意将自 2014 年以来担任该职位的延斯·斯托尔滕贝格 (Jens Stoltenberg) 的任期延长一年。 It&#39;s his fourth extension.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most members wanted a woman to be the next secretary general, and Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen had been considered a favourite.但波兰坚持选择来自波罗的海国家的候选人，因为北欧已经连续出现过两任秘书长。 (Stoltenberg was a Norwegian prime minister and Rasmussen was a Danish prime minister.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others are sceptical of accepting a nominee from the Baltics, whose leaders tend to be more provocative in their approach to Russia, including supporting Ukraine&#39;s desire to rapidly join Nato.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;dpa, Agence France-Presse and Associated Press&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese pharma tech giant Wuxi Biologics plans to spin off international business in Hong Kong IPO]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3227127/chinese-pharma-tech-giant-wuxi-biologics-plans-spin-international-business-hong-kong-ipo?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 12:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/3fa8b833-5e13-4946-8c6b-3d38906970a9_524a0b29.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Wuxi Biologics, China&#39;s largest biologic drugs services company, is planning to spin off its international business, Wuxi XDC, in an initial public offering in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wuxi Biologics holds a 60 per cent controlling stake in Wuxi XDC, which will remain its subsidiary after the spin-off, according to a filing submitted to the stock exchange on Sunday. The company did not disclose the amount it hopes to raise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wuxi plans to expand its offering beyond so-called antibody-drug conjugates (ADCs) to “strengthen our in -house discovery and development capabilities and manufacturing capacity”, the filing said. ADCs are biopharmaceutical drugs designed as a targeted therapy for treating cancer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Capital raised from the IPO will go towards building new manufacturing facilities in Singapore, expanding production capacity in China, strategic investments and acquisitions as well as working capital and other general corporate purposes, according to the exchange filing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wuxi XDC saw net profit increase 16.5 per cent in the first quarter of the year to 80.7 million yuan (US$11.16 million) compared to the same period last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Morgan Stanley, Goldman Sachs and JPMorgan have been named joint advisers for the IPO.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shares of parent company Wuxi Biologics, which listed in Hong Kong 2017, jumped as much as 3 per cent in early morning trading on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The announcement comes as a string of biotech companies file to list their shares in Hong Kong. Insilico Medicine, which is based in the city, has set its sights on a US$200 million IPO, according to sources, while Sichuan Kelun-Biotech Pharmaceutical is ready to list on Tuesday, with the aim of raising US$208.6 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s biotechnology ecosystem has grown significantly since the introduction of legislation called chapter 18A, which allows pre-revenue biotech companies to list in the city, said Louis Lau, a partner at KPMG China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The city has become a very attractive option for IPO applicants engaged in specialist technologies,” said Lau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said this is also attributable to Hong Kong&#39;s position as “connector” to mainland China and international markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong is the world&#39;s second-largest fundraising hub for biotechnology after the Nasdaq, and the largest in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lau said uncertainty arising from tensions between the US and China gives Hong Kong an edge over the US market.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 13:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>