<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Germany wants to deepen China agricultural trade ties by combating climate change suffering, eyes lifting of pork ban]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3227191/germany-wants-deepen-china-agricultural-trade-ties-combating-climate-change-suffering-eyes-lifting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/259cbb34-e63f-46e4-9f73-f7aa203d1663_edfacea9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在气候变化问题恶化和全球供应链中断的情况下，中德应深化农业合作德国外交官表示，他们也希望北京放宽猪肉进口禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国有社会责任分享其高度数字化农业领域的经验和专业知识，而中国则发挥着重要作用，因为德国驻北京大使馆经济部部长兼公使衔参赞亨德里克·巴克林 (Hendrik Barkeling) 表示，“没有哪个工业比农业更受气候变化的影响”。巴克林周五在甘肃省西北部城市兰州举行的中国（甘肃）-德国农业未来合作会议上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每个国家都有特殊的责任应对这些挑战，进一步提高农业生产效率，同时确保自然资源的保护。”他在由德国农业学会、德国驻华大使馆和中国国际贸易促进委员会共同主办的活动中补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十几家德国农业企业的中国代表出席了此次会议，该会议与一年一度的兰州投资贸易洽谈会同时举行，还有来自甘肃省各地的众多企业和地方官员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “[此类交流]尤其重要，因为过去三年的新冠大流行阻碍了人员交流并扰乱了供应链。由于俄罗斯对乌克兰的侵略，世界上最大的粮食出口国之一与世界隔绝了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西方并未对俄罗斯粮食贸易实施直接制裁，但对银行进行了限制战争造成的物流障碍和其他物流障碍使出口商运输农产品和安排付款变得更加困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就是为什么在德国关于去风险的讨论越来越多，同样的讨论巴克林说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“不会再出现下降”：中国的农作物打击行动针对关键谷物、油籽&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他表示，中国日益关注安全和自给自足 — — 这不是一个问题。仅限于农业领域——有着相似的逻辑，关键是提高两国未来经济关系的可靠性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这可能包括恢复中国进口德国猪肉，而德国猪肉在去年被禁止。 2020年9月，由于非洲猪瘟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国一直在试图说服中国接受“区域化概念”，即仅停止从发现该疾病的地区进口，而不是全面禁止进口。整个国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“德国希望再次向中国出口，”Barkeling 补充道。 “疫情已被成功遏制。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国驻北京大使馆农业和食品参赞弗里德里克·多夫勒表示，中国是德国在欧盟以外最重要的出口国家之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;德国约三分之一的农产品用于出口，而中国则面临着用不到 10% 的耕地养活世界近 20% 人口的挑战，她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“这向我们表明，贸易是重要的，我们必须共享资源、分工合作、互通有无。”她在兰州会议期间也表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席多次发出强烈呼吁近年来，特别是在乌克兰战争之后，中国实现了粮食自给自足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在12月举行的年度中央农村工作会议上，习近平表示，农业是国家安全的基础，而薄弱环节——包括生产力低下——必须解决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平表示，2022年乌克兰战争爆发以来，已有30多个国家粮食出口受到限制，有的国家出现社会动荡甚至政权更迭。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“世界其他地区的遏制措施不断升级，各种不确定性和不可预测性明显增加，”他在三月份发布的讲话全文中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“农业出了问题，我们的碗就到了别人手里，我们就得靠别人吃饭了。那么我们如何实现现代化呢？”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mainland China running ‘more subtle’ campaign to sway 2024 vote, Taipei says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3227214/mainland-china-running-more-subtle-campaign-sway-2024-vote-taipei-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 21:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/7af97a6b-9a74-439c-a9f3-f7d48c66ff59_24b77db9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京正在尝试用“更微妙的方式”在总统大选之前影响台湾选民台北的一位安全消息人士警告说，一月份的立法院选举。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家安全局的消息人士称，这次夸大的两岸战争幽灵加上取消某些进口禁令等软性让步正在发挥作用。台湾最高情报机构台湾情报局表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去的选举年中，北京对倾向独立的民进党发表敌对言论，希望选民选择国民党等亲大陆政党的候选人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，在之前打击民进党的努力适得其反后，它似乎正在缓和批评，而是选择强调如果执政党继续执政，爆发战争的风险更大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“除了不间断的军事威胁之外，中国共产党还试图通过制造战争迫在眉睫的气氛以及人们如果继续支持民进党或亲民主派就会面临失去家园和家人的感觉，在台湾内部制造恐惧。”消息人士称。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;台湾总统候选人赖清德强调两岸现状&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京一直试图利用 TikTok 和其他社交媒体等平台给台湾人留下深刻印象消息人士称，民进党政府及其“敌对”大陆政策应将台湾带入战争边缘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了更频繁的战机飞越之外，中国人民解放军还携带随着民进党与美国的关系日益密切，近几个月来，台湾在台湾周围进行了大规模的实弹演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[北京]还试图营造这样的印象：我们的外国朋友，包括美国，消息人士称，“台湾不值得信任，因为一旦发生两岸战争，他们不太可能派兵救援台湾。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京根据“一个中国原则”声称对台湾拥有主权，并且认为其与海外政府的交流是一种违法行为。它还警告这个自治岛屿，任何宣布独立的行为都将导致攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国与大多数国家一样，不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对任何单方面改变台湾主权的行为。以武力改变两岸现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;协助保卫台湾也受到国内法的约束，其中包括武器销售和军事交流，但尚未直接宣布将派遣美军到台湾有助于阻止来自北京的任何攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于台湾是否面临潜在的海峡两岸攻击的争论一直占据着近年来的头条新闻，俄罗斯入侵乌克兰再次引发了人们对北京对台湾的军事意图的猜测。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在 2021 年 4 月的一篇文章中，《经济学人》将台湾视为亚洲最危险的战争爆发点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是在美国前官员和学者发表评论两个月后国会听证会将该岛列为美中关系的第一大爆发点，有可能引发军事冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印太司令菲利普·戴维森和美国空军司令迈克·米尼汉将军是美国官员中的一员预计2025年至2027年期间与北京会因台湾问题发生冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消息人士称，台湾认为，除了渲染战争风险外，北京还试图描绘外国代表团的一系列访问“这是为了迷惑台湾公众，激起他们对政府不顾一切邀请外国游客的不满。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;消息人士称，另一个花招是“先暂停某些台湾产品的进口，直到选举临近才恢复发货”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后不久，北京禁止进口2000多种台湾食品美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 于 8 月访问台北，此举也引发了解放军在台湾周围进行数日史无前例的实弹演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后于 12 月延长了对 11 家啤酒和酿酒厂的禁令来自台湾的物品。然而，一些产品的进口从一月份开始逐渐恢复，包括某些鱼类、农产品和酒类产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当北京于 6 月 20 日解除对台湾糖苹果的禁令时，主要反对党国民党声称此举消息人士称，虚假信息是北京试图影响选举而发起的影响力运动的另一个主要部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一月份之间6 月份，我们发现了 1,800 多条虚假信息，目的是渲染民进党政府不适合继续统治。”该消息人士称，并补充说，随着选举的临近，预计这一数字只会增加。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[President Joe Biden takes tea and talks about climate change with Britain’s King Charles III]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227216/president-joe-biden-takes-tea-and-talks-climate-britains-king-charles-iii?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 21:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/f097ccfe-21de-4323-9f62-8d621f64e9fd_a4e57513.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登于 2019 年 12 月 11 日与国王查理三世进行茶会和气候变化会谈周一，在北约领导人乌克兰峰会之前与英国首相里希·苏纳克举行花园会议后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;80 岁的拜登总统乘坐他的海军陆战队一号直升机从伦敦市中心的唐宁街飞往温莎城堡，下来接受身穿红夹克的威尔士卫队的欢迎仪式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;星条旗永不落和上帝保佑国王在伦敦西部庄严的皇家住所修剪整齐的草坪上响起，然后两人就消失了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是自查尔斯五月正式加冕为国王以来拜登首次与查尔斯会面。美国总统没有出席加冕典礼，但由他的妻子第一夫人吉尔·拜登代表。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乔·拜登将前往欧洲。国王和战争已提上他的议程&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年 9 月，这对夫妇参加了查尔斯的母亲伊丽莎白女王的国葬，而拜登则在 2021 年七国集团峰会后在温莎看望了已故女王.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文周日表示，74 岁的查尔斯是一位终身环保主义者，拜登认为他是气候变化问题上的“号角”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;顶级金融家和慈善家们也在温莎开会，讨论气候融资，以加大对发展中国家减少碳排放的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出席会议的有英国能源安全和净零部长格兰特·沙普斯和拜登的气候特使约翰·克里。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;英国政府表示，到 2030 年需要超过 1 万亿美元来帮助发展中经济体在 2050 年实现净零碳排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;额外投资，包括来自私人部门的投资部门需要减少非二氧化碳排放、停止砍伐森林以及适应和增强气候变化的抵御能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登于周日晚间乘坐空军一号抵达英国，正前往美国立陶宛首都维尔纽斯参加为期两天的北约会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登对英国进行飞行访问之际，乌克兰成为即将举行的联盟会议的首要议程，基辅在与俄罗斯的战争结束后将推动加入。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西方盟友一致认为，乌克兰不能在战争仍在激烈的情况下加入，因为这将使北约陷入与拥有核武器的俄罗斯的直接冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但美国被视为最有可能加入的国家。对其成员身份犹豫不决。拜登称基辅的申请“为时过早”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他对美国有线电视新闻网 (CNN) 表示，“我认为基辅还没有准备好加入北约”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，一位西方官员表示盟友“准备”放弃乌克兰申请的会员行动计划要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登和苏纳克签署关于人工智能、清洁能源的“大西洋宣言”协议&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;拜登和苏纳克举行了会谈不到 40 分钟，坐在藤椅上，喝着唐宁街特别品牌的杯子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐宁街表示，两人“一致认为有必要加强我们的联盟并保持对乌克兰的支持”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐宁街表示，两人“一致认为有必要加强我们的联盟并保持对乌克兰的支持”。 >;&lt;p>;苏纳克还淡化了一些西方盟友质疑美国向乌克兰供应集束弹药以及人权组织对其对平民构成危险的担忧后出现的裂痕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理的官方发言人随后对记者表示，讨论了这个问题，并承认提供武器“对美国来说是一个艰难的选择”。但他补充说，这是“俄罗斯的侵略战争强加给他们的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来，拜登和苏纳克定期会面，这位英国领导人试图修复因特朗普任期动荡而紧张的跨大西洋关系。鲍里斯·约翰逊和利兹·特拉斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爱尔兰裔美国人拜登对英国与欧盟就英国脱欧后北爱尔兰贸易问题发生争执的立场被视为紧张局势的核心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;自苏纳克和布鲁塞尔就货物流动达成一项协议以来，两国关系有所改善，保护了该省因英国统治而发生的 30 年来的暴力事件后来之不易的和平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登告诉记者，他“不可能”与更亲密的朋友和更伟大的盟友会面”，并补充道：“我们的关系坚如磐石。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登从立陶宛前往北约最新成员国芬兰，参加美国-北欧领导人峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong travellers takes to skies again, with more and longer trips and higher spending, survey finds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3227209/hong-kong-travellers-takes-skies-again-more-and-longer-trips-and-higher-spending-survey-finds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 20:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/987da472-087b-4ccb-b069-fe69c363f6be_385a193c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港市民的出行次数越来越多，出行时间也越来越长，消费也较去年同期有所上升一项调查发现，尽管机票价格天价，但仍处于大流行前的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城市在线旅行社 Klook 表示，在 2 月份取消旅行限制后，公众已经弥补了损失的时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Klook客路总经理Kenny Sham Ho-ki补充道，随着航空公司继续从疫情中复苏，机票价格持续上涨，但这似乎并没有阻止人们出行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港人非常聪明。他们有很多方法来应对这一点。例如，他们可能会选择不太热门的时间去旅行，”他解释道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“或者，如果是在旺季，他们会选择不为人知的城市，这样机票争夺就不那么激烈了。” .”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Klook客路在6月份对3,412名受访者进行了调查，96%的受访者表示他们计划在未来12个月内至少旅行一次，40%的受访者告诉该公司他们预计出国三次或以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;首选的旅游目的地是日本——66% 的受访者表示他们计划明年去那里旅行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其次是台湾、泰国、韩国和欧洲。第五名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;受访者表示，他们准备每次旅行至少花费 10,000 港元（1,277 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在疫情爆发之前，香港人倾向于消费他们去度假时每人花费约 5,000 至 6,000 港元。”岑说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这表明与疫情前相比，他们目前更愿意在旅行上消费。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;大多数人或接受调查的人（78％）表示，食物和餐饮是最重要的活动，其次是参观景点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅行者表示，他们正在寻找更深入的当地体验和更倾向于另辟蹊径。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;就座位数而言，新加坡不再是香港前五条航线之一&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;答案与另一项民意调查结果一致，受访者表示，购物不再是旅行的主要目的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sham 补充说，调查显示，69% 的游客仍然更喜欢四到七天的短暂休息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他Sham 强调，约 25% 的旅行者希望将外出时间延长至连续 8 至 15 天，与新冠疫情爆发前相比，选择长途旅行的人数增加了 92%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sham补充道，18 至 26 岁的年轻人是希望在国外度过更长时间的重要群体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东瀛旅游执行董事 Steve Huen Kwok-chuen 也同意他注意到的与城市的“重大差异” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“例如，在疫情之前，报名我们东亚目的地的客户大部分都选择了五日游。但现在，很多人选择了六天或更长时间。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“实际上，现在选择五天的人的比例已经下降到10%左右。”&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;香港机票价格可能会在 2024 年中期之前保持高位：卡塔尔航空高管&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;禤表示，他认为这一趋势是机票价格上涨和需求被压抑的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“也许他们认为这样更物有所值。另外，他们可能已经有一段时间没有旅行了。”他解释道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他也同意日本很受欢迎，主要是因为飞往该国的航班恢复较快，尽管前往目的地的机票价格也仍然很高.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;禤表示，香港居民前往内地的比例已回升至疫情前水平的80%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，中国大陆也已成为一个有吸引力的目的地，与大流行之前相比，更多的旅客前往北方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你可以乘坐高铁过境，前往内地的航班也相对便宜，”禤说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“此外，那里的通货膨胀并不像其他地方那么严重。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在政府取消大部分旅行限制并在二月份重新开放边境后，从香港出发的机票价格与全球趋势一致，飙升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;航空公司面临着员工短缺和燃油价格昂贵的困境，该市的旗舰航空公司国泰航空预计机票价格要到明年年底才会下降。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Salt + light + tech = record-setting Chinese solar power station]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3227202/salt-light-tech-record-setting-chinese-solar-power-station?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 20:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/49265cca-4c44-4717-9232-3eb41c79a231_89985af4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;世界上最大的联合太阳能发电站和盐场已并入电网据其运营商称，中国有能力满足 150 万户家庭的电力需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国有企业中国华电集团公司表示，华电天津海景电站已并入北部城市的电网周六，天津。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该站由大量太阳能电池板组成，安装在超过 13 平方公里的长芦盐田上，长芦盐田是中国最古老的沿海盐场之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “盐光互补”系统利用双面太阳能电池板产生电力和盐，吸收上方的直射阳光以及下方水面反射的阳光。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国华电表示，该站有一个装机容量1吉瓦，每年发电15亿千瓦时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司表示，所产生的绿色电力将有助于减少碳排放，同时不会影响盐田的环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;国家电视台中央电视台表示，这些面板的间距比其他工厂更远，以优化能源和盐的生产，并以特定角度倾斜，以最大限度地减少水面的阴影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;盐田还项目负责人杨帆向央视表示，该设施是“漂浮式光伏发电的新型复合工业模式， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方通讯社新华社称，山东省滨州市的一个养虾场在其顶部建造了太阳能项目后，年产量增加了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;据报道，产量增加是因为面板遮蔽了虾池，使水温降低了 1 至 2 摄氏度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国华电董事长蒋毅表示，该项目增加了公司的装机容量产能超过200GW。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang表示，该公司正在运营其他“千兆瓦项目”，包括一座设计每小时生产600立方米氢气的太阳能制氢工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家能源局政府的目标是到年底全国太阳能发电装机容量达到490GW。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国电力企业联合会的数据，截至3月份，太阳能发电装机容量达到430GW。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Philippines has the edge on global workers supply thanks to its young population, expert says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3227205/philippines-has-edge-global-workers-supply-thanks-its-young-population?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 20:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/9b9015a4-27da-4ed7-bb75-b065aa662b34_f55a57bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;与日本和韩国等富裕邻国不同，老龄化社会可能会这是菲律宾未来几十年面临的问题中最小的一个，使其有能力为世界提供所需的人力资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人口挑战不在于人口老龄化，而更多在于年轻人口。世界银行发展研究小组驻华盛顿的首席经济学家 Quy-Toan Do 在马尼拉表示，“在国内或国际上寻找工作机会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在未来，我们可以放心地做出预测：到 2050 年，菲律宾的人口规模仍然不断扩大，而且仍然年轻化。”他指出，菲律宾每名妇女生育的孩子数量约为 2.8 个，远高于 2.1 个替代率。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着出生率下降，菲律宾想要更少的婴儿&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;多边机构在其《2023 年世界发展报告：移民、难民和社会》中表示，富裕国家以及越来越多的中等收入国家，传统上移民的主要来源地面临着人口下降的问题。报告称，这将加剧全球对工人的竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 4 月份首次发布的报告，中等收入国家“在致富之前就开始老龄化”，并与菲律宾政府官员、招聘人员和专家进行了讨论。周一的民间社会团体。相比之下，人口激增国家的年轻人“在不具备全球劳动力市场所需技能的情况下进入劳动力市场”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些趋势使得有必要根据移民的情况来指导政策&#39; 技能符合目的地国家的需求。世界银行表示，全球约有 1.84 亿移民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾中央银行预计，在稳定的收入支持下，该国的汇款（消费者支出的主要驱动力）今年和明年将增长 3%。对菲律宾工人的需求和东道国的劳动力短缺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界银行的 Do 预测，随着人们移民和获得更好的工作，菲律宾的汇款将继续增长。然而，他警告这个以精通英语的工人而闻名的东南亚国家，要警惕来自印度等其他国家的日益激烈的竞争。 “有竞争力是件好事；主要的挑战是保持现状，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong talent drive: more than 100,000 applications received in 6 months, city leader says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227198/hong-kong-talent-drive-more-100000-applications-received-6-months-city-leader-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 19:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/7819e3e7-56a0-4455-b433-548b1ae2b517_ca6d5ab9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;今年至今，香港各类人才计划已收到超过10万份申请，行政长官李家超表示，这表明香港继续保持对专业人士的吸引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港领导人周一还强调，香港应充当国际资本和高素质人才之间的牵线搭桥。绿色项目，为国家和地区层面的行业发展做出贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李在香港未来论坛上发表讲话，介绍了政府吸引工人的不同计划的最新成功情况并抵消了人才流失的影响，截至 6 月底，已收到超过 10 万份申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这几乎是每年引进 35,000 名工人目标的三倍。这充分体现了香港对世界各地人才的吸引力。”他说，但没有详细说明有多少申请已获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;领导人李家超表示，香港已做好重返国际的准备&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;去年 12 月，政府启动了顶尖人才通行证计划，降低了现有准入计划的某些要求，并在海外办事处设立了团队，吸引专业人士来到香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee 上个月在华盛顿邮报论坛上表示，截至5月底，政府已收到84,000份申请，约49,000份已获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港领导人周一表示，得益于“一带一路”赋予的优势，香港作为国际金融中心的地位依然稳固。 “一个国家，两种制度”的治理原则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，在全球范围更广泛的不确定性中，香港稳定的金融体系也仍然具有高度吸引力，并指出国际货币基金组织最近的一项评估赞扬了香港的联系汇率制港元兑美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港将继续依托金融、贸易、航运等传统优势，同时通过创新科技、文化艺术探索新的经济引擎。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他认为，绿色项目是值得挖掘的增长领域之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“凭借金融业的优势，香港必须在引导国际资本方面发挥重要作用”由于富裕游客数量的增加和本地消费的强劲，下半年的表现将会更好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他表示，未来经济将主要由金融和创科驱动。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中央政府驻香港联络办公室主任郑彦雄在论坛上表示，香港已经度过了技术和产业变革、地缘政治冲突和疫情冲击带来的全球挑战时期。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港的每一次崛起都是在世界变化中实现的”。 “世界的每一次变化都有利于香港，为香港带来新的篇章”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港是“增值超级联系人”，人才计划大获成功：领跑者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;他补充说，作为中国与世界之间的“超级联系人”，中央政府赋予了这座城市最重要的作用，这将进一步巩固其独特的地位和优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑应立法会主席梁君彦的邀请，定于周五与香港立法会议员共进午餐。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia’s Mahathir turns 98 with ‘Malay supremacy’ on his mind. Is he ‘obsessed’ with Anwar?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227200/malaysias-mahathir-turns-98-malay-supremacy-his-mind-he-obsessed-anwar?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 19:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/5940e9e5-baa0-4b6c-8953-09104e236eb5_9ada7e1a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周一庆祝自己 98 岁生日的马哈蒂尔·穆罕默德拒绝离开政坛尽管去年在马来西亚大选中遭遇耻辱性失败，但他还是在关键州民意调查中及时返回捍卫马来人权利，这可能会挑战他的宿敌——总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他的前门生安瓦尔上任后不久在担任多种族政府掌舵的总理后，马哈蒂尔回归了自己的政治活动主义，推出了“马来公告”，概述了该国占多数的马来族所面临的“严峻形势”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该文件已此后成为该国马来民族主义者的集结点，得到了国民联盟（PN）联盟领导人的认可，该联盟在议会中构成了强大的、完全由马来人反对的席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两次任职作为马来西亚政坛不可撼动的遗产，马哈蒂尔面临着越来越多的质疑，质疑其竞选活动的动机，这场竞选势必会激起马来人以及马来西亚其他宗教和族裔群体的焦虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;答案已经出现观察人士称，他将成为安瓦尔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“马哈蒂尔的一方面真正关心他所认为的马来人至上主义的侵蚀，而他和许多马来人都认为马来人至上主义是神圣不可侵犯的，”吴艾说新加坡国际事务研究所高级研究员孙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“马哈蒂尔也有一面痴迷于仇恨，从而试图让安瓦尔脱离总理职位。因此，我们现在看到的是马哈蒂尔这两方面之间的相互作用。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马哈蒂尔与安瓦尔的关系如何塑造马来西亚的政治&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两人之间的积怨源于1998 年，在安瓦尔首次担任总理期间，马哈蒂尔因在亚洲金融危机最严重的时期如何管理国家财政方面存在分歧，决定解雇他的副手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔最终因以下原因入狱：腐败和鸡奸——他坚称这些指控是出于政治动机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在服刑之前，安瓦尔发起了改革运动，该运动旨在团结反对派，并慢慢削弱马哈蒂尔领导的长期执政的巫统政党的根基。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，安瓦尔在接受记者采访时表示，他这边的宿怨也没有消退，他形容马哈蒂尔在民调结果惨淡后迫切希望保持自己的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在线新闻门户网站《当今大马》援引安瓦尔的话说：“我会让他变得无关紧要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马哈蒂尔也因涉嫌试图通过《马来文公告》破坏议会民主而受到调查。 Police took his statement last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mahathir, a doctor with roots in the royal town of Alor Setar in northern Kedah state, attempted a comeback at the general election last November with a new party, Pejuang. But it fell flat as he failed to defend his long-held parliamentary seat on the popular holiday island of Langkawi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The usually media savvy nonagenarian went into near-radio silence before re-emerging with his “Malay Proclamation” which warned that Anwar&#39;s new multiracial administration would erode the rights and privileges of Malays, who account for nearly two-thirds of voters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Malays have already lost so much territory … [they] will disappear from their country and from the world,” Mahathir said last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Malays voted in droves for the Malay nationalist alliance of Bersatu and PAS amid deep-seated anger over decades of alleged corruption and mismanagement by Umno.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Malaysia&#39;s Muhyiddin, Anwar make rival claims about forming next government&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Public sentiment was also soured by rising living costs and prolonged financial strain caused by the pains of the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And with six states in the peninsula going to polls on August 12, the pressure is on Anwar and his unity government to do what they can to at least staunch the bleed in Malay support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What Mahathir has been doing is his way of undermining the unity government,” said Adib Zalkapli, a Malaysia director with government affairs and public policy consultancy BowerGroupAsia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no space for him to compete in the elections after a humiliating defeat at the last general election, but Mahathir is still very influential, there are segments of the Malay community that look up to him.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While a political comeback may appear far-fetched, Mahathir continues to be well-regarded by Malays across age and class.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many older business owners are grateful for the preferential treatment that they were afforded during his earlier rule, while some youths are enamoured by the “golden age” of development under his wing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mahathir has a long record of going after leaders who he deems have failed to uphold the rights and privileges of the Malays.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He had an infamously bad relationship with Malaysia&#39;s first prime minister, Tunku Abdul Rahman, who Mahathir blamed for allowing the wealth disparity between Malays and ethnic Chinese, which officials say was the reason behind the deadly riots of May 13, 1969.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When his own turn came to take the premiership, Mahathir made sure he left his mark. To date, he is the longest-serving prime minister, having spent 22 years at the helm during his first tenure from 1981 to 2003.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Described as Malaysia&#39;s father of development, he fast-tracked Malaysia&#39;s industrialisation as he launched the national car, oversaw the construction of modern highway networks across the peninsula and built world-renowned monuments such as the KL Twin Towers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But critics also accused him of nepotism and rent-seeking, as well as a tendency to brook no dissent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After stepping down from office in 2003, Mahathir continued to exert his influence, ultimately backing the rise of yet another of his proteges – Najib Razak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ultimately, Mahathir and Najib also clashed, as the former leader balked at the new government&#39;s attempts to liberalise the market and potentially ease pro-Malay affirmative action policies that had been in place for decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The turning point came after news broke in 2015 about the multibillion-dollar scandal at state fund 1Malaysia Development Berhad (1MDB). Mahathir quit Umno and a year later led other leaders who were sacked or quit to form a new party, Bersatu.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;With Najib behind bars, is Malaysia&#39;s corruption fight finally winnable?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mahathir attended Anwar&#39;s court hearing for a second sodomy trial, ahead of formally striking a partnership with his erstwhile rival&#39;s coalition in a bid to oust Najib and Umno from power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mahathir&#39;s gambit paid off in the 2018 national polls, and he returned as prime minister for a second time, albeit briefly – he fell to a political coup in 2020 orchestrated by Malay leaders in his own party and those in Umno and Islamist party PAS.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he has said quitting politics would be “selfish” with so much relying on him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If I&#39;m only thinking about myself, I will not be in politics now.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China needs process, time to heal economic scars left by coronavirus, ex-finance minister Lou Jiwei says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3227190/china-needs-process-time-heal-economic-scars-left-coronavirus-ex-finance-minister-lou-jiwei-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 18:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/68fb4dae-809c-41c1-8e88-4ffe3b6e5b8c_d459e858.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing should not bail out its indebted local governments, and instead an increase in its fiscal deficit is needed to speed up China&#39;s economic recovery, according to former finance minister Lou Jiwei, who said a “process” is needed to heal the “scars” left by the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an interview with the state-backed China Daily, as well as in an article published by the Shanghai-based The Paper over the weekend, Lou said that policymakers need to adjust their priorities “in time” to “restore” the economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lou was China&#39;s finance minister between 2013 and 2016 and has been vocal about the country&#39;s economic problems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The scarring effect caused by the pandemic is relatively serious,” said Lou.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Enterprises, residents and local governments are all repairing their balance sheets, and it is a process to restore confidence. Only when the balance sheet returns to normal and confidence is restored, can companies dare to invest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Residents dare to consume only when the employment situation improves and they have confidence in their future income. Correspondingly, fiscal revenue will also increase.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s slower-than-expected recovery has been a growing concern among investors and businesses, especially the country&#39;s mounting local government debt.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ease up on local-debt restrictions, advisers urge as Beijing eyes stimulus boost&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Several local authorities have said recently they are not able to meet their debt repayments, raising fears over the risk of a major default.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is not expected that there will be a large-scale default in local government debt. At present, the tendency to exaggerate the risk of local government debt and put pressure on [policymakers] is on the rise,” Lou told the China Daily newspaper on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A debt swap by Beijing to relieve the local government debt burden is a “moral hazard”, and regional economies should instead sell off their own assets to meet funding deficits, Lou added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lou also suggested expanding the fiscal deficit – the shortfall in the government&#39;s income compared with its spending – by between 1.5 trillion yuan (US$208 billion) and 2 trillion yuan to subsidise rents and utilities, as well as the interest rate payments for small companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing should also drop its policy of restricting real estate loans and purchases, as well as the limits put on the rise and fall of housing prices, in order to help demand in the real estate market recover, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that an “appropriate rise” of the fiscal deficit for local governments should be used to make up for the funding gap for existing rather than for new projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If scientifically it shows that short-term fiscal policy needs to be expanded, it is necessary to increase the fiscal deficit in time to restore the economy to a normal state as soon as possible. This approach will cost the least,” Lou said in an op-ed in The Paper on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s official 2023 deficit is pegged at around 3 per cent of China&#39;s gross domestic product, and an increase of between 1.5 trillion yuan and 2 trillion yuan would lift the ratio to around 4.16 to 4.55 per cent.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘We must not forget’: Thailand remembers cave rescue that saved lives of 12 boys]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3227194/we-must-not-forget-thailand-remembers-cave-rescue-saved-lives-12-boys?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 18:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/226f4ae4-d264-485e-89f2-694fbfc70686_269d3eda.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hundreds of people gathered on Monday to mark the five-year anniversary of the dramatic rescue against impossible odds of 12 young footballers from a flooded cave in northern Thailand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now in their late teens, the boys and their coach, Ekkapol Chantawong, descended into the spotlit chambers of the Tham Luang cave complex to pay tribute to the thousands of people who worked for 18 days and nights to get them out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Wild Boars team had entered the caves in June 2018 and were trapped when rains flooded the complex, emerging after a daring international rescue operation to global acclaim.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How the Thailand cave rescue unfolded&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“If it weren&#39;t for these people we wouldn&#39;t have survived, and wouldn&#39;t have been alive this day”, Ekkapol said. “I&#39;d like to say thank you to all of you from the bottom of my heart”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the joyful anniversary was tinged with sadness following the death of 17-year-old captain Duangpetch Promthep, who passed away while on a football scholarship in Britain earlier this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His former teammates each laid white flowers at a memorial image of him outside the caves, surrounded by crowds in the bright sunlight and vivid jungle flora.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A video tribute was also played inside the cave for ex-Chiang Rai governor Narongsak Osatanakorn, who won plaudits for his handling of the incident, and who died last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must not forget the efforts of everyone involved in the rescue mission, especially of those who are no longer here with us,” said Varawut Silpa-archa, minister of natural resources and environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Offerings were also made to Jao Mae Nang Nong – a legendary princess said to be the spirit of the caves in which she supposedly died, and who was frequently invoked for strength during the rescue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The boys were on a day trip to the cave complex on June 23, 2018, when heavy rains flooded the complex via underground waterways.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They were feared dead until two British cave divers negotiated a series of narrow waterways and corridors and found them on July 2, trapped in a deep chamber, 4km (2.5 miles) from the entrance.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How Thai cave rescue of Wild Boars created new tourism destination&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The next hurdle was safely moving the boys and their coach out of the caves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a highly risky operation, they were sedated, dressed in wetsuits and breathing apparatus, and hauled through the complex by foreign cave hobbyists, expert divers, and a team of Thai navy SEALs including Saman Kunan, who died during the rescue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the odds, the boys and their coach all made it out alive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adul Sam-on, one of the footballers who shot to fame after he thanked the divers who found them in English, was granted Thai nationality following the rescue, as were his coach and two teammates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking on Monday, the now-19-year-old said he had just graduated high school in the United States, and would shortly be attending university.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While there has been a steady stream of books, TV series, and film adaptations of the rescue, the boys themselves have mostly kept out of the limelight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mongkol Booneiam, known as Mark, said he still lives – and plays football – in a nearby village.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If I have free time then I&#39;d try to go play,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘How helpless she must have felt’: Chinese mother forced to throw newborn baby into outstretched quilt from blazing third floor flat]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226901/how-helpless-she-must-have-felt-chinese-mother-forced-throw-newborn-baby-outstretched-quilt-blazing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/07/794ba721-9b64-4784-8379-3426ab16c50f_cd0ea4c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A mother&#39;s desperate act to save her month-old infant from their burning third-floor flat has captivated mainland social media after a video emerged of her throwing the baby to waiting rescuers below.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tense scene was recorded on July 5 in Wenzhou, in the eastern province of Zhejiang, and has been viewed 100 million times on Weibo and 10 million on Douyin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thick smoke can be seen billowing from the building as the mother and another woman stand at a window with the baby.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Below, more than 10 people – neighbours, shop owners and even passers-by – stand ready to catch the infant in an outstretched quilt.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Video news outlet Daxiang News said the baby was caught safely in the improvised net and the two women were rescued by firefighters who arrived minutes later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A neighbour, whose name was not given in the report, said the baby was just 40 days old.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some time after the incident, when I recalled the mother throwing down her baby, it still horrified me,” the neighbour said, adding: “The smoke was too dense. They couldn&#39;t find any way to leave.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many people on China&#39;s social media platforms sympathised with the mother&#39;s dilemma, though some criticised her actions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“How helpless she must have felt when she let go of her baby,” one person wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The mother&#39;s action was too risky!” another commenter said. “What if the baby was not caught? Why not use a basket to hold the baby and a long rope to lower the basket?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One online observer said the infant would have “definitely died” from smoke inhalation and added that the mother&#39;s decision was correct.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“She is the baby&#39;s mother. She loves her baby more than any of you. If there was another choice, would she have done what she did?” said a commenter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s good that all people came to offer their help. The scene warmed my heart,” another said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;News stories about people narrowly escaping from fires often trend on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, an 11-year-old boy in eastern Anhui province attracted widespread praise when he led his mother to safety from a fire in their flat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At his suggestion, the boy and his mother covered their mouths and noses with wet towels and crouched to minimise their exposure to the smoke as they walked down the stairs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But not all of these stories ended happily.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the eastern province of Jiangsu, two children were caught by neighbours in a quilt after their mother threw them from their third-floor home to escape a fire.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was not so lucky, missing the quilt in her own attempt and suffering serious head injuries, from which she later died.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese ride-hailing giant Didi narrows losses in first quarter on back of improved demand as domestic competition heats up]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3227151/chinese-ride-hailing-giant-didi-narrows-losses-first-quarter-back-improved-demand-domestic?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/e891c16d-ab94-481e-a06d-4d92485b3c9c_397ab47e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese ride-hailing giant Didi Global has substantially narrowed its losses in the first quarter on the back of improved demand, several months after regulators slapped it with an 8.026 billion (US$1.2 billion) fine for data violations and amid increased domestic competition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Didi recorded a net loss of 1.2 billion yuan in the first three months of this year, a 93 per cent improvement from its 16.3 billion yuan loss in the same period in 2022, the Beijing-based company reported on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First-quarter revenue reached 42.7 billion yuan, up 19.1 per cent from 35.8 billion yuan a year earlier, driven by a rapid recovery in daily transactions after a period of lacklustre demand during the Lunar New Year holiday in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Operations on the mainland, which account for Didi&#39;s primary revenue source, increased 18.7 per cent year on year to 39 billion yuan, while the company&#39;s international business grew 40.7 per cent to 1.7 billion yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Didi&#39;s adjusted Ebitda – earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortisation – for its domestic operations showed a gain of 1 billion yuan, compared to a 6.2 billion yuan loss in the first quarter last year, which was the period when it booked the hefty fine for data violations imposed by internet regulator the Cyberspace Administration of China (CAC). The fine was announced publicly last July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company&#39;s strong performance this first quarter showed how it continues to dominate China&#39;s ride-hailing market, despite going through a year-long cybersecurity investigation and efforts to “rectify” its operations. The CAC said in July last year that Didi had committed 16 offences involving the illegal collection of data from drivers and passengers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This first quarter marked Didi&#39;s first earnings result since it returned to mainland app stores and resumed new user sign-ups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Didi was only able to resume registrations of new users and make its main app available for download again in China in January this year, nearly 18 months after it was ordered to halt customer enrolment in line with the CAC&#39;s investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Didi zooms past big fine and Covid-19 to narrow losses in 2022&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Didi, which conducted its initial public offering on the New York Stock Exchange under the name Didi Global in June 30, 2021, started trading on the over-the-counter market in June last year, following a shareholder vote to delist the company from the NYSE where it raised US$4.4 billion in a public listing that angered Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The firm&#39;s return to local app stores this year was marred by weak macroeconomic conditions and fresh competition from a number of Big Tech companies, including on-demand delivery platform operator Meituan, telecommunications equipment giant Huawei Technologies, Tencent Holdings&#39; WeChat and ByteDance-owned Douyin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 313 ride-hailing platform companies had obtained licences to operate by the end of May this year, compared to 236 in June 2021 before Didi was put under a cybersecurity investigation, according to data from China&#39;s Ministry of Transport.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A growing number of Chinese cities – including Dongguan and Zhuhai in southern Guangdong province, Wenzhou in eastern Zhejiang province, Jinan in eastern Shandong province and Sanya in southern Hainan province – have issued a raft of notices in April and May that state how their ride-hailing markets are either saturated or would soon be in such a state.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China reduces penalties imposed on a range of ride-hailing violations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The local transport agency in Sanya, for example, has stopped issuing permits to new drivers since May 5, citing the “nearly saturated capacity after the rapid increase of ride-hailing platforms and cars in recent years”. Ride-hailing platforms also faced a deluge of new drivers, as the country&#39;s macroeconomic environment weakened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China had 5.1 million registered online taxi drivers at the end of last year, up 76 per cent from 2.9 million in 2020, according to the country&#39;s transport ministry. By contrast, the number of ride-hailing passengers grew just 20 per cent in the same span to 437 million last year from 365 million in 2020, according to the China Internet Network Information Centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Didi driver in Beijing surnamed Zhang, who joined the platform in March after being laid off four months earlier, said his daily orders and pay have steadily declined.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are just lots of people like me who started driving Didi after losing jobs in the last two years, making it hard for especially new [Didi] drivers to get enough orders,” said Zhang, who is in his late 20s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jobless rate for people aged 16 to 24 notched another record high of 20.8 per cent in May, according to the latest data released by the National Bureau of Statistics. Meanwhile, nearly 11.6 million college graduates are set to enter the workforce later this year. The country&#39;s overall unemployment rate remains unchanged at 5.2 per cent.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China and Thailand launch air combat drills as Beijing shores up military ties in Southeast Asia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3227189/china-and-thailand-launch-air-combat-drills-beijing-shores-military-ties-southeast-asia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 18:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/1402b5f3-3031-4485-b46b-f570398610eb_bef191da.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;An annual joint air combat exercise between China and Thailand opened on Sunday to “strengthen military cooperation between the two countries and maintain regional peace and stability”, the state-run Xinhua news agency reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s defence ministry said Chinese fighter jets, bombers, airborne early warning aircraft and ground-to-air missile installations would take part in the drills in Thailand, known as “Falcon Strike 2023”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xinhua added that the two countries&#39; air forces would conduct training on joint air defence, air support and large-scale deployments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An opening ceremony for the exercises was held on Sunday at Udorn Royal Thai Air Force Base located about 30km (19 miles) from Bangkok and less than 50km (31 miles) from the Gulf of Thailand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The annual drill was first held in 2015. Last year, China sent its JH-7A fighter bomber, Shaanxi KJ-500 early warning and control aircraft, and six Chengdu J-10 C/S fighters – the most advanced line-up in the exercise&#39;s history.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China and Thailand to expand military ties amid &#39;security challenges&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The joint training adheres to the principles of mutual benefit and the standard of real and practical combat training, which will further improve the training level of China and Thailand&#39;s air forces,” said Chen Jun, commander of the Chinese troops, according to Xinhua.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Boripat Ratchaneepun, an officer with the Thai air force&#39;s directorate of operations, added that the drill would enhance “mutual trust and friendship” between the Thai and Chinese air forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has been shoring up its military ties with Southeast Asian countries this year as Beijing and Washington bolster their military presence in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China held its first naval drills with ally Cambodia in March and conducted exercises with Singapore and Laos in May. It also took part in Indonesian military exercises off the coast of Makassar in South Sulawesi, along with the US and other forces, in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US, meanwhile, conducted several drills with regional allies such as Japan, South Korea, India, Indonesia and the Philippines in the first half of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore last month, Chinese Defence Minister General Li Shangfu declined Washington&#39;s request for a formal meeting with his US counterpart Lloyd Austin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thai Prime Minister Prayuth Chan-ocha has maintained close ties with Chinese President Xi Jinping in various fields, including security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thailand was among the few countries Xi visited last year before China abandoned its zero-Covid policy and reopened its borders. During Xi&#39;s visit to Bangkok last November, Prayuth agreed to explore cooperation under China&#39;s Global Security Initiative (GSI) to “address traditional and non-traditional security challenges”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China was Thailand&#39;s largest trading partner in 2022, with a bilateral trade value of 3.69 trillion baht (US$104.7 billion), accounting for about 18 per cent of Thailand&#39;s total foreign trade volume, according to China&#39;s Ministry of Commerce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thailand will begin the first round of voting to select its next prime minister on Thursday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mystery of headless man found in Japanese love hotel, police seek small person wearing wide-brimmed hat]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3227184/mystery-headless-man-found-japanese-love-hotel-police-seek-small-person-wearing-wide-brimmed-hat?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 17:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/3d0ccb8d-1d04-498a-8439-2b63f6399d8e_687e52a5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A man&#39;s headless body was found in a love hotel in Japan. He was last seen alive while entering the building with a person dressed in women&#39;s clothing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man, identified by police as Hitoshi Ura, was found dead in a love hotel on July 2, according to local newspaper The Japan Times. The incident occurred in Sapporo, on the northern Japanese island of Hokkaido.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Sunday, near the love hotel, police officers approached pedestrians in search of evidence that could lead to the arrest of the perpetrator, according to the Japanese newspaper The Asahi newspaper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ura, 64, was seen entering the hotel with another person at 10.50pm on July 1, the receptionist told police, according to The Asahi newspaper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some three hours later, the receptionist was told that the person would be leaving the hotel first and that Ura would be left alone in the room, per The Asahi newspaper. The report did not state if Ura was the one who informed the receptionist.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan&#39;s Hokkaido issues urgent bear alert after fisherman decapitated&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The following day, police found Ura naked in the bathroom of a guest room, where he was said to have been decapitated, The Japan Times reported, citing investigators. Police said the cause of death was haemorrhagic shock, per the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to The Asahi newspaper, the person who accompanied Ura into the love hotel was small in size. The person was seen wearing a wide-brimmed black hat, dark clothing, and carrying a large suitcase.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police noted that Ura&#39;s mobile phone and personal belongings were missing, per the report. On July 4, his car was found in a car park.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The investigation is progressing. We are trying to gather as much information as possible in the hope it will lead to the arrest of the perpetrator,” said Daiki Kanamori, a detective with the Sapporo Chuo Police Station, per The Asahi newspaper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Love hotels in Japan typically feature themed rooms and charge hourly rates. They are often used by couples looking for a discreet place to meet for sexual encounters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some 4,900 love hotels currently operate in Japan, per Statista. These hotels do not require guests who live in Japan to provide identification when checking in, according to the news agency Kyodo News.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deaths in love hotels in Japan are rare – but previous incidents have been reported. In 2021, a man and woman were found dead in a love hotel in Tokyo. Police reported the woman, who was in her 30s, had killed the man, who was in his 20s. She then killed herself.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2018, a 46-year-old man and a 16-year-old girl were found dead in a love hotel in Saitama, just outside Tokyo. Police said they killed themselves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Japan National Police did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Two-thirds of applicants get first choice of Hong Kong secondary school through central allocation system, Education Bureau says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3227176/two-thirds-applicants-get-first-choice-hong-kong-secondary-school-through-central-allocation-system?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 17:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/0e55f25a-68df-47a7-ba17-dee007b04920_542fd4d1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Two-thirds of applicants have been given their first choice of Hong Kong secondary through the central allocation system, a slight drop on last year, education authorities have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pupils will be told their result on Tuesday, but families who were disappointed might find it more difficult this year to approach their preferred schools – known as “door-knocking” – after the Education Bureau announced last week it would reduce the number of places available because of falling school rolls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Education Bureau on Monday said 50,508 Primary Six children, 1,060 more than last year, joined the secondary school places allocation system for the next academic year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pupils were allocated places at secondary schools in two stages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Youngsters in the first group were granted school places based on discretionary factors, such as academic and interview performance. Pupils could apply direct to any two schools in this phase and the results were released in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Children who failed to secure a place at the discretionary stage were placed in the computer-based central allocation system, where they could pick up to 30 schools in their “school net” – catchment areas – based on their home addresses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 66 per cent per cent of pupils got their first pick through the central allocation system, down on last year&#39;s record high of 71 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eighty per cent of pupils either received offers at the discretionary stage or their top pick in the central allocation, down from 83 per cent last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 91 per cent of 12-year-olds were allocated one of their two discretionary place choices or one of their top three picks by central allocation, down from last year&#39;s figure of 94 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong schools told to halve number of &#39;door-knocking&#39; spots for Secondary One classes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The bureau, confirming an earlier report by the Post, said last Wednesday that schools could only use one of the two places reserved by Secondary One classes for pupils who had to repeat a year to enrol children unhappy with their allocated schools.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After careful consideration and listening to the opinions of stakeholders, the Education Bureau decided that only one repeater quota in each Secondary One class can be used to admit non-repeaters starting from the 2023-24 school year,” schools were told last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bureau added that the new policy ensured the places would be used for their original purpose.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Schools agreed the reduction in door-knocking places would help to prevent a “musical chair effect” where pupils switched schools, which could threaten the survival of some education institutions because of the decline in the pupil population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bureau said all pupils who took part in the central allocation process should visit their primary schools on Tuesday to collect allocation and admission slips for secondary education.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong authorities plan to cut &#39;door-knocking&#39; places to help unpopular schools&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Parents will also be notified by SMS messages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Education officials added the registration period for secondary schools would be held on Thursday and Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chu Kwok-keung, the principal of a school near the border and a lawmaker for the education constituency, said the return of pupils from mainland China after all travel restrictions were dropped in February was one of the reasons for pushing down the rate of top choice successes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After the pandemic, some students across the borders applied for Primary Six in the North district”, he explained. “As I know, more than 200 Primary Six students in our districts were allocated their secondary school places in Kowloon due to keen competition, and the number is more than last year.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chu added another reason for the rate coming down was more parents and pupils being aggressive in their choice of traditionally popular schools as they may have thought the emigration wave meant there would be less competition.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Crossing between Hong Kong, mainland China partially closed over cracked roads; truck drivers heading north face 1-hour travel delay]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3227164/crossing-between-hong-kong-mainland-china-partially-closed-over-cracked-roads-truck-drivers-heading?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/735af950-808d-425b-a457-c1c541acd34f_b3140dad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Truck drivers heading from Hong Kong to mainland China faced an extra hour of travel on Monday, a day after the Man Kam To border crossing was partially closed due to an “emergency situation” caused by a rare land subsidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Photos from Sunday showed the roads had cracked and debris spread across three of the crossing&#39;s northbound lanes. The surface in front of three booths had also sunk, causing the roofs of two to break.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A video also revealed a water leakage at a vehicle checkpoint.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But a member of Hong Kong&#39;s transport sector on Monday said the checkpoint&#39;s closure would have little impact on drivers, since only northbound traffic had been affected and the delay was between 20 minutes and one hour.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Scores of Hong Kong drivers cross border for road trips under new travel scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Local educators said the incident would not affect cross-border pupils since the summer break was approaching.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Container Transportation Employees General Union chairman Chan Dik-sau said cross-border truck drivers had switched to using the Heung Yuen Wai crossing, about a 20-minute drive from the Man Kam To checkpoint.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The border checkpoint had congested traffic on Monday morning. Drivers will need an extra hour to complete their trip to the mainland,” he said. “The incident has not affected the fresh food supply from the mainland to Hong Kong … Drivers can still complete their jobs within the day.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Transport Department described the incident as an “emergency situation” and said cross-border coaches travelling north would be diverted to the Heung Yuen Wai control point. It also revised the wait time between buses from 30 minutes to about 45 minutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chu Wai-lam, principal of Fung Kai No 1 Primary School, said the incident would have no effect on cross-border students since Monday was a school holiday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only students from certain years would need to return to campus before summer break started, including Primary Six pupils who would get their secondary school allocation results on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As the incident does not affect southbound travel, students can still take school buses and other public transport to school,” Chu said. “But they will need extra time to head back home. Normally it only takes 10 minutes to arrive at the checkpoint, but they will need 20 to 30 minutes to go to another checkpoint.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What Hongkongers need to know about driving into mainland China under new scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The principal added that he hoped the northbound lanes roads could be fixed during the summer holiday to reduce the impact on pupils crossing the border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Office of Port of Entry and Exit of Shenzhen Municipal People&#39;s Government on Sunday night said the land subsidence happened at around 6pm, prompting authorities to halt cross-border services for tourists and trucks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The date for resuming services would be announced once repairs were completed, it added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s newly appointed Cardinal Stephen Chow says elevation has given him ‘new mission’, calls for greater reconciliation in city]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3227172/hong-kongs-newly-appointed-cardinal-stephen-chow-says-elevation-has-given-him-new-mission-calls?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 17:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/bd447406-90ca-4b4a-9f34-c4d6cc82ea68_86609919.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s newly appointed Cardinal Stephen Chow Sau-yan has said the elevation has given him a “new mission” and called for greater reconciliation in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chow, who remains a Catholic bishop pending his appointment by the papacy at the end of September, said he felt a sense of responsibility with his new role.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It feels like this is a mission given to me by God through the Pope,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chow, widely seen as politically neutral, also highlighted the importance of healing divisions in society.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think Hong Kong should have more reconciliation, so Hong Kong people can have a chance to take a break, reconcile and calm down. This is what I hope to do,” he said. “This will require the cooperation of many parties to happen.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked whether he would continue to call for lenient treatment of those involved in the 2019 anti-government protests, Chow said it was crucial to give young people hope, particularly those who had committed offences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 63-year-old was meeting the press since his elevation to cardinal was revealed by Pope Francis on Sunday during his weekly public appearance at St Peter&#39;s Square in Rome.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong Bishop Stephen Chow appointed to College of Cardinals by Pope Francis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He will be the fourth cardinal from Hong Kong, following the late John Baptist Wu Cheng-chung, 91-year-old Joseph Zen Ze-kiun and 83-year-old John Tong Hon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pontiff appointed Chow bishop of the Catholic diocese of Hong Kong two years ago, making him one of the youngest to hold the position since the first Chinese prelate was appointed in 1969, following the death of Michael Yeung Ming-cheung in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chow paid a five-day visit to Beijing in April after being invited by Bishop Joseph Li Shan of the Beijing diocese, marking the first time a senior Catholic clergyman from Hong Kong had visited the capital since the handover from British to Chinese rule in 1997.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s Cardinal Zen given private audience with Pope Francis in Vatican&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said at the time the visit underlined the mission of the Hong Kong church to act as a bridge and promote exchanges between the faithful on the two sides.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bishop also called for closer ties between the city&#39;s diocese and churches and their counterparts in mainland China.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong accountant swindled out of HK$1 million in digital Tether coins in bogus cryptocurrency deal]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3227158/hong-kong-accountant-swindled-out-hk1-million-digital-tether-coins-bogus-cryptocurrency-deal?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/6429cab8-ab6d-40d4-9d0a-09ad9adfe42f_3a7f5a81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong police are hunting fraudsters who swindled an accountant out of HK$1 million in digital money in a bogus cryptocurrency deal at a Tsim Sha Tsui shop.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Detectives are investigating whether the fraud syndicate set up the shop in the basement of Chevalier House on Chatham Road South to cheat the woman, 29.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The accountant saw an Instagram post about trading digital coins at a higher exchange rate with contact details provided, a source familiar with the case said on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong, mainland police arrest 17 in connection with 149 online fraud cases&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;She wanted to sell Tether digital coins and contacted a fraudster who posed as a shop employee. She was asked to visit the shop to carry out the transaction on Sunday night.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“During the meeting in the shop, a scammer posing as a staff member put a bundle of HK$1,000 banknotes on the counter for payment of the transaction,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the woman transferred 128,040 Tether coins as instructed to a designated e-wallet account in exchange for HK$1 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After she completed the transfer, the &#39;employee&#39; asked the victim to wait outside the shop because he needed to go to the toilet,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She realised she had been conned when the man failed to return and she was unable to contact him. She then called police at about 10pm on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong accountant loses HK$27 million amid surge in investment scams&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The “banknotes” were left on the counter, another source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Except for two genuine banknotes on the top and bottom of the bundle, the others were bogus bills,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bills, known as training notes, look genuine aside from three Chinese characters for “practice coupon” printed on them. They bear no security features such as a watermark and are said to be used by mainland Chinese bank staff for training and counting practice.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong retiree loses HK$7 million in cryptocurrency investment scam&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Officers combed the area, but no arrests were made. Police also pored over security camera footage to gather evidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police have classified the case as deception. Detectives from the Yau Tsim criminal investigation unit are handling the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 4 last year, a cryptocurrency trader was lured into transferring HK$1.5 million in digital money in a bogus transaction in a Nathan Road shop in Tsim Sha Tsui.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police arrest 19 in crackdown on money laundering syndicate&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The 30-year-old trader and two colleagues met a man posing as a buyer to make a deal inside the shop&#39;s meeting room.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As instructed, the victim transferred HK$1.5 million in digital money into a designated e-wallet. The “buyer” claimed he needed to go to the staff room to get money and exited the meeting. Instead, the man left the shop via the rear exit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The victim and her colleagues realised it was a scam when the “buyer” did not return and the trio found they had been locked in the room. They then called police.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong architect cheated out of HK$24.5 million in crypto investment scam&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;An investigation found that a shell company had rented the shop a month earlier, according to the force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In August last year, a businessman transferred about HK$1.58 million in digital money in exchange for two bundles of fake banknotes in a bogus cryptocurrency transaction in a Hung Hom office that had been rented by a fraud syndicate in July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Between January and March this year, police handled 8,886 reports of deception, up 65 per cent from 5,378 cases logged in the same period last year.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Auckland’s bold housing reforms an example for Australia’s unaffordable market]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/article/3227121/aucklands-bold-housing-reforms-example-australias-unaffordable-market?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/2b904e1d-cf59-4832-bb17-ab9b6d8e6de4_c10d2762.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;At first glance, Australia&#39;s housing market is performing significantly better than New Zealand&#39;s. Both countries&#39; central banks have been among the most hawkish in advanced economies, raising interest rates aggressively to tame inflation at the cost of inducing a recession.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This makes the sudden recovery in Australian house prices this year all the more striking. Since bottoming out in February, home values have risen 3.4 per cent, reducing the peak-to-trough decline to just 5.7 per cent. In Sydney, the largest and most expensive market, prices have shot up 6.7 per cent, according to CoreLogic data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In New Zealand, by contrast, house prices have yet to find a floor, having fallen for 15 straight months. Last month, they fell at their sharpest pace in eight months, taking the decline in the past year to 10.6 per cent. In Auckland, the country&#39;s largest city, prices have plunged 16.8 per cent since their peak, more than twice the peak-to-trough decline in Sydney, according to CoreLogic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet, while Australia&#39;s housing market has proved more resilient, the rebound in prices has only served to heighten concerns about the deterioration in affordability.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the main reasons for the short downturn is the lack of supply. Last month, new listings in the capital cities were 10 per cent below their previous five-year average while inventory levels were more than a quarter below the average for this time of year, according to CoreLogic data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Supply constraints are particularly acute in the rental market, where the steep rise in interest rates has dampened demand for purchases of properties for investment purposes. In April, there were just under 92,000 rental listings nationwide, down from more than 180,000 at the start of the pandemic and 38 per cent below the average level for the previous decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia&#39;s housing crisis a blessing and a curse for build-to-rent sector&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The rapid pace at which demand – which is being fuelled by the surge in net overseas migration – has outstripped supply has driven up rents sharply, especially for flats. Rents in the capital cities increased 16.2 per cent in the past year, and by as much as 18.8 per cent in Sydney. The upwards pressure on rental prices is mainly attributable to the persistent undersupply of medium-to-high-density housing, a key factor behind the decline in the stock of social housing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unfortunately, the deterioration in rental affordability, particularly for lower income households, has become deeply politicised. Last month, opposition parties delayed legislative approval of the ruling Labor Party&#39;s signature A$10 billion (US$6.7 billion) social and affordable housing fund, mainly because of the Green Party&#39;s insistence on the imposition of a two-year nationwide freeze on rents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rent controls would only make matters worse by disincentivising investment, thereby reducing the supply of rental accommodation even further. Yet, the political divisions over Australian housing policy have sharpened the focus on delays and inefficiencies in the planning system, which are at the root of the country&#39;s housing crisis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this context, the bold zoning reforms introduced by Auckland&#39;s government, designed to encourage the development of medium-density housing, is eye-catching. A uniform set of land use rules known as the Auckland Unitary Plan (AUP) in 2016 led to the upzoning of much of the city&#39;s residential land, ushering in a residential construction boom that spared the city from the dramatic rise in rents and prices in the rest of the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Research undertaken by Ryan Greenaway-McGrevy of the University of Auckland revealed that the liberalisation of the city&#39;s zoning laws not only led to a surge in building in upzoned areas, it shifted the focus of construction to attached multifamily housing – as opposed to single-family detached homes – in established suburbs well-served by public infrastructure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The findings of a paper published by Greenaway-McGrevy in May also showed that the reforms improved rental affordability, with rents for two- and three-bedroom dwellings currently 14 to 35 per cent lower than they would have been in the absence of changes to the planning system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The AUP helped lay the groundwork for a cross-party consensus in New Zealand on housing reform. In October 2021, the Labour government and the opposition National Party joined forces to pass legislation on overhauling planning laws to encourage medium-density housing in all major cities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although New Zealand&#39;s rental market remains tight, rents are growing at an annual pace of roughly 4 per cent, a much slower rate than in Australia. Nick Goodall, head of research at CoreLogic New Zealand, said rental gains were more in line with “household incomes rather than landlords&#39; costs”. Still, despite the progress made in boosting supply, particularly in Auckland, it has been “very difficult to undo the damage stemming from years of undersupply,” Goodall said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Kiwis are behind New Zealand&#39;s runaway house prices, not foreign buyers from China or Singapore&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;This is all the more reason for Australia to embrace Auckland-style planning reforms as soon as possible. The Grattan Institute in Melbourne notes that Australia is one of only a handful of countries among advanced economies in which housing stock per capita has stagnated during the past two decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a submission to the upper house of parliament in the state of Victoria this month on ways to tackle the housing crisis, the Grattan Institute urged Victoria&#39;s government to liberalise its planning laws by permitting more medium-density housing in existing suburbs. “No state government in Australia has been as bold as Auckland has,” said Joey Moloney, senior associate at the Grattan Institute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This requires a major shift in urban planning and development and, crucially, the political will to take on the nimby crowd who have so far succeeded in stymieing medium-to-high-density housing schemes in popular suburbs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even in New Zealand, the cross-party consensus on housing is crumbling ahead of a parliamentary election in October. This makes Auckland&#39;s planning reforms look even bolder. Australian cities would do well to follow suit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blackpink, Barbie and Beijing’s South China Sea claims collide in Vietnam]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227132/blackpink-barbie-and-beijings-south-china-sea-claims-collide-vietnam?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/fabb2783-21c6-4d46-b835-ed859c0343ea_d1413260.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;First it was a scribbled map in the Warner Bros&#39; Barbie film, now Blackpink are facing the ire of Vietnamese nationalists calling for a boycott of the K-pop supergroup&#39;s coming tour dates in Hanoi, as pop culture increasingly takes collateral damage from geopolitics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eagle-eyed social media users noticed last week that the website of iMe Entertainment, the Chinese company organising the Blackpink concerts in Vietnam slated for July 29 and 30, featured a map showing Beijing&#39;s controversial “nine-dash line” claim in the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The line, depicting China&#39;s territorial claims over much of the disputed waterway, has become a lightning rod for anger from other countries – most notably Vietnam and the Philippines – that hotly dispute it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The issue often provokes outrage, especially among Vietnam&#39;s nationalists – as the Blackpink concert organisers are finding out the hard way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Get the f*** out of our country … we don&#39;t need a show that doesn&#39;t respect the sovereignty of the sea and islands. Please get out of Vietnam,” said one person in the comments on Blackpink&#39;s official Facebook announcement of their Hanoi visit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Stop spreading the illegal map,” said another, while a third user commented: “I also heard that [the organising] company is Chinese and is supporting Vietnamese enemies … I intended to save money to go to the concert but now I&#39;m not going any more.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 2016 United Nations-backed arbitral tribunal in The Hague repudiated Beijing&#39;s nine-dash line claim as having no legal basis. China rejected the ruling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hanoi has a long, contentious history with Beijing in this area, largely focused on the Spratly, or Truong Sa in Vietnam, and Paracel, or Hoang Sa, archipelagos.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Blackpink&#39;s Vietnam concert dates in hot water over South China Sea map&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In 1988 the two sides fought a brief naval skirmish over part of the Spratly Islands, with Vietnam losing 64 soldiers and control of several reefs and atolls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the years since, the Vietnamese government has emerged as one of the sharpest critics of China&#39;s activities in the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pham Thu Hang, spokeswoman for Vietnam&#39;s foreign ministry, called the map on promoter iMe&#39;s website “unacceptable” and a “hot button issue”. “The promotion and usage of products or publications featuring the nine-dash line in Vietnam is in violation of the laws,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The iMe website has been down for maintenance since the issue surfaced. On Thursday, a day before tickets were due to go on sale, Brian Chow, CEO of iME, apologised for the “unfortunate misunderstanding”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The image of the map on the website does not represent the territory of any country and we are aware of respecting the sovereignty and culture of all the countries” where iME has a presence, he said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“iME quickly reviewed and committed to replace the images that are not suitable for Vietnamese,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The outcry has put the Vietnamese government in a tough spot, as it is adamant about the country&#39;s sovereignty over the Paracel and Spratly islands but has close economic and political ties to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the iMe controversy began, tourism officials were playing up the potential positive impact of Blackpink&#39;s concerts – especially for a country that rarely hosts major international music stars – while a comment reading “WELCOME TO VIETNAM” with several celebratory emojis was left on the K-pop group&#39;s Facebook page by the government&#39;s official account.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China, Vietnam pledge to work together on South China Sea &#39;code of conduct&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;By July 5, however, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture had ordered an inspection of iMe&#39;s website to verify the presence of the nine-dash line.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But there has been no indication of a boycott, yet. Tickets for the concerts went on sale on Friday as scheduled, with more than 122,000 people joining the digital queue within minutes. By midday on Sunday, many ticket categories were already sold out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Barbie movie was not so fortunate. Vietnam&#39;s National Council for Film Appraisal and Classification banned the film on July 3 “for scenes depicting China&#39;s nine-dash line”. The star-studded blockbuster was scheduled for release on July 21, but cinema chains quickly removed it from their “coming soon” pages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The film has come under fire in the Philippines as well, with one senator calling for a disclaimer saying that the nine-dash line is “fiction” to be included before screenings. Manila&#39;s Movie and Television Review and Classification Board is currently looking into the matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Hanoi has been widely ridiculed for reacting so strongly to a movie like Barbie, Nguyen Khac Giang, a researcher of Vietnamese politics at the ISEAS – Yusof Ishak Institute in Singapore, said the response was understandable as Vietnam battles China&#39;s geopolitical narrative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Exposure to the line may not make people support China&#39;s disputed claim, but it makes them aware of it,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is not the first time such a thing has happened in a Hollywood movie,” Nguyen said, adding its “presence is not just annoying, but it is believed by Hanoi to be part of a carefully crafted plan by China to establish a narrative and create a perception of legitimacy”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ban was well-received in Vietnam, where people called out Warner Brothers, the main studio behind Barbie, for “pandering” to China&#39;s Communist Party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The studio, for its part, released a statement saying “The map in Barbie Land is a whimsical, childlike crayon drawing. The doodles depict Barbie&#39;s make-believe journey from Barbie Land to the real world. It was not intended to make any type of statement.” Vietnam responded by saying it would uphold the ban.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official Barbie Vietnam Facebook page, with 89,000 followers, posted: “We love Barbie, but we love our country above all. We do not support any action violating our territorial sovereignty.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vietnam&#39;s government has a storied history of combating pop culture deemed to offend national sensibilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It banned the animated movie and the Tom Holland-led Uncharted in March last year for including depictions of the nine-dash line – a similar image was cut from a scene in 2018&#39;s Crazy Rich Asians.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Vietnam bans Barbie movie for showing Beijing&#39;s South China Sea claims&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But the vocal nature of social media users in response to both Barbie and Blackpink is relatively new.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think Vietnamese public sentiment has not significantly changed over the years, but it has been reinforced by the rise of social media and China&#39;s increasingly aggressive activities in the South China Sea,” Giang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He ultimately believes Vietnam – and the Philippines – made the right decision in taking a stand against depictions of the line in popular culture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From the perspective of Hanoi and Manila, there is no dispute – you can&#39;t simply draw arbitrary lines over a vast expanse of sea and claim it as yours,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a sign that the battle is far from over, Vietnamese authorities on Monday gave Netflix 24 hours to remove Chinese television show Flight to You from its platform in the country for featuring the nine-dash line in various scenes in a number of episodes. In June 2021, the streaming service pulled the Australian show from its Vietnam offerings for similar reasons.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>