<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link>https://www.scmp.com</link><item><title><![CDATA[16 injured in collision between 2 buses on Hong Kong’s Lantau Island]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3227259/16-injured-collision-between-2-buses-hong-kongs-lantau-island?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 12:22&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/eda96213-1a8f-4deb-a8a9-fdf585fb1e21_6800a46b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sixteen people were injured in a collision between two buses at a public transport terminus on one of Hong Kong’s outlying islands on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seven fire engines and 11 ambulances were deployed soon after 10.30am when the Fire Services Department received a report of multiple casualties at Yat Tung Estate in Tung Chung, on Lantau Island.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the department, the collision involved a single-deck bus and a double decker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its spokesman said 16 people – two men and 14 women – were injured in the incident and most suffered minor injuries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said seven of the injured were sent to Princess Margaret Hospital and the other nine were rushed to North Lantau Hospital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Bus driver trapped, passengers stranded in Hong Kong tunnel after crash with crane&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officers from the New Territories South traffic unit are investigating the cause of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Passengers describe horror as Hong Kong double-decker crashes, tilts&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between January and May this year, 49 road deaths were recorded and 332 people suffered serious injuries in traffic accidents across the city. During the whole of last year, 90 people died in 89 fatal crashes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Europe seals data transfer pact with US limiting access by intelligence services, but a new legal challenge is expected]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3227261/europe-seals-data-transfer-pact-us-limiting-access-intelligence-services-new-legal-challenge?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 12:35&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/e259b844-680a-41b7-9f72-f1bf17653ebc_e8909188.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Commission announced a new data transfer pact with the United States on Monday, seeking to end the legal uncertainty plaguing thousands of companies that transfer personal data across the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move was immediately criticised by non-profit group noyb, led by privacy activist Max Schrems, which said it would challenge the agreement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The commission and the United States had been struggling to reach a new agreement after Europe’s top court annulled two previous pacts that underpinned the transfer of personal data across the Atlantic for services ranging from cloud infrastructure to payroll and banking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Hong Kong and mainland agree to cross-border data deal after new rules in China&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The commission, the EU’s executive arm, said measures taken by the United States ensured an adequate level of protection for Europeans’ personal data transferred across the Atlantic for commercial use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It said new binding safeguards, such as limiting US intelligence services’ access to EU data to what is “necessary and proportionate” and the establishment of a Data Protection Review Court for Europeans, address the concerns raised by Europe’s top court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;US President Joe Biden welcomed the data transfer pact and said it reflected a “joint commitment to strong data privacy protections”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EU justice chief Didier Reynders said he was confident of fending off any legal challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The principles of the data privacy framework are solid, and I am convinced that we have made significant progress which meets the requirements of the European Court of Justice case law,” he told a news conference. “I am very confident of fighting, defending the new data agreement.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Schrems said the latest revision was inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Just announcing that something is ‘new’, ‘robust’ or ‘effective’ does not cut it before the Court of Justice. We would need changes in US surveillance law to make this work,” he said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We have various options for a challenge already in the drawer, although we are sick and tired of this legal ping-pong. We currently expect this to be back at the Court of Justice by the beginning of next year,” Schrems added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lobbying group DigitalEurope, whose members include Airbus, Amazon, Apple, Ericsson, Nokia, Philips and Samsung, welcomed the deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Data flows underpin the EU’s annual 1 trillion euros of service exports to the United States, and this decision will give companies more confidence to conduct business and help our economies to grow,” its director general, Cecilia Bonefeld-Dahl, said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the EU’s privacy watchdog, the European Data Protection Board, said the latest data agreement still fell short and urged the commission to do more to protect Europeans’ privacy rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Europe’s top court scuppered the previous two deals after challenges by Schrems because of concerns about US intelligence agencies’ accessing European citizens’ private data.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wagner will keep part of its African empire after Russian mutiny]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3227262/wagner-will-keep-part-its-african-empire-after-russian-mutiny?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 12:38&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/3ca31206-bedd-4a65-aa09-482fc49b5bf9_71aac1d1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Kremlin is willing to let Yevgeny Prigozhin’s Wagner Group keep some of its extensive operations in Africa, according to two people with knowledge of the discussions, as Russia scrambles to retain its influence in the resource-rich continent in the aftermath of his attempted mutiny.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The deal includes Wagner’s operations in the Central African Republic and has the support of President Vladimir Putin, one of the people said, asking not to be identified because the matter is sensitive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The agreement emerged as the Kremlin disclosed Monday that Putin held nearly three hours of talks with Prigozhin and Wagner commanders on June 29, just five days after the unprecedented mutiny in Russia that threatened the president’s nearly quarter-century rule.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By building an army of thousands of guns-for-hire, Wagner has for years given the Kremlin a way to pursue its foreign policy in Africa on a shoestring, making inroads at the expense of the US and former colonial power France, with the added bonus of deniability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later this month, Russia will reinforce its engagement by hosting its second Africa summit in St Petersburg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what Russia describes as military instructors, the US says are Wagner operatives in combat roles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Russia’s top general shown in video, first time since Wagner mutiny&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Defence Ministry – bogged down in Ukraine and hampered by Western sanctions – isn’t immediately in a position to take over Wagner’s complex and often murky operations in CAR and may also need the private contractors to achieve its foreign policy objectives in Sudan and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond CAR, Putin was assessing his options but would likely end up leaving Wagner in charge of operations that pay for themselves while bringing activities more directly dependent on Moscow under its direct control, according to another person close to the Kremlin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Wagner will stay in Africa, that’s for sure,” said Sergei Markov, a political consultant with close Kremlin ties. “But whom it will report to, Prigozhin or another oligarch, has yet to be decided.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAR is one of three former French colonies that have strengthened security ties with Russia following disputes that led to the expulsion of French and international forces fighting jihadists in the Sahel region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it is Wagner forces that have helped the CAR government fight off a rebel insurgency since 2018. The US and others have accused them of involvement in massacres again Muslims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In return, Wagner-linked companies have been granted gold and timber concessions and run one of the country’s leading beer-makers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As many as 600 Wagner contractors have left CAR since the short-lived mutiny in Russia ended on June 25, Sky News reported in recent days, after refusing to switch to Russian Defence Ministry contracts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alexander Ivanov, the official representative of Russia’s military trainers in CAR, issued a statement Saturday saying they were there to stay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAR is confident that Russia will keep up its support, Hassan Bouba, the former rebel leader and influential Livestock Minister, said in a phone interview.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Russian TV shows Prigozhin’s ‘palace’ in move to discredit him&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moscow’s two key interlocutors in CAR are local Wagner commander Vitali Perfilev and Dmitri Sytyi, who runs the Russian House cultural centre. Both remain on the ground and hold daily meetings with the CAR army chief, said Bouba.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“They are the leaders in Bangui. For us, nothing has changed,” he told Bloomberg. “The last word resides with President Putin to say if the Central African Republic continues with Wagner or there will be new forces that will come and replace them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prigozhin’s main asset to African leaders was his access to Putin, which makes him less useful than he was, said a person in a Russian state company with knowledge of Africa operations who requested anonymity to talk about the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, his personal connections with those African leaders, and his men’s loyalty, mean he also won’t be easy to replace, said Marat Gabidullin, a former senior Wagner commander and Sergei Khrabrykh, an ex-Russian Defence Ministry official. Both now live in France.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mutiny, prompted by a row over the handling of Russia’s war in Ukraine, came as Wagner was busy expanding its African footprint. It has held talks with military rulers in Burkina Faso and sent a small contingent to the Democratic Republic of Congo to offer training and assistance to forces battling rebels, according to three people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wagner’s spreading influence on the continent was drawing US scrutiny – and sanctions – even before Prigozhin’s revolt. And the US has used the turmoil to step up calls on African leaders to expel the mercenaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We continue to urge governments in Africa and elsewhere to cease any cooperation with Wagner and not pursue any further,” State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Russia eyes Chechens and convicts to fill gaps left by Wagner&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next big question could be the future of Wagner operations in Sudan, where Prigozhin had been assisting rebels battling the army even while Moscow maintains close ties to the military leadership in Khartoum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US in May accused Wagner of delivering surface-to-air missiles to Sudan’s Rapid Support Forces, which since April have been waging a campaign to overthrow the military junta that seized power in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sudan is also a critical part of the logistical corridor that connects Wagner’s operations from Syria to Libya and deeper into Africa, allowing it to ferry equipment and fighters to countries including CAR and Mali.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Africa remains a high priority on the Russian foreign policy agenda and so far no sign of disruption is going on there. It could take time to untangle Wagner Group and replace it with something else,” said Lou Osborn, an analyst at All Eyes on Wagner, a consortium that tracks the group’s activities using open-source investigation. “It may not even happen.”&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s talent-strapped multinationals cast their line internationally to reel back ethnic Chinese]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3227264/chinas-talent-strapped-multinationals-cast-their-line-internationally-reel-back-ethnic-chinese?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 12:46&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/6b0f38de-1aa9-4671-81a8-8af2a7578dad_b1b776d5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talent-strapped corporations from China are looking to hire Chinese people overseas because those candidates are seen as more willing to relocate and likely to fit in, recruitment specialists have found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Chinese now in the US, a reservoir for higher education valued by companies in China, say they would not mind considering a move back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese employers have reached out overseas to fill positions, particularly in hi-tech, biotech and other economic pillars, international talent experts say, especially when the United States has intensified tech curbs amid a prolonged bilateral rivalry. Those hires come with top skills, native Chinese language ability, a shared culture and – in some cases – access to foreign business networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“They will definitely bring some expert Chinese to their positions for key roles, especially that of head engineer,” said Linda Yang, Greater China general manager for recruitment process outsourcing at the Los Angeles-based management consulting firm Korn Ferry. While hiring locally is preferred, she said, the next rung is to “hire local Chinese back”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;China needs process, time to heal economic scars: ex-finance chief Lou Jiwei&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Normally, hiring someone from abroad would take time, but a recruit who is originally from China or has parents who still live there could become a “push factor”, said Sean Li, China general manager with the British recruiting firm Robert Walters Group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is a big target for the agencies to look at,” Li said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Economic development in China has outpaced growth of the educational system while turnover trends high, together causing a talent void. Hong Kong, Taiwan, Singapore and other parts of Asia are also coming up short of local talent, mostly due to ageing populations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese companies are searching for top talent in generative artificial intelligence (AI) as the country now lacks such workers compared with the United States during a race to develop ChatGPT-style services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In smart manufacturing, job listings rose by about 54 per cent last year over 2021 on the Chinese recruitment platform Zhaopin.com. It says software engineering, electronics and automation experienced some of the worst shortages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among biopharmaceutical firms, an industry promotion group forecasts an annual talent shortage of more than 100,000 people in Shanghai alone, mostly in manufacturing and R&amp;D jobs, the state-run Shanghai Daily reported. Companies working in green energy and electric vehicles are scrambling to secure new people too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese employers have been recruiting from their diaspora offshore since at least last year to plug talent shortages, said Aiko Kikkawa, an economist with the Asian Development Bank in Metro Manila. She said those companies try to make their mark with good pay-benefit packages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Networking giant Huawei Technologies has spent US$150 million on finding talent overseas, a company spokeswoman said in June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ren Zhengfei, chief executive of the 207,000-employee firm, had said in 2021 that Huawei was targeting non-Chinese hires from overseas because the number of talented, foreign-educated Chinese students had declined, indicating that Chinese nationals had been the priority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Let us do our thing: US firms give China another shot – but there’s a new hurdle&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese companies have used the University of California campus in Berkeley to recruit students, and Chinese students are interested, said Ann Hsu, a university alumnus and advisory board member for the Berkeley China Summit, which is organised by a student group that also plans events for Chinese recruiters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That group, the Berkeley Chinese Students and Scholars Association, hosted a recruitment activity for the Chinese search engine Baidu in 2017, according to the Baidu Facebook page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overseas Chinese are most likely to consider working in China if they can handle “revolutionary projects” and jobs with “bigger scopes”, Li said. They would go for high salaries and attractive stock options “to an extent that it makes sense to just work there for three years”, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The search for “better career prospects” has brought an increasing number of Chinese students home after studying abroad – about 80 per cent of the total – state-run China Daily said last year. It said 1 million returned in 2021, up from 770,000 in 2020 and 580,300 in pre-pandemic 2019. Just 134,800 went back in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who stay overseas must vie with locals there for jobs and often race against work-visa deadlines. The US allows a grace period of one to two years after university graduation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some Chinese living abroad may still prefer their native environment, especially if they are stationed in the US and feel threatened by anti-Asian violence that made headlines in the US during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“So, this is happening. A lot of [students] are interested in going back to China to work,” said Hsu, who lives in San Francisco. “It’s the hard environment of the visas, and the soft environment of just [the US being] not so friendly any more toward China.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;San Francisco restaurateur George Chen said his uncle, the designer of a bilingual typing system, moved back to China after he was says he was denied a Southern California home purchase due to his race.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I think, as Chinese-Americans, we all have an ethnic pride,” said Chen, founder of the high-end Eight Tables eatery. He said fellow ethnic Chinese people whom he knows would consider China again “if the trade was friendly, and I could go and help and make good money, and have my children learn their mother tongue because they’re ethnic Chinese”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;‘More local talent’: China’s foreign firms try to replace expats in zero-Covid&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, some Chinese employers still prioritise local hires, because of their knowledge of the home front. And not all Chinese people overseas are fixated on returning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Returning graduates may be seen lacking the “localised knowledge needed to work in Chinese companies and ability to adapt to the local environment”, researchers with Australia-based Deakin University School of Education found in a 2021 study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Candidates with both a Chinese and international network “can be regarded as a marker of distinction in the home labour market”, the study says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shang Kaibo, 21, of Beijing, says it is too early for him to commit to returning home. He is on a summer programme at Berkeley and plans to finish his economics bachelor’s degree in France.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’ve never been to France, so it’s hard for me to say whether I’ll like it,” Shang said. But in China, he recalls, “young people struggle to find work”.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[South Koreans’ rejection of Japan’s Fukushima water release plan puts Yoon’s bid for improved Tokyo ties to the test]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227215/south-koreans-rejection-japans-fukushima-release-plan-puts-yoons-bid-improved-tokyo-ties-test?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 12:00&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/11f3bb10-8fdb-445c-a885-bb5efb933a13_aba698b7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;South Korea’s President Yoon Suk-yeol is walking a political tightrope, analysts say, as he attempts to calm growing public hostility over Japan’s plan to dump treated radioactive water into the sea while also trying to mend diplomatic ties with Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yoon has so far remained silent over the issue, which has become a political hot potato, but he will soon face the moment of truth when he meets Japan’s Prime Minister Fumio Kishida on the sidelines of a Nato summit in Lithuania this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kishida is expected to use the meeting – his second with Yoon in two months – to explain the safety of the planned release of the treated water from the wrecked Fukushima power plant and call for Seoul’s cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The government’s basic stance is that priority must be given to public health and safety. If Japan raises this issue, [Yoon’s] remarks will be made in accordance with this principle,” said a senior official in the presidential Blue House last week, asking not to be named.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within weeks, Japan is set to start releasing more than a million tons of treated radioactive water currently being stored at the crippled nuclear power plant north of Tokyo. Much of it had been used to cool the reactors that were destroyed by a 2011 earthquake and tsunami.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Japan has faced opposition to its plan, both at home and abroad, including from South Korea, despite assurances from the UN’s nuclear agency that the water is safe after being filtered to remove most isotopes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Yoon is caught up in a political dilemma between public oppositions against the discharge and his policy of improving ties with Japan,” said Yoon Sung-suk, a political-science professor at Chonnam University.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue had degenerated into a “political football” between rival parties ahead of next year’s crucial National Assembly elections, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What to know about Japan’s plan to release Fukushima waste water into the sea&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polls suggest eight out of 10 South Koreans oppose Japan’s water release plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Yoon will ask Prime Minister Kishida to take the South Korean people’s concerns over the health impact into consideration before discharging the contaminated water, but Japan would accept this request as a tacit approval for the release,” the academic said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Yoon and other analysts agreed the issue would remain a sticking point, as was the case with Seoul’s 2008 decision to allow beef imports from the United States despite widespread public concern over mad cow disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Months-long protests erupted across the country at the time, creating a serious political crisis for the administration of Lee Myung-bak, who later apologised and suspended the relaxing of beef import rules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Monday, a group of 15 protesters, including 11 opposition MPs and four fishermen’s representatives, flew to Tokyo for a three-day trip to take part in street marches and rallies outside the Japanese parliament and the prime minister’s residence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Polluting the ocean constitutes a crime against humanity,” fisherman Lee Taeyong, 53, told journalists before the flight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) on Tuesday last week said its two-year review had found Japan’s planned release of the water to be “consistent” with its safety standards, and that the treated water would have a “negligible” radiological impact on both people and the environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The South Korean government said it would “respect” the UN nuclear watchdog’s safety review results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The IAEA report eases the political burden on Yoon at a time when his government has been seeking to assuage public safety concerns,” said Choi Jin, head of the Institute of Presidential Leadership think tank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has done little to quell the anger, however. All 167 lawmakers of the opposition Democratic Party of Korea staged a 17-hour sit-in at parliament until early on Friday, the length of time the Fukushima nuclear reactors took to melt down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting the sit-in, the party’s leader Lee Jae-myung urged the government to call for a joint investigation with other countries in the Pacific to verify the safety of the discharge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s feared that the South Korean government’s endorsement of the IAEA report will fuel pressure on Seoul from Japan to remove its import ban on Fukushima seafood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But South Korea has ruled out the possibility of doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It is not a subject for discussion or review,” Park Ku-yeon, the first deputy chief of the Office for Government Policy Coordination, told journalists on Monday, noting that the president had repeatedly stressed the ban would remain in effect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Park Won-gon, a political-science professor at Ewha University, said President Yoon was unlikely to call for the water discharge to be delayed when he met Kishida, judging from the way Seoul had been handling the issue so far.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“And Seoul will stick to the import ban until all other countries in the region agree that Fukushima seafood is safe to consume,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div&gt;获取更多RSS：&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.net" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.net&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.best" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.best&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 12:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US Marine Corps in historic leadership limbo due to Republican block]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227255/us-marine-corps-historic-leadership-limbo-due-republican-block?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 12:02&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/ad2e438e-027c-4625-9d4a-3e08ed3e665c_a5d34565.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US Marine Corps is now without a Senate-confirmed leader for the first time in over a century thanks to a Republican senator’s block on military nominations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Retiring General David Berger formally relinquished command on Monday as the Marine Corps’ commandant, creating the first of several possible vacancies of Senate confirmed leaders on the US military’s Joint Chiefs of Staff in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Republican Senator Tommy Tuberville, who represents Alabama, has blocked hundreds of military nominations from moving forward because he believes the Pentagon is improperly using government funding to cover travel costs for abortions for service members and their dependents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin denounced the delay at Berger’s retirement ceremony, saying it was undermining readiness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Smooth and timely transitions of confirmed leadership are central to the defence of the United States,” Austin said, adding he expected the Senate to “meet its responsibilities”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pentagon spokesperson Sabrina Singh said last time the Marine Corps had an acting Commandant was from December 1, 1910 to February 2, 1911.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Join US military, become citizen: Uncle Sam urges legal migrants to sign up&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The longer these unprecedented holds remain, the greater risk the Department runs in experiencing knowledge and expertise gaps in certain critical and often difficult to fill positions,” Singh said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the US Supreme Court last year overturned the landmark 1973 Roe vs Wade ruling recognising a constitutional right to abortion, the Pentagon said it would cover travel costs for service members seeking abortions and up to 21 days off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several states have limited abortion access since Roe vs Wade was overturned, and the military argues that women service members cannot choose where they are stationed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Senate’s approval of military promotions is usually smooth. Tuberville’s hold cannot prevent the Democratic-majority Senate from voting on any promotion, but it can drastically slow down the process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More high-profile posts are expected to be vacated in the coming months, including the top general leading the US Army, the top admiral leading the US Navy and the next chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nominee to become chairman, Air Force General Charles “CQ” Brown, will field questions at his confirmation hearing on Tuesday before the Senate Armed Services Committee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Berger’s retirement leaves General Eric Smith, the Marine Corps’ No 2, also filling the role of “acting” commandant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He is President Joe Biden’s nominee to become the next commandant but is expected to avoid major decisions without Senate confirmation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional reporting by dpa&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 12:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong will ban ‘large number of prefectural sea products’ from Japan over Fukushima waste water discharge, John Lee warns]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3227256/hong-kong-will-ban-large-number-prefectural-sea-products-japan-over-fukushima-waste-water-discharge?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 12:09&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/d88af12f-3791-47e9-86cb-cf8beb338801_dc3b58a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong will ban “a large number of prefectural sea products” from Japan if the country proceeds with a controversial plan to discharge radioactive waste water into the sea, the city’s leader has warned while adding he is willing to “err on the side of caution”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu on Tuesday also vowed to take a “very serious” attitude in handling the matter to assure food safety in the city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee’s latest comments were centred on a Japanese plan to release treated radioactive waste water from the Fukushima nuclear plant disaster into the sea as early as August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would take an estimated 30 years to dispose of the 1.37 million tonnes of contaminated water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee called the scale of the planned discharge “unprecedented”, warning the risks were “very unknown” in other areas and that he would be “willing to err on the side of caution”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Hong Kong still wary of Japan radioactive water discharge plan, despite UN go-ahead&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I can tell you that the action we will take, if the exercise really starts, is that we will be banning a large number of prefectural sea products beyond the present scale,” Lee said on Tuesday ahead of his weekly meeting with key decision-making body the Executive Council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said the ban would “definitely go beyond” the current practice, in which five Japanese prefectures – Fukushima, Chiba, Gunma, Ibaraki and Tochigi – are only allowed to export certain food types to Hong Kong if they can provide radiation certificates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The city leader also noted that the side effects of consuming radioactive food would only surface several years later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It affects the present population. It will also affect the next generation, our children,” he stressed, highlighting the importance of assuring food safety in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The city’s catering and seafood industries earlier warned increased restrictions on food imports from Japan could lead to higher prices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Hongkongers to buy less Japanese food, avoid country over waste water plan: poll&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Responding to their concerns, Lee on Tuesday said the sector should understand the “forced” decision by the government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m sure that they will know safety is important. And they will know that public confidence in food safety is so important that it will affect the whole catering sector if we don’t handle it in a way that citizens will feel safe,” Lee argued.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Hong Kong team unveils cheap ‘artificial mussels’ to check for nuclear pollution&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mainland China last week announced plans to ban imports from 10 Japanese prefectures, including Fukushima, with all shipments from other regions of the country to be fully screened, instead of undergoing spot checks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Secretary for Environment and Ecology Tse Chin-wan last month warned that a potential ban on Japanese seafood imports could cover more than five prefectures already under restrictions. He added authorities would boost screening resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 12:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea repelled a US spy plane, Kim’s sister says, after threat to shoot them down]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3227249/north-korea-repelled-us-spy-plane-kims-sister-says-after-threat-shoot-them-down?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 11:33&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/8de86260-27da-43e0-91dc-3e24405d5d48_73bf7093.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;North Korea said it scrambled warplanes to ward off a US spy plane in its exclusive economic zone, after raising the possibility of “shocking” consequences if the incursions persist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kim Yo-jong, the powerful sister of leader Kim Jong-un, said early on Tuesday in a statement carried by the Korean Central News Agency that the US aircraft “retreated” when the North Korean air force sent up a sortie of planes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The intrusion into the DPRK’s 200-nautical mile economic water zone by the reconnaissance asset of the hostile country … is clearly a grave encroachment upon the sovereignty and security of the DPRK,” Kim said, referring to North Korea by its formal name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“A shocking incident would occur in the long run in the 20-40 section in which the US spy planes habitually intrude into the sky above the economic water zone” of North Korea, she added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her comments came hours after Pyongyang claimed US drones and spy planes flew for eight straight days along its coasts, with aircraft repeatedly violating its airspace. North Korea’s Defence Ministry accused the US of flying a strategic reconnaissance plane into its “inviolable airspace” several times and warned that approaching aircraft might be shot down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the Defence Ministry statement seemed to imply an intrusion into North Korean territorial airspace, Kim Yo-jong accused the US of conducting aerial surveillance over the North’s exclusive economic zone, the area within 200 nautical miles of its territory where it controls rights to natural resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;South Korea’s military disputed those accusations, saying the aerial reconnaissance aircraft did not violate North Korean airspace. It said Pyongyang had wilfully stirred tensions by launching threats over “normal flight activities” over international waters. It urged the North to immediately cease such actions. A spokesman for Seoul’s Joint Chiefs of Staff added that South Korean and US personnel are maintaining a readiness posture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kim Yo-jong also criticised South Korea for defending the US activities, using an abbreviation of the country’s official name. “As regards the provocation by the US forces, the military of the ‘ROK’ again impudently took the lead in denying the encroachment on the DPRK’s sovereignty, while shamelessly asserting that it was a ‘normal flight.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;North Korea threatens to shoot down US planes as it condemns nuclear moves&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The latest flare-up in tensions on the peninsula came as Nato leaders prepare to gather in Lithuania for their annual summit. The leaders of Japan, South Korea, Australia and New Zealand will also attend in a bid to bolster awareness of security threats in the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking at a forum in Seoul on Monday, John Weidner, chief of staff at US Forces Korea, reaffirmed Washington’s commitment to enhancing the “regular visibility” of powerful military assets in South Korea, referring to the “upcoming visit” of a US nuclear ballistic missile submarine, Yonhap reported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The US will enhance regular visibility of strategic assets to the Korean peninsula as evidenced by the upcoming visit of a US nuclear ballistic missile submarine to the ROK,” Weidner said, referring to South Korea by its formal name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In her statement early on, Kim Yo-jong reasserted that intensifying US reconnaissance activities were encroaching on the North’s sovereignty and that US forces would “experience a very critical flight” if they continue with their illegal intrusions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;North Korea vows ‘revenge’ against US in rallies marking war anniversary&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, tensions on the Korean peninsula rose sharply as the pace of North Korean weapon tests and US-South Korea joint military exercises have intensified. North Korea has test-fired nearly 100 missiles since the start of 2022 as Kim Jong-un expands a nuclear arsenal he apparently sees as his strongest guarantee of survival.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States stations about 28,500 troops in South Korea as deterrence against potential aggression by North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional reporting by Associated Press&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 11:50:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[TikTok crackdown bill in US faces changes after ByteDance’s US$100 million lobbying spending spree, senator says]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3227250/tiktok-crackdown-bill-us-faces-changes-after-bytedances-us100-million-lobbying-spending-spree?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 11:33&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/483eee4c-4356-404f-9f0c-77c3cf534db9_dcf904dc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;US lawmakers are considering changes to address concerns about a bill that would give the Biden administration new powers to ban Chinese-owned TikTok, the chair of the Senate Intelligence Committee who has cosponsored the legislation said on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Democratic Senator Mark Warner told Reuters that aggressive lobbying by the ByteDance-owned short video app TikTok against the Restrict Act “slowed a bit of our momentum” after it was introduced in March.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Warner said lawmakers have “a proposal on a series of amendments to make it explicitly clear” and address criticisms, including that individual Americans could be impacted or that the bill represents a broad expansion of government power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We can take care of those concerns in a fair way,” Warner said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;TikTok owner ByteDance is testing AI chatbot to challenge ChatGPT&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The legislation endorsed by the White House would grant the Commerce Department new authority to review, block, and address a range of transactions involving foreign information and communications technology that pose national security risks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I will grant TikTok this – they spent US$100 million in lobbying and slowed a bit of our momentum,” Warner said, adding that initially it seemed it would be almost “too easy” to get the bill approved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TikTok did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Warner’s assessment of its lobbying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March, Republican Senator Rand Paul blocked a bid to fast-track a separate bill to ban TikTok introduced by Senator Josh Hawley, who said the Restrict Act “doesn’t ban TikTok. It gives the president a whole bunch of new authority.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Biden administration in March demanded TikTok’s Chinese owners divest their stakes or face a US ban. Attempts in 2020 by then-president Donald Trump to ban TikTok were blocked by US courts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Warner said there are a lot of conversations about the bill, adding it could be attached to an annual defence bill or could be part of a China-related bill that Senate Democratic Leader Chuck Schumer wants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The need for legislation is clear, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There have been another three or four apps that have come out that are Chinese controlled so we need a fair rules-based process to deal with this rather than kind of a one-off basis,” Warner said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TikTok, which is used by more than 150 million Americans, says it has spent more than US$1.5 billion on rigorous data security efforts and rejects spying allegations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company is fighting a ban by the state of Montana set to take effect on January 1. A judge has scheduled an October 12 hearing on TikTok’s request.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Climate change: China ranks third behind Australia, Canada for readiness to boost output of metals critical for clean energy transition]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3227247/climate-change-china-ranks-third-behind-australia-canada-readiness-boost-output-metals-critical?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 10:57&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/c7bfc7e3-e060-40ed-bb80-cf3c3b168017_86ae7a81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China ranked third – after Australia and Canada – among 10 markets assessed on their readiness to boost the supply of metals essential to the global clean energy transition and the fight against climate change, according to a study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China scored 65 out of 100 in an assessment of countries’ preparedness to expand production of key minerals such as lithium, copper and graphite carried out by clean energy and commodity markets research provider BloombergNEF. That compares with Australia’s 92 and Canada’s 73.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study’s criteria included abundance of reserves, availability of talent and robustness of environmental impact assessment frameworks, each carrying a 25 per cent weighting. Sector strategy and political stability each accounted for 12.5 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“While the mining sector in China performs less well in terms of its ability to attract talent versus other industries, the country’s score is boosted by the availability of a wide range of mineral reserves,” said the report published on July 5.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China is the dominant producer of rare earths and graphite globally, and was the third-biggest miner of lithium last year, the report noted. It also owns around a third of global rare earths, a sixth of graphite and an eighth of lithium reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rare earth, found in the magnets of wind turbines, and cobalt, lithium, and graphite which are widely deployed in batteries, are ranked as having the biggest strategic value when it comes to energy transition in most economies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although China has the second-highest score, after Australia, for resource endowment, it trails in the areas of talent, sector development strategy and political stability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mining workers are paid just 2 per cent more than the average annual salary across all industries, the report noted, citing government statistics. That may not be enough to attract and retain skilled talent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While various provincial governments’ five-year plans for the mining sector have mentioned preferential treatment for critical minerals exploration, there were no specific funding or tax incentives, it added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other key mining players in the study were Brazil, Chile, Indonesia, South Africa, the United States, the European Union and the Democratic Republic of Congo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indonesia, which is rich in nickel resources with one fifth of global reserves, and Congo, which has nearly half of the world’s cobalt, ranked bottom for their readiness to boost supply, because of their insufficient skilled talent and “unstable and restrictive” policies that undermine investment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Globally, rising demand for the materials needed to produce climate mitigation equipment has prompted countries to find ways to boost supply and relieve bottlenecks, said the BloombergNEF report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Recognising their importance in the race to net-zero emissions, economies around the world are drafting critical minerals lists, along with strategies to raise supply,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Global electric cars sales are set to grow 35 per cent this year to 14 million units, accounting for 18 per cent of the overall car market, up from 4 per cent in 2020, the International Energy Agency forecast in April.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Installation of new wind farms may increase at an average annual rate of 15 per cent in the five years to 2027, according to a forecast by the Global Wind Energy Council. For this year, installations are tipped to grow by 47.4 per cent to 115 gigawatts (GW), just over half of that expansion in China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The growth will be driven by China’s efforts to bolster renewable energy, new incentives for clean energy projects in the US, and Europe’s drive to shore up energy security after it cut supply from Russia after the invasion of Ukraine, the industry body said in a report in March.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China is on track to reach Beijing’s target of doubling its solar and wind power capacity to 1,200GW by 2025, five years ahead of schedule, non-profit researcher Global Energy Monitor said last month.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Remembering Coco Lee: tearful tribute as Chinese farmer, 83, recalls how late Hong Kong star helped entire village sell 100,000 kilos of fruit in 2016]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3227157/remembering-coco-lee-tearful-tribute-chinese-farmer-83-recalls-how-late-hong-kong-star-helped-entire?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 11:00&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/6329cb26-e9e0-4a47-897c-3b45c551de3b_16c76e55.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The late pop diva Coco Lee helped an elderly farmer in central China to sell oranges so he could get home for Lunar New Year, prompting tears from 83-year-old Zhang Wanghan as he remembered her act of kindness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee’s death on July 5 at the age of 48 has prompted a massive outpouring of grief on mainland social media, with many recalling their encounters with the Hong Kong pop star.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’ve always remembered her kindness. I am grateful for her. Since I did not have her telephone number, I could not contact her to express my gratitude,” a tearful Zhang said, according to The Paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Li Xiaoyang, a volunteer with a public welfare NGO based in Hunan province, said Lee was appearing on a programme at a TV station in the provincial capital Changsha in January 2016 when she heard about an old man selling oranges on the cold, snowy street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The volunteers at Li’s organisation told Lee that Zhang was sleeping on the roadside when he wasn’t selling his fruit as he had nowhere to go in the city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the Lunar New Year holiday looming, he could not get back to his village – more than 400km (250 miles) east of Changsha – until he had sold all of the oranges, according to the report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Coco said she’d like to offer her help. As her flight was delayed that day, she asked her sister and mother to buy the oranges from the old farmer,” Li said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the help of the volunteers, Lee’s sister and mother found Zhang and bought 50kg (110lbs) of oranges from him. They also gave four boxes of health enhancing products, two quilted jackets and 2,000 yuan (US$280) in cash to the farmer and his wife.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The star shared the oranges with the other singers and staff on the television show but her generosity did not stop there, according to the report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When she heard that Zhang’s fellow villagers were all having difficulty selling their fruit, Lee then used her appearance on the programme to call on local residents to buy the produce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In just a few days, the entire village was out of stock, thanks to Lee’s appeal, Zhang said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story has received widespread attention on mainland social media and touched millions of people on the internet in just a few days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I cried. I think when this grandpa heard of the death of Coco, he would also feel heartache. Rest in peace, Coco!” one person said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“She is such a good-hearted girl. I hope she can be happy in another world and be kind to herself,” another wrote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“She is an all-round, highly-qualified idol. With good character, kindness, patriotic and beautiful songs. I am very sorry that we’ve lost her forever,” one comment read.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping, meeting Russian parliament leader, vows further Beijing-Moscow cooperation]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227242/xi-jinping-meeting-russian-parliament-leader-vows-further-beijing-moscow-cooperation?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 11:00&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/2c4aaf70-cdee-4ff8-b702-9b4d5989dcb1_006dbddd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China will continue to deepen its partnership with Russia, President Xi Jinping told the speaker of the Russian parliament’s upper house in Beijing on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“To develop China-Russia relations is a strategic choice made by both countries based on the fundamental interests of their respective countries and peoples,” Xi was quoted by state broadcaster CCTV as saying to Valentina Matviyenko, chairwoman of the Federation Council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Thanks to the joint efforts of the two sides, China-Russia relations have maintained a healthy and stable momentum of development. Cooperation in various fields has been steadily advancing, and the social and public opinion base of friendship between the two countries has become stronger for generations.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China is willing to continue to work with Russia to develop their comprehensive strategic partnership of cooperation, “to promote the building of a prosperous, stable, fair and just world”, Xi added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meeting with Matviyenko, Russia’s third-ranking official, came just after a visit by United States Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen, who met a host of senior Chinese finance officials in Beijing – but not Xi – in her four-day trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to a Reuters report, Russia’s Tass news agency quoted Matviyenko as saying that Russia would continue to cooperate with Beijing and could count on China’s “firm and reliable friendly shoulder”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matviyenko, council chairwoman since 2011, is Russia’s third-highest governmental official, behind only President Vladimir Putin and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s state media reports did not mention any discussions of the Ukraine war during the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;China and Russia seek to expand bloc as alternative to Western order: analysts&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matviyenko hailed the “highest level in history” of the Russia-China ties, saying that the Russian parliament widely supports the deepening of Russian-Chinese cooperation and is ready to further strengthen exchanges and dialogue with China’s National People’s Congress to provide legal guarantees for the implementation of the consensus of the two countries, CCTV reported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China has significantly upgraded ties with Russia in recent years – announcing a “no limit” partnership last year – as its relations with the US have deteriorated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xi recalled his visit to Moscow in March, saying he reached an important agreement with Putin on deepening a comprehensive strategic partnership and practical cooperation in various fields between the two countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xi told Matviyenko that the legislatures of both countries should make laws to promote “a sustainable and healthy development of cooperation”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He added that the two sides should also strengthen collaboration in multilateral organisations – such as the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) and the BRICS bloc – to lead the reform of global governance and safeguard the common interests of emerging markets and developing countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What’s on the table for Nato at summit in Vilnius?]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227248/whats-table-nato-summit-vilnius?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 11:14&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/4a2125fa-17f7-4cd4-81be-2b4f70dce268_b7457af4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nato leaders meet in Vilnius on Tuesday and Wednesday to address topics ranging from divisions over Ukraine’s membership bid and Sweden’s accession to boosting ammunitions stockpiles and reviewing the first defence plans in decades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will be the fourth Nato summit since Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, with the first held virtually on February 25, 2022, just one day after the assault, followed by meetings in Brussels and in Madrid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The extraordinary flurry of gatherings stands in contrast to the previous rhythm of annual Nato summits and shows how war on its doorstep has forced the alliance to strengthen cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following is a list of the main issues to be discussed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The summit looks set to be dominated by how Nato will define its future relationship with Ukraine, amid repeated calls by President Volodymyr Zelensky for Kyiv to receive an invitation into the alliance at Vilnius.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nato Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg has said that Kyiv will not become a member while war rages and that the summit will not issue a formal invitation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Ukraine goes on Nato membership offensive ahead of summit&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, allies are divided over how swiftly Ukraine should be allowed to join after the fighting ends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While eastern European countries say a road map should be offered to Kyiv, the US and Germany are wary of any move that might take the alliance closer to war with Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the run-up to Vilnius, some countries have suggested to allow Kyiv to skip the so-called Membership Action Plan (MAP) programme that sets out political, economic and military targets candidates have to meet and that other eastern European nations had to pass before joining Nato.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stoltenberg said he had put forward a package that included the removal of MAP but stopped short of confirming a tweet by Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba who stated there was a consensus among allies to drop MAP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With such a move, the alliance could address demands to go beyond the declaration of the Bucharest summit in 2008, which said Ukraine would become a member eventually, without offering Kyiv an actual invitation or timetable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nato is also likely to find a stronger wording than in 2008 to underscore Kyiv’s perspective for joining the alliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leaders could agree upon something like “Ukraine’s rightful place is in Nato”, echoing remarks by Stoltenberg on a visit to Kyiv in April, or stress that “trans-Atlantic security would be incomplete without Ukraine”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leaders are expected to discuss what security assurances Kyiv should get for the time after the war, even though these pledges will be bilateral and not issued by the alliance itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They will likely include the promise of continued military and financial aid to Kyiv to deter Russia from a renewed attack once the war has ended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stoltenberg has underlined that Nato – under Article 5 of the Washington Treaty – will provide full-fledged security guarantees to full members of the alliance only.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leaders will approve the first defence plans the alliance has drawn up since the Cold War, detailing how Nato would respond to a Russian attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The revival of the so-called regional plans signifies a fundamental shift. With the plans, the alliance also gives nations guidance on how to upgrade their forces and logistics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nato had for decades seen no need for large-scale defence plans but with Europe’s bloodiest war since 1945 raging just beyond its borders in Ukraine, it is now warning that it must have all planning in place well before a conflict with a peer adversary such as Moscow might erupt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turkey had been blocking approval of the plans over the wording on geographical locations such as Cyprus but allies reached agreement one day before the summit, five diplomats told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nato will also raise targets for the stockpiling of ammunitions as Kyiv is burning through shells much faster than Western countries can produce them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, allies will show how they aim to implement Nato’s goal, agreed at last year’s Madrid summit, of putting over 300,000 troops on high alert, up from 40,000 in the past, to counter Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turkey’s President Tayyip Erdogan agreed on Monday to support Sweden’s bid to become the 32nd member of Nato, a move that will expand the military alliance and strengthen its Baltic flank as Russia pursues its invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turkey had blocked its accession, accusing Stockholm of harbouring members of militant groups on its territory and saying it must crack down on them before being allowed to join Nato.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turkey was the last hurdle after Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban’s chief of staff said on Thursday that Budapest would no longer block Sweden’s Nato membership. Nato applications must be approved by all members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nato allies have reached agreement to raise the alliance target for military spending to at least 2 per cent of national GDP, according to two diplomats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 31 allies agreed on “an enduring commitment to invest at least 2 per cent” of their GDP into their militaries in the future, two diplomats said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stoltenberg had intended to make Nato’s previous military spending target of 2 per cent of national GDP a minimum requirement rather than a goal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2023, even the old target will be met by only 11 of the 31 members of the alliance, according to Nato estimates. The goal was set in 2014, when Nato leaders agreed to increase spending towards 2 per cent of their GDP on defence within a decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 11 allies are the United States, Britain, Poland, Greece, Estonia, Lithuania, Finland, Romania, Hungary, Latvia and Slovakia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bringing up the rear are Canada, Slovenia, Turkey, Spain, Belgium and Luxembourg whose defence spending was under 1.4 per cent of GDP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div&gt;获取更多RSS：&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.net" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.net&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.best" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.best&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why has the Hong Kong Arts Centre seen an exodus of staff in the past 12 months?]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/arts-culture/article/3227187/why-has-hong-kong-arts-centre-seen-exodus-staff-past-12-months?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 11:15&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/d2d9df0e-0203-46e5-9c84-7c1d4f1685e3_05e3dcad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Management’s attempt to overhaul the Hong Kong Arts Centre has triggered a mass walkout at the 46-year-old non-profit institution, with former employees reporting that at least half of its staff have left since the previous executive director stepped down in August 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those who have left in recent months include key personnel such as programme director Teresa Kwong, director of its Ifva film and video festival Kattie Fan, and senior programme manager Ian Leung, according to several people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to its most recent annual report, the centre had a staff of 63 as of June 30, 2022, excluding the Hong Kong Art School, a subsidiary relatively unaffected by the management change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former employees tell the Post that at least half of those people, as well as some recent recruits, have gone, mostly voluntarily, since Connie Lam Suk-yee left after 13 years at the helm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lam, who had been with the organisation since 1997, did not give a reason for her departure. The board replaced her with Rebecca Ip, a former executive director of the Hong Kong Ballet who was most recently the head of private nursery and kindergarten operator Victoria Educational Organisation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ip has told staff members that the HKAC should try to generate more revenue by focusing on ceramics and art courses for children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1977 as the first non-government arts venue, and with a dedicated curatorial team, galleries, a cinema and theatres, the HKAC does not receive a regular government subsidy and its upkeep relies on it renting out part of its headquarters, a distinctive, 19-storey triangular building in Wan Chai.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Arts censorship vs arts centre: Hong Kong must make ‘red lines’ clear&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Goethe-Institut, which runs German language classes and presents its own arts programmes on the 13th and 14th floors, is in the process of renewing its lease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a written reply to queries about the staff exodus, on July 6 the HKAC said that it was under financial pressure because of the downturn in the property market and the termination of an advertising contract for its giant rooftop billboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“To facilitate sustainability of its income streams, HKAC needs to review and enhance its areas of operations, including diversifying activities and courses to include art programmes for children,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last financial year, property rental yielded HK$20.8 million (US$2.7 million), 10 per cent lower than in 2020, and the centre had a deficit of HK$4.9 million, according to its annual report. Rental income from its galleries, cinema and theatres plunged by half during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2020 introduction of Hong Kong’s national security law also brought a new set of challenges. The Ifva, the centre’s independent film and video awards that held its 28th edition this spring, has had to pull finalists’ works from public screenings after Hong Kong’s film censorship board objected to scenes considered politically sensitive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The HKAC has also been suspected of self-censorship, for example when it cancelled outspoken singer Denise Ho Wan-see’s concerts in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June, its decision to call off a local theatre group’s musical over unexplained “infringements” also raised the ire of practitioners. Playwright Candace Chong Mui-ngam, who premiered , at the HKAC in 2019, has called on the arts centre to explain its decision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“As I was growing up, the HKAC was fashionable, innovative and daring to be different,” she wrote on Facebook. “I am very disappointed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One recent leaver, who wishes to remain anonymous, says: “There have been instances when the board and the executive director’s office overreacted when faced with a sensitive situation, but that is not the main reason why people have quit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Many are leaving because they cannot bear to stay on and just do programmes with little meaning. And because the new management seem to have little respect for the centre’s strong ties with the local arts community.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The centre said in the statement: “Regarding human resources management, HKAC regularly reviews the number of staff and their workloads, and continues to actively seek suitable candidates to fill vacancies through natural attrition.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its review of resources has also led to the termination of support for long-running partnerships and projects in the past year, such as Art in Hospital, and Class 7A Drama Group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2020, several new board members have been appointed, including the economist Francis Lui Ting-ming, and chairperson Dominica Yang was reappointed. Three board members and the chairperson are appointed by the chief executive under the Hong Kong Arts Centre Ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the decade before Hong Kong’s return to China in 1997, the centre’s then executive director, Oscar Ho Hing-kay, initiated public art projects aimed at making the arts less elitist. He also recognised the cultural significance of the period by curating landmark exhibitions about Hong Kong identity, such as “Hong Kong Incarnated”, which took place during the handover.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During Lam’s tenure as executive director, the centre continued to present programmes that were relevant to contemporary society. She also oversaw major expansion: it became the operator of a new comics and animation centre at a government-owned heritage building in 2013, and added two campuses to the Hong Kong Art School, which provides post-secondary-school programmes as well as short courses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But since the arrival of major Hong Kong arts venues such as the West Kowloon Cultural District and Tai Kwun, both of which boast world-class visual arts and performing arts programmes, the centre has been increasingly overshadowed and criticised for complacency, as well as for focusing too much on just renting out space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Hong Kong-based art collector puts his 200 films by 92 artists online&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There were also administrative matters that could be improved upon,” said another former employee, who also wished to remain anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There was anticipation that the new management could bring some positive change. Sadly, that has yet to happen.”&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Move over America, China and India will have bigger economies by 2075, Goldman Sachs says]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/article/3227246/move-over-america-china-and-india-will-have-bigger-economies-2075-goldman-sachs-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 10:36&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/2ba3b141-18a7-4175-b063-3d9a9258f18d_51cc191d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;India’s economy is on track to surpass the United States by 2075 to become the world’s second-largest after China, according to Goldman Sachs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street bank projects that the South Asian nation’s gross domestic product will surge to US$52.5 trillion by then, compared with forecasts of US$57 trillion and US$51.5 trillion for China and the US, respectively. India’s growth will be powered mainly by its large labour force, advances in technology and rising capital investment, the bank said in a note.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At present, India ranks as the fifth-biggest economy in the world with a GDP of US$3.74 billion and a per capita income of US$2,600, according to the International Monetary Fund.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;High-profile market experts such as American investor Ray Dalio and fund manager Mark Mobius have hailed the Asian nation as the next biggest investing opportunity. Even major companies including Apple, Tesla and SpaceX have leaned into the emerging economy as a hub for its supply chains instead of China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“India has made more progress in innovation and technology than some may realise,” said Santanu Sengupta, Goldman Sachs’s chief India economist. “Innovation and increasing worker productivity are going to be important for the world’s fifth-biggest economy. In technical terms, that means greater output for each unit of labour and capital in India’s economy.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But India also faces hurdles in its journey towards economic superpower status. These include hefty import taxes, bureaucracy and red tape, and the dominance of domestic business tycoons – which make it harder for foreign companies to snap up any market share in key industries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;In a blow to Modi’s chip dreams, Foxconn exits US$20 billion Indian joint venture&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Goldman’s Sengupta, capital investment, which refers to money invested in a business for its long-term growth, is going to be a key engine of India’s growth moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Driven by favourable demographics, India’s savings rate is likely to increase with falling dependency ratios, rising incomes, and deeper financial sector development, which is likely to make the pool of capital available to drive further investment,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;India’s Prime Minister Narendra Modi has been a cheerleader for capital expenditure, recently urging the nation’s private sector to boost investment and take advantage of the federal 2023-24 budget, according to the Hindu newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lastly, India has the opportunity to turbocharge its GDP by integrating its growing population into the labour force. The South Asian nation recently overtook China to become the world’s most populous nation, with 1.4 billion people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“India’s large population is clearly an opportunity, however the challenge is productively using the labour force, by increasing the labour force participation rate. That will mean creating the opportunities for this labour force to get absorbed and simultaneously training and upskilling the labour force,” Sengupta said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article was first published by &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div&gt;获取更多RSS：&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.net" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.net&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.best" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.best&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine’s grain supplies to Asia shrink as ‘lifeline’ Black Sea deal expiry looms]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3227188/ukraines-grain-supplies-asia-shrink-lifeline-black-sea-deal-expiry-looms?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 09:30&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/fdb81b4a-52da-4c6d-bc8b-5f17d2f9b362_33e63164.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine’s grain shipments have been halted ahead of the expiry of a Black Sea deal with Russia this month, throwing into uncertainty food supplies to Asia from one of the world’s most productive regions and threatening to drive up prices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Black Sea deal, which was brokered by Turkey a year ago, allowed Ukraine to send agricultural goods from its seaports despite its war with Russia – but Moscow has said there are no grounds to further extend the deal beyond its July 18 expiry date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our agricultural shipments have stopped completely in the last 14 days as Russian authorities have stopped inspecting our shipments to allow them for export,” said Alex Lissitsa, CEO of Warsaw-listed agricultural company IMC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IMC owns 120,000 hectares of land in Ukraine close to the Russian border, on which it grows corn, wheat and sunflower. It usually ships half of the corn output to China, and also sends produce to Pakistan, India and Bangladesh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 90 per cent of the war-torn country’s agriculture exports were routed through the seaport of Odesa, which was kept open under the Black Sea deal. However, Russian authorities would only allowed agricultural cargoes to pass after inspections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United Nations says the Black Sea deal has been a “lifeline for food security” as it enabled the export of 32 million tonnes of grain to 45 countries across three continents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the volumes of shipments have been in decline since February and last month dipped to less than one-quarter of the 7.3 million tonnes dispatched in January last year, before the start of Russia’s invasion, said Julia Bereshchenko, who is in charge of sustainable business development for Astarta, one of the largest agriculture firms in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An end to the Black Sea deal would mean nearly half of wheat and corn produced by 4,500 small Ukrainian farmers could end up rotting in the fields as they lack the storage capacity and need to sell the crops immediately, Bereshchenko said. Wheat is typically harvested in July and the income from sales helps farmers plant crops for the next growing season, which begins in the autumn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia’s occupation means that around 20 per cent of Ukraine’s land is not available for crop cultivation, bringing down its agriculture output this year to about 80 million tonnes of grains and oilseeds from 100 million tonnes previously, Bereshchenko said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But a drastic drop in domestic consumption – a result of the mass exodus of people since the Russian invasion in February last year – means 50-60 million tonnes will have to be exported, she said. In addition to the corn it exports to China, Ukraine is also an important supplier of wheat, sunflower oil and soybeans to India, Bangladesh, Thailand and other Asian nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We [can] export one million tonnes per month via rail, but it will be insufficient,” Bereshchenko said, explaining that Ukraine uses a wider railway gauge than neighbouring nations like Poland and Romania, impeding freight movement. The cost of overland transport, at around US$100 per tonne, is at least double that of seaborne freight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Asia must embrace technology to ensure solid food supplies amid climate change&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Ukrainian farmers will lose money on growing corn and wheat if they have to pay such high freight costs,” said Bereshchenko, adding that the farmers had started reducing their corn and wheat acreage and shifting to other crops. “If the Black Sea deal is not renewed, then the wheat and corn crop is going to be even lower.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The chances of Russia extending the Black Sea deal are likely to depend on whether Western nations agree to its demand that its state-run agricultural bank be reconnected to the global Swift monetary transfer system from which it was severed in the wake of the invasion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Financial Times reported that the European Union was considering a proposal to allow Russia’s Rosselkhozbank to establish a subsidiary to connect to Swift, but Moscow has rejected the proposal as “unworkable” since it will take several months to set up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moscow has also opposed extending the deal because it says that Ukraine’s agricultural goods have flowed to “well-fed countries” and five of the poorest countries – Ethiopia, Sudan, Yemen, Somalia and Afghanistan – have accounted for only about one-quarter of shipments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I think the grain deal will not be extended. Ever since the Togilattle-Odesa ammonia pipeline was blown up in early June, the likelihood of a renewal became minimal,” said Viktor Katona, lead crude analyst at Kpler, a commodities data and analytics company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pipeline, the largest of its kind in the world, carried ammonia from a petrochemical plant in the southern Russian city of Togliatti to Odesa in Ukraine for European markets. It was destroyed by unknown actors in June among a spate of arson and other attacks on Russian assets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commodity price patterns in the financial markets show that grain trading has turned into a “contango” – when the futures price of a commodity is higher than its spot price – an indication that traders are bracing for a deal collapse and tighter markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the market’s worst fears come true, Asia will feel the impact as the region accounts for about one-quarter of Ukraine’s seaborne exports, though the impact may vary from country to country, Katona said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia, which has already reaped a bumper wheat crop and expects another one to be harvested soon, may step in to fill the breach by selectively supplying some countries, such as those in Africa, to win their diplomatic support at the UN, analysts say.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Russia cannot completely replace the grain coming from Ukraine if the deal collapses. However, they can export a significant quantity,” said Cedomir Nestrovic, a professor of geopolitics at the ESSEC Business School Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Moscow embarks on such a grains-for-votes push, then global prices are likely to increase because there may be less supply available in global trading hubs, he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Why a delay to South Asia’s monsoon is ‘bad news’ for global rice supplies&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such a development will hit many countries in Asia, especially as El Nino conditions – which increases ocean surface temperature – have disrupted monsoon rains that are critical to agriculture. For example, rainfall in Thailand during this year’s monsoon is expected to be 10 per cent lower than usual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blistering heatwaves have also reduced wheat production in India, one of Asia’s largest grain producers, and the country may only have enough to meet its own needs after the harvest, said G Chandrashekhar, an independent policy commentator. The onset of El Nino during the monsoon could prolong the South Asian country’s woes as it is also the world’s top supplier of rice, he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Global prices for grains and edible oils are likely to rise unless Russia and Ukraine extend the Black Sea deal, Chandrashekhar said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Food inflation will remain at elevated levels. A rising tide lifts all boats,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div&gt;获取更多RSS：&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.net" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.net&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.best" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.best&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:50:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese law enforcers cure police-fixated girl, 3, of her police-uniform obsession after mother goes to station in desperation]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226891/caring-chinese-law-enforcers-cure-police-fixated-girl-3-her-police-uniform-obsession-after-mother?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 09:00&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/2cc78f03-2d31-40d2-86fd-2149b4423f6a_63cce243.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mother of a three-year-old girl in China with a police fixation who refused to take off a law enforcement costume was forced to seek help from real officers to rid her daughter of her obsession.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A surveillance video clip featuring the little girl shared on mainland social media earlier this month received 4 million views on Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It shows the toddler’s desperate mother carrying her in-costume daughter into a police station in central China’s Hubei province on July 3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The unidentified woman begged the officers at the front desk to persuade her daughter to take off a police costume and white gloves she insists on wearing at all times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She said her daughter was in a car accident two years ago and was hugged and comforted by a policeman afterwards, which made a lasting impression on the girl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A dream of becoming a policeman when she grew up had been planted in her head, and she wore the costume uniform every day, refusing to take it off despite a rash appearing on her back, the mother said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She also refused to grow her hair long or wear girls’ sandals, in the belief that all police officers were male, like the one who had rescued her after the car accident.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her mother said she took her daughter to the police station so she could see that “there are many aunties who are police officers”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A policewoman on duty at the station patiently told the girl that women and men can be police officers and that they only wear police uniforms when they are at work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“When we are off duty, we dress ourselves up like your mum,” the officer told the girl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese news outlet Star Video reported that the girl let go of her obsession with the uniform after they left the police station.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mainland social media has been charmed by the girl’s childish fixation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“She is only three, and she already has a goal,” said one person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“She was probably seeking a sense of security after the car accident. The policeman was the light she saw at a time of danger,” commented another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“What her mother did was nice, persuading her while also protecting her dream,” said a third online observer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Children showing admiration for their “heroes” are a constant source of human interest stories on mainland social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In April, another three-year-old girl from central China gave hugs and snacks to a group of firefighters who were resting by the roadside after completing a job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Douyin, a six-year-old girl from eastern China’s Jiangsu province attracted 1 million followers with her “professional” doctor games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The girl, who wants to be a doctor when she grows up, had been playing doctor since she was a toddler, looking after her “patients” who were played by other family members, her pet corgi and a cat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div&gt;获取更多RSS：&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.net" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.net&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedx.best" style="color:orange" target="_blank"&gt;https://feedx.best&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:20:08 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Head of crypto firm Circle accepts ban in mainland China, but sees role for yuan-backed stablecoins]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3227171/head-crypto-firm-circle-accepts-ban-mainland-china-sees-role-yuan-backed-stablecoins?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 09:00&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/27522d63-88b1-4342-b7f6-fa00fd614a3a_10bcee3f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Allaire, co-founder and CEO of the USDC stablecoin operator Circle, said he is under no illusions about mainland China opening its markets to cryptocurrencies, but he remains optimistic about Web3 development in Hong Kong and the local monetary authority’s move towards regulating stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The reality is that every other major financial market in the world is also embracing digital assets, and the biggest financial institutions in the world are embracing digital assets. So for Hong Kong to be relevant, it has to,” Allaire said in an interview with the South China Morning Post on Friday, the final day of his two-week trip to Asia, which included an appearance at the World Economic Forum in Tianjin last week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I think there is Chinese government support for that,” he added. “That’s different than feeling like it says something about opening up the trading of crypto on the mainland. I don’t think there’s anything there.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Bank of China unit issues securities on Ethereum blockchain in Hong Kong&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While some government officials from mainland China, where cryptocurrencies are banned, have made statements in the past suggesting support for Hong Kong’s moves to court the industry, there has been no indication that Beijing itself is warming to crypto, as some have hoped. Allaire acknowledged this, but he said stablecoins – cryptoassets that are typically pegged to fiat currency – are unique in that they could offer a more immediate solution for the government’s goal to internationalise the yuan than the central bank digital currency (CBDC) eCNY.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If eventually the Chinese government wants to see the RMB used more freely in trade and commerce around the world, it may be that stablecoins are the path to do that more than the central bank digital currency,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allaire referred to a stablecoin pegged to the offshore yuan (CNH) as an example of how this might work. Members of the team behind the stablecoin CNH Coin, which makes another pegged to the Hong Kong dollar called HKD Coin, were detained in Shanghai in May, according to Chinese media. Authorities have yet to give an explanation for the detention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stablecoins are the next front in Hong Kong’s bid to regulate crypto markets and become a global virtual asset hub.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) has promised to roll out regulations on stablecoins by 2024, noting the potential impact such products could have on financial markets. The Securities and Futures Commission has also said it is working on its own complimentary regulations for stablecoins, which comes after the regulator’s rules on licensing sellers of other types of cryptocurrencies went into effect last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;USDC, or USD Coin, is the second-largest US dollar-backed stablecoin in the world by market capitalisation, after Tether (USDT). Boston-based Circle calls itself the world’s largest “regulated dollar stablecoin issuer”, as USDC is considered a “stored-value instrument” in the US. Tether Ltd, which manages USDT, is owned by Hong Kong-based iFinex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allaire said Circle is encouraged by plans from the HKMA, which in January released a conclusion on its discussion paper for cryptoassets and stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re excited that this is a priority for the Hong Kong government and it seems like it’s a real priority for the HKMA,” Allaire said. “That’s tremendously positive and is really motivating for us to want to be able to grow our business here.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Central banks around the world have expressed concern about the potential for stablecoins to impact financial stability. As a possible mitigation measure for this, the HKMA said in its conclusion paper that the “value of reserve assets … should meet the value of the outstanding stablecoins at all times”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The HKMA has also been researching a possible digital Hong Kong dollar. The city is already part of a cross-border trial for the eCNY using a blockchain referred to as the mBridge. Thailand and the United Arab Emirates are also part of the trial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There have been some questions about the future role of stablecoins in a well-regulated environment once CBDCs are available. For Allaire, CBDCs are complementary and private coins still have a role to play in innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If central banks are going to upgrade their own systems to move away from legacy technology into more modern distributed ledger technology, that’s great,” he said. “There’s a whole bunch of things that are useful from that, but I view that as very different than the work that the private sector does to innovate on the public internet.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much of Circle’s business activity today is in Asia, its largest non-US market and where it has about 125 employees, according to Allaire.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:20:08 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong power firm’s new system predicts tree growth near overhead cables to prevent electricity disruption]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227204/hong-kong-power-firms-new-system-predicts-tree-growth-near-overhead-cables-prevent-electricity?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 09:00&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/d457f19c-d376-4076-abc6-0e6e70bcd0fb_bcba5112.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Hong Kong power company has worked with scientists to develop a model that predicts the growth rate of trees near overhead cables in an effort to prevent them from disrupting electricity supply in the New Territories, Lantau Island and parts of Kowloon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The monitoring system was introduced last April, and CLP Power’s vegetation management team carried out 80,000 pruning works based on alerts issued by the system over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The system’s most significant feature is the ability to predict the growth of trees … to identify those that may pose a potential risk to nearby overhead cables,” said Michael Lau Ho-yin, a north region director at CLP Power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“When CLP Power’s vegetation management team carried out tree maintenance in the past, it was difficult to grasp the growth of trees within the range of overhead cables.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He added that the new system could save more than HK$1.5 million (US$191,000) in annual operating costs as it would help allocate resources and labour more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The power company created a database using geographic information system (GIS) technology to record information on more than 170,000 trees, including their species, age and pruning history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Hong Kong ‘risks losing’ endangered trees under plan to build golf course flats&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 200 species, including kapok, camphor wood, bauhinia and Chinese banyan, have been identified along the power grids in the New Territories, Lantau Island and parts of Kowloon amounting to about half of the tree species documented in the city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liu Wai-lung, a senior technical supervisor in the vegetation management team, said the system had improved work efficiency since they could prioritise pruning work according to the risk of disturbing the overhead cables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s easier for us to identify the location of the tree because the system will tell us the GPS position, as well as the cable’s location and name,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Director Lau said the model also helped to reduce paper consumption by 70 per cent as data obtained on-site could be directly added to the system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countries such as Britain, the United States and Canada have used such technology for more than a decade to monitor tree growth and collect spatial data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jim Chi-yung, a research chair professor of geography and environmental science at the Education University of Hong Kong, who co-led the project, said it was the first time the system was being used in the city, and its predictive function was advanced and detailed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The project began in 2019 to monitor the growth rate of trees along CLP Power’s overhead cables in the New Territories, Lantau Island and parts of Kowloon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Major Hong Kong power cut caused by use of 10-year-old backup cable&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the following year, the research team conducted experiments to analyse the effect of weather, temperature, sunlight and rainfall on pruned trees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The findings revealed that the higher the sun intensity, temperature and rainfall, the faster a pruned tree developed epicormic shoots, an abnormal structure that grows on its trunk, stem or branch in response to adverse events such as fires or fungal infections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The closer the tree was to the overhead power line, the more likely it was to cause power to disperse to the ground, leading to voltage instability, the vegetation management team explained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jim said the system helped the team carry out pruning work in a “more scientific, accurate and objective” way, since it was largely based on experience and knowledge fostered through past training.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:20:08 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google AI expert warns of ‘data poisoning’ as Chinese scientists work to ward off emerging threat]]></title><link><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3227213/google-ai-expert-warns-data-poisoning-chinese-scientists-work-ward-emerging-threat?utm_source=rss_feed]]></link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;2023.07.11 09:00&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/4166e380-e5d6-4baa-ae3b-5d6fcdaa81fd_6ffe8d7f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Google researcher has warned that attackers could disable AI systems by “poisoning” their data sets, and Chinese researchers are already working to come up with countermeasures to guard against this emerging threat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At an AI conference in Shanghai on Friday, Google Brain research scientist Nicholas Carlini said that by manipulating just a tiny fraction of an AI system’s training data, attackers could critically compromise its functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Some security threats, once solely utilised for academic experimentation, have evolved into tangible threats in real-world contexts,” Carlini said during the Artificial Intelligence Risk and Security Sub-forum at the World Artificial Intelligence Conference, according to financial news outlet Caixin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In one prevalent attack method known as “data poisoning”, an attacker introduces a small number of biased samples into the AI model’s training data set. This deceptive practice “poisons” the model during the training process, undermining its usefulness and integrity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Use AI to beat Chinese censors if Taiwan is attacked, think tank tells US&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“By contaminating just 0.1 per cent of the data set, the entire algorithm can be compromised,” Carlini said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We used to perceive these attacks as academic games, but it’s time for the community to acknowledge these security threats and understand the potential for real-world implications.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision-making process and judgment of an AI model largely stem from its training and learning process, which is dependent on vast quantities of data. The quality, neutrality and integrity of the training data significantly influence the model’s accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A model will perform poorly if it is trained on data contaminated with malicious images. For example, if an algorithm designed to identify animals is fed an image of a dog that is mislabelled as a cat, it might mistake other dog images for cats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some poisoning attacks are very subtle. Poisoned models perform normally on clean data – identifying a cat image as a cat, for instance – but produce incorrect results on data specifically targeted by the attacker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This type of attack, which makes the AI model yield erroneous results on select data, could cause substantial damage or even grave security breaches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a long time, poisoning attacks were deemed impractical because inserting malicious data into a rival’s machine learning model is a complex task.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, data sets used for machine learning in the past were manageable and uncontaminated compared to today’s standards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, the MNIST database, which was frequently used for training machine learning models in the late 1990s, only had 60,000 training images and 10,000 test images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today scientists use vast data sets to train sophisticated machine learning models. These data sets, most of which are open source or otherwise publicly accessible, may contain up to 5 billion images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Users who download the data set only access its present version, not the original one used for training. If someone malignly alters the images in the data set, all models trained on the data set would be compromised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tests conducted by Carlini showed that data poisoning could occur by altering just 0.1 per cent of the data set. By making minute alterations, the data set’s owner could gain control over the machine learning model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To address these security concerns, Li Changsheng, a professor at the Beijing Institute of Technology, proposed a method of reverse-engineering AI to bolster defences against training data that has been tampered with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a paper published in the Journal of Software earlier this year, Li and his team introduced a technique known as member inference. In this process, when the algorithm receives data, an auxiliary algorithm initially uses this data for a preliminary training exercise and compares the training results to determine if the data qualifies as reasonable training data. This technique can eliminate harmful data before it enters the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Similar algorithms could be employed to remove imbalanced data, analyse flaws in the model and more. However, this method is resource-intensive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Compared to regular artificial intelligence tasks, reverse intelligence tasks are considerably more challenging, demanding higher computational resources and potentially a new architecture or greater bandwidth,” Li said in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, large-scale poisoning attacks are a threat that cannot be overlooked. “Poisoning attacks are a very real threat that must be factored in whenever models are being trained,” Carlini said.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:20:08 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>